<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Pharmacopoeia Lemeriana contracta Lemery's Universal pharmacopoeia abridg'd, in a collection of recepe's and observations compar'd with the London and with Bates's dispensatories, and also with Charas's Royal pharmacy : to which are added some remedies recommended by the members of the French Royal Academy of Science, most collected out of the history of that society lately published by John Baptista du Hamel.</title>
            <title>Pharmacopeé universelle. English. 1700</title>
            <author>Lémery, Nicolas, 1645-1715.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 212 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 98 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A47661</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L1042</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R26151</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">09369913</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 09369913</idno>
            <idno type="VID">42878</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A47661)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 42878)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1311:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Pharmacopoeia Lemeriana contracta Lemery's Universal pharmacopoeia abridg'd, in a collection of recepe's and observations compar'd with the London and with Bates's dispensatories, and also with Charas's Royal pharmacy : to which are added some remedies recommended by the members of the French Royal Academy of Science, most collected out of the history of that society lately published by John Baptista du Hamel.</title>
                  <title>Pharmacopeé universelle. English. 1700</title>
                  <author>Lémery, Nicolas, 1645-1715.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[10], 167, [12] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Walter Kettilby,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Includes index.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Pharmacopoeias.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Pharmacopoeia Lemeriana Contracta:</hi> LEMERY's Univerſal
<hi>Pharmacopoeia</hi> abridg'd, IN A COLLECTION OF Recepe's and
Obſervations, Compar'd With the <hi>London</hi> and with <hi>Bates</hi>'s
<hi>Diſpenſatories;</hi> and alſo, with <hi>Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ras</hi>'s Royal
Pharmacy.</p>
            <p>To which are added, Some Remedies recommended by the Members of
the <hi>French</hi> Royal Aca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demy of Sciences, moſt collected out of the
Hiſtory of that Society, lately publiſhed by <hi>John Baptiſta du
Hamel.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Walter Kettilby</hi> at the
<hi>Biſhop's-head</hi> in St. <hi>Paul</hi>'s Church-yard, 1700.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="preface">
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:2"/>
            <head>THE PREFACE.</head>
            <p>THE Choice, due Preparation and Mixture of Medicines are of ſuch
known conſequence to the welfare of Mankind, that I ſhould loſe time, if
I ſpent any in recommending <hi>Pharmacy;</hi> and it be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing little leſs
obvious, that a Skill in <hi>Chymiſtry</hi> is indiſpenſably
neceſſary to make an able <hi>Apothecary,</hi> I ſhall think it
needleſs to inſiſt upon any Praiſes of Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> in this
particular, ſince his Ingenious and Learn'd Treatiſe upon the Subject, ſo
well receiv'd over all <hi>Europe,</hi> that it has been printed nine times in
<hi>French,</hi> thrice in <hi>Engliſh,</hi> and ſeveral times in
<hi>Latin,</hi> is an unqueſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable proof of his Ability. Therefore I take
the only thing incumbent on me, to be, to account why I have taken ſo lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle
<pb facs="tcp:42878:3"/>from a Book which I take pains to inſinuate, is valuable; for
which I ſhall offer theſe reaſons. 1. That upon com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paring his to the
<hi>London</hi> and <hi>Bates</hi>'s <hi>Diſpenſatories,</hi> and with
Monſieur <hi>Charas</hi>'s <hi>Royal Pharmacy</hi> already Engliſh'd, I
have found very many good Remedies borrow'd from the two firſt, and not a few
taken from the lat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, which I thought as needleſs as diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingenuous to
inſert in this <hi>Collection,</hi> thoſe Books being in moſt peoples
hands already; if I take notice of any, it is very ſeldom but where ſome
alteration is made, or to vindicate our Compoſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons from faults my Author
pretends to find in them. 2. I do often abridge into ten or a dozen words what
I find ſpun out uſeleſly into twenty or thirty lines: It is in telling
what quantity of different Ingredients are contain'd in a determinate portion
of a Compoſition; my Author is not content to ſay, that there is ſo much
contain'd in a Scruple or in a Drachm, but begins a-new, and tells there is
ſo much contain'd in two Scruples, and in two Drachms, and <pb facs="tcp:42878:3"/>commences again, and goes on often to an Ounce and a half, and that
ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times in ſuch ordinary Compoſitions as <hi>Lenitive Electuary</hi>
for <hi>Gliſters.</hi> For my part, I believe neither this nor any other Book
would be of uſe to ſuch as ſhould want Brains to calculate, that if a
Drachm contains ſo many Grains of an Ingredient, two Drachms of the ſame
Compoſition muſt contain twice ſo many Grains; and ſo any other
aſſignable quantity thereof, more or leſs as it is contain'd in, or
contains a Drachm. 3. I avoid what does conſiderably aug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment the Bulk of
this great <hi>Pharma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy, viz.</hi> a frequent Repetition of tedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Remarks,
deſign'd for the Inſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of <hi>Novices,</hi> but altogether
uſeleſs to ſuch as are under the direction of <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters</hi> to
learn their <hi>Calling,</hi> and far ſhort of Sufficiency to render any
other an <hi>Artiſt;</hi> for there is a certain <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dus,</hi> a nice
<hi>ſecundum Artem</hi> in duely preparing Medicines, which is as
im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible to be learn'd by dry Precepts without Manual Operation directed
by a <hi>viva voce</hi> Inſtruction, as it is unlikely <pb facs="tcp:42878:4"/>to become
a famous Fencer by Contem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plation and ſerious Study of <hi>Agrippa</hi>'s or
any other great Artiſt's Poſture-Book. And truly it is wonderful, that in
ſuch a Nation as this is, where plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty affords due means to preſerve
Health, people ſhould riſque this Comfort of Life, in making uſe of the
adulterate, dilite<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious, ſlovenly Compoſitions of ignorant pretending
Quacks, whoſe number grows daily upon us thro' the <hi>Diſſention</hi> of
<hi>Phyſicians</hi> among themſelves, and the unhappy <hi>Difference</hi>
of the <hi>College</hi> with the <hi>Apothecaries,</hi> whereof there can
likely be no proſpect of Accommoda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, when Methods are taken to widen the
Breach to the conſiderable detriment of <hi>Phyſick</hi> in general, and no
leſs diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reputation of <hi>Engliſh Phyſicians,</hi> hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therto
deſervedly famous over all the Learned World. To heal a Wound by irritating
it, and putting its ſever'd parts at a greater diſtance, was never learn'd
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Hippocrates,</hi> and will
be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways as unſucceſsful as the attempts of a late ingenious Author to
ridicule Men into Conformity. Such Conſtraints are <pb facs="tcp:42878:4"/>too like
Dragooning to take in this free Nation, and it is pity he has thrown a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way ſo
much truly noble Verſe, <hi>Claudi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an</hi>-like, on ſo mean a Subject. As
for the anonymous Author that has ſo diſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geniouſly labour'd to
leſſen <hi>Apothe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caries,</hi> they ſet ſo little by his mighty
Performance, that upon diſcovery of his Name; they have only cut off the
Initial Letter, and it's ſaid, the beſt of them are ſo little averſe to
a fair Accommodation with the <hi>College,</hi> that they would not be
againſt a Subordination, equally diſtant from vying with approv'd able
<hi>Phyſici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans</hi> and a too ſervile dependance on them. It is more than
probable, that ſuch a tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per would prove to the Credit and Intereſt of
both. But I muſt leave this Subject to acquaint the Reader, that I generally
prefer the leſs Compound when larger Compoſitions are not recommended by
ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perienc'd <hi>Practitioners;</hi> for all Plants and Minerals are in
themſelves Compo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitions where Nature has regulated the Doſes and
Mixtures of Principles with an exactneſs unattainable by Art, if we were but
fortunate enough to hit upon <pb facs="tcp:42878:5"/>them and to apply them right; on the
other hand, the over-nice uncompounded<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs ſought after by laborious and
tireſome Analyſes, ſeems an equal Error, many <hi>Quinteſſences,
Elixirs, Ethereal Oyls,</hi> and ſuch others, call'd, <hi>the Souls of
Mixts,</hi> proving ſhort of the efficacy of the groſſer parts, witneſs
the <hi>Kinkina.</hi> Let <hi>Experience</hi> guide here as in caſes of this
nature it ought, being the only Teſt that can be ſafely rely'd on in the
uſe and choice of <hi>Medicines,</hi> for <hi>Taſt</hi> and <hi>Smell</hi>
(Dr. <hi>Floyer</hi>'s Touch-ſtone) prove wofully deceitful on many
occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and do not reach ſome Sovereign Remedies, as the
<hi>Ipecacuanha</hi> and <hi>Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuit's Bark,</hi> that have no Smell at all,
and <hi>Mercury</hi> and <hi>Antimony</hi> that have neither Taſt nor Smell.
Before I con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude this <hi>Preface,</hi> I muſt take notice of a Method in
Practice peculiar (for what I can learn) to Mr. <hi>Lemery, viz.</hi> leaving
on or continuing Bliſtering-Plaiſters to the ſame part for 16 or 20 days
together, and that he ſays with ſucceſs in young Children troubled with
obſtinate Defluxions on their Eyes. Tho' <pb facs="tcp:42878:5"/>his
<hi>Veſicatory</hi> is not ſo ſtrong of the <hi>Cantharides</hi> as ours
generally are, I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve few will think it ſafe to preſcribe it his way
here, where there is a freſh Inſtance of that degree of prejudice
a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the foreign Fly, that ſome have been ſeverely handled for
ordering the internal uſe in a very ſmall quantity and wary circumſpect
manner; the caſe ſo deſperate, that ordinary Medicines prov'd
ineffectual. In my Judgment the Reaſons urg'd againſt the Practice, well
conſider'd, prov'd it ſafe. I will add my Thoughts, and humbly ſubmit
them to the unbyaſs'd Reader.</p>
            <p>The Arguments us'd againſt the inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal uſe of the
<hi>Cantharides</hi> ran moſt thus, That an external application raiſes
Bliſters, tears the Fleſh, cauſes often a great pain in the Bladder,
accompany'd ſometimes with bloody Urine, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, if
taken inwardly they will of ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity excoriate the Stomach, tear the
tender Blood-veſſels in the Lungs, and endanger all the noble parts.</p>
            <p>If we duly examine how Bliſtering-Plaiſters apply'd to the
Neck, Arms, or <pb facs="tcp:42878:6"/>other external parts, cauſe the Pain and
Bloody-Urine complain'd of, we will find, that both are occaſion'd by an
ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heſion of ſome Corroſive Particles of the <hi>Cantharides</hi> to the
inner Membrane and Neck of the Bladder; and if we examine how ſuch Particles
come to theſe parts from the Back or Arms, we will find, they muſt of
neceſſity paſs through the <hi>Lungs</hi> and <hi>Heart,</hi> and that
pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bably ſeveral times before they are car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry'd off by Urine; for
paſſing gradually with the refluent Blood to the <hi>Heart,</hi> it is not
unlike they impregnate the Maſs equally; and if ſo, there can be no more
carry'd to the <hi>Kidneys</hi> in one Circulati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, than what the Blood of the
Emul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent Arteries happens to be then loaded with, which muſt bear the ſame
pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion to the whole, as this quantity of Blood doth to the entire Maſs,
the reſt of the <hi>Cantharides</hi> at the ſame time, being carry'd to
thoſe call'd <hi>Noble,</hi> as well as to other parts, as they receive more
or leſs of the impregnated Fluid. Since thus it is manifeſt, that the
<hi>Acri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monious Salts</hi> of the <hi>Cantharides</hi> paſs <pb facs="tcp:42878:6"/>through the <hi>Lungs</hi> and <hi>Heart</hi> when from an external
application they affect the Bladder, and that it ſeems more than probable,
that ſome portion is at the ſame time convey'd with the Blood to all the
other <hi>Noble Parts,</hi> it follows, that either the fear of giving them
inwardly in a ſmall quantity and with good cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectives is groundleſs, or
that there muſt be evident danger in a frequent External Application, which
is contrary to daily Experience. If <hi>Cantharides</hi> were ſo pernicious
as ſome imagine, what dread<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful effects would they not work when ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd in
<hi>Veſicatories</hi> to ſuch as are apt to ſpit Blood, or are ſubject
to <hi>Dyſenteries?</hi> What a condition muſt they be in, that have half a
dozen Bliſters on at a time? can it be ſuppos'd that there is not more of
the <hi>Fly</hi> circulating among their <hi>Noble Parts</hi> than would be in
one that ſhould take in half a Grain at the Mouth; cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly the great
benefit found by <hi>Veſica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tories</hi> in the fuſion of a groſs
ſluggiſh <hi>Serum,</hi> and the conſequent excretion of that with the
Peccant Matter by Urine and copious Sweats, is an unqueſtiona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble <pb facs="tcp:42878:7"/>proof of the intimate mixture of a conſiderable part of their
Acrimonious Particles with the Maſs of Blood if there were no other Argument
to prove it. Much more might be alledg'd on this Subject from matters of fact,
but that would make the <hi>Preface</hi> as big as the <hi>Book,</hi> ſo I
ſhall end here, and beg the <hi>Reader</hi> to pardon ſome falſe
pointings and literal errors, and to take the words <hi>Filter</hi> and
<hi>Filtration</hi> (which are often us'd in this ſmall <hi>Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lection</hi>)
in their larger Sence, for ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary ſtraining, not for paſſing Liquors
through Cap-paper as <hi>Chymiſts</hi> uſe them.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="section">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:42878:7"/>
            <head>OF INFUSIONS AND Decoctions.</head>
            <p>HEre they are deſervedly cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſured, that overcharge their
Liquor with too great a quantity and number of Drugs, it being manifeſt, that
neither Infuſion nor Decoction becomes thereby the ſtronger, becauſe no
aſſignable Men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruum can load it ſelf, nor take up more of any
ſubſtance, than fills its pores, or can adjuſt it ſelf to its
inſenſible conſtituent parts. But theſe intercepted Interſtices
varying in Figure and Capacity, it fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows, <pb n="2" facs="tcp:42878:8"/>that when a
Liquor is ſo ſatiate with a certain ſubſtance, that it will not
diſſolve one Grain more of it, though it ſhould ſtand never ſo long
thereon; yet it will readily take up another body, whoſe minute parts are
more proportio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate to its unpoſſeſs'd Pores, or can adjuſt
themſelves better to its inconſpicuous Principles. I add this laſt,
becauſe it is demonſtrable, that the parts of the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd body are
not all receiv'd into the empty ſpaces that lie interſpers'd in the
diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolving Liquor; ſince this does often con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderably increaſe in
Volume, and that ſometimes proportionably to the bulk of what is
diſſolv'd therein, which could not be, if only <hi>vacuola,</hi> or
intercepted empty ſpaces, became ſatiate. What is here advanc'd, is
manifeſtly prov'd by the following eaſie and unexpenſive Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periments.
Take 6 or 8 Ounces of wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, throw common Salt into it, untill it will
diſſolve no more, then pour off the Liquor, and add Sugar untill that
re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mains unalter'd: then take Nitre, Sal-Armoniac, Alum, Vitriol, Borax, and
you will find, that your water will ſtill diſſolve a ſmall quantity of
each, becauſe the Receptacles commenſurate to the fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gure and ſize of
their minute parts did <pb n="3" facs="tcp:42878:8"/>not admit the undiſſolv'd part of
the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Salt and Sugar, by reaſon of their different ſhape and bulk.
You may ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve, that water will take up four times as much Sugar as of
green Vitriol, and twenty times the quantity of Sugar that it will diſſolve
of Borax, that what diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolves ſooneſt raiſes the water leſs; and
<hi>è contra.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It is by the proportion of the Figure, Size, and Site of the parts
of the diſſolu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble bodies to the diſſolving Liquors, that we can
account why common water is a fit Menſtruum for Senna, Rhubarb, and
Tamarinds, but altogether improper for Jalap, Turbith, and ſuch other
reſinous Mixtures as require ſulphureous Liquors, as Spirit of Wine,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> Hence it appears how abſolutely neceſſary it is for
Apothe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caries to know the various Subſtances of medicinal Drugs, both that
they may chuſe the propereſt Menſtruums, and duly regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>late their
Infuſions and Decoctions, as to degree of fire, length of time, and other
circumſtances, left by preſcription ſolely to their Prudence and
Diſcretion.</p>
            <p>When ſeveral Drugs are us'd in a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coction, the moſt ſolid,
ſuch as Woods, are firſt put in, then Roots, Barks and Fruits; next Herbs,
Berries and Seeds; <pb n="4" facs="tcp:42878:9"/>Flowers the laſt of all. The Woods,
Roots and Barks are rasp'd, bruis'd or cut ſmall, Fruits ſlit, Herbs
chop'd, Ber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries and Seeds ſlightly beat, and Flowers put in whole. However
this method, though pretty general, admits of excep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, for thin and fpungy
Wood requires leſs boyling than one that is more cloſe and ſolid. Barley
whole endures as much boyling as Wood. On the other hand, Aromatic Roots and
Woods will not bear long boyling, but their better and more eſſential parts
will diſſipate. Barks, Fruits, and Aromatick Seeds require on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly a bare
Infuſion. Liquoriſh-Roots is put in after the Herbs. The Maiden-Hairs or
Capillaries at the ſame time with the Liquoriſh or immediately after. The
cold Seeds at the ſame time as the Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers.</p>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Cephalic Decoction.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Miſletoe of the Oak, Roots of Male Peony, Avens, of
each ſix Drams; ſhavings of an Elk's hoof, Juniper-Berries, of each three
Drams; leaves of Sage, Betony, Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joram, Baſil, of each an handfull; Flowers
of Caſſadonie, Lilies of the Vallies, Clove-Gilly-Flowers, Lime-tree, of
each one Pugil; <pb n="5" facs="tcp:42878:9"/>let them be boil'd according to art, in three
quarts of common water.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Decoction ſtrain'd and ſettled will hardly keep above
two days in Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, if not plac'd in a cold Cellar, nor above four in Winter.
It is recommend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed againſt Epilepſies, Apoplexies, Lethar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gies, and other
diſtempers of the head, occaſion'd chiefly by ſtoppages in the
paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage, and ſmall Channels of the Animal Spirits, of from the turgency
of crude Humours that preſs over-much the ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of the Brain.</p>
               <p>He boils River-Crabs in his pectoral Decoction, borroweth
<hi>Sydenham</hi>'s <hi>deco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctum album,</hi> which he ſweetens with Sy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rup
of Comfrey inſtead of Sugar, when he deſigns Aſtriction. His bitter
Deco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction is the ſame with ours, only that he uſes equal parts of Wine and
Water, this and other Bitters are Febrifuges becauſe the ſaline and
ſulphureous parts they con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſt of, attenuate and diſſolve groſs
viſcid Humours, and ſo raiſe the Obſtructions that occaſion
Fevers.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Sudorific Decoction or Diet-Drink.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Of Sarſaparilla</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces, China<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>root</hi> 
                  <pb n="6" facs="tcp:42878:10"/>1 <hi>Ounce, Contrayerva and Holy-wood of each half an
Ounce, crude Antimony groſly beat and tied in a knot</hi> 4 <hi>Ounces; let
them be infus'd hot in</hi> 4 <hi>quarts of common water for</hi> 12 <hi>hours,
then boil'd to the conſumption of a third part; add towards the latter
end</hi> 6 <hi>Ounces of ſlic'd Liquoriſh, with</hi> 3 <hi>Drams of
Saſſafras Wood.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This drink is taken three or four times a day, about ſix
Ounces at a time, and continued for ſome days in Rheumatiſms to attenuate
the viſcid roapy Serum, and in the cloſe of the cure of a Gonorrhea, to
correct and carry off the peccant Humours by Tranſpiration.</p>
               <p>Priſans and Decoctions differ only in this, that the firſt
are leſs loaded with In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gredients, for being deſign'd for the ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary
drink of ſick perſons, the leſs they are clog'd with Drugs, the more
agreea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble and palatable they prove. They are much us'd in <hi>France,</hi> the
following is the common Ptiſan.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>℞. <hi>Pick'd Barley cleanſed from all filth one handfull,
let it boil in</hi> 2 <hi>quarts of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon water to the conſumption of a
third part, then add ſlic'd and beaten Liquoriſh half an Ounce, and make
the Ptiſan accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="7" facs="tcp:42878:10"/>The Liquoriſh is but ſlightly boil'd,
be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe otherwiſe it would communicate an unpleaſant bitterneſs,
eſpecially if new. There may be added Citron Peel, Cori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ander Seed, Cinamon,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> to pleaſe thoſe that love theſe things. The Priſan
ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers, that ſell it all Summer long in the Streets of <hi>Paris,</hi>
content themſelves with a bare Infuſion of Liquoriſh in fair water.
Ptiſans may be made Pectoral by additi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Raiſins, Jujubs,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> aperitive by making uſe of openning roots, or binding
thus.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>℞. <hi>Whole Barley</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces, ſhavings of
Harts-horn</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, Tormentil roots half an Ounce, Berberries one
handfull, boil them in three quarts of water, untill a third part be
conſumed.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They that would have i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> more aſtrin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent, may, inſtead of common, make uſe of
ſteel'd water.</p>
               <p>They uſe the following Infuſion at <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ris,</hi> as we do
the <hi>decoctum Sennae Gercinis</hi> here.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The common purging Infuſion.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Choice cleans'd Senna</hi> 3 <hi>Drams, Salt 
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:42878:11"/>of Tartar</hi> 1 <hi>Scruple; infuſe them hot a whole
night in</hi> 8 <hi>Ounces of water, then ſtrain and preſs out the Liquor
for a Doſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Three Drams of Senna will impregnate ſix Ounces of water, ſo
that the Tincture will not become ſtronger by addition of a greater quantity,
ſince a Menſtruum (as was ſaid before) cannot load it ſelf, but with a
determinate portion of any ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance. This Infuſion in water is
eſtee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med preferable to others made in Deco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions, becauſe the Liquor in
theſe is al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready ſo charged with Particles of other Ingredients, that
there is little or no room left for thoſe of the Senna. The Salt of Tartar
doth not only render the Menſtruum more penetrating, and conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently
fitter to draw a Tincture from the Senna, but alſo attenuates and rarifies
the viſcid ſubſtance drawn from the leaves, and ſo prevents the griping
pains that would be occaſion'd by the adheſion of this gluiſh
ſubſtance, to the inward Membrane of the Inteſtines. Inſtead of Salt of
Tartar may be us'd <hi>Sal Polycre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtum,</hi> cryſtal Mineral, or ſoluble
Tartar, commonly called Vegetable Salt; but of all Salts the Alkaline are the
moſt proper to diſſolve the viſcous ſlimy Subſtances, 
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:42878:11"/>that yield the Tincture, and to prevent Gripes. The Antients
unacquainted with theſe Salts, made uſe of Cinamon, Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tron, and
Orange-Peel, Ginger, and Carminative Seeds, which in all reſpects come far
ſhort of the other.</p>
               <p>Senna is ſaid to purge off Melancholy more than other Humours,
which if true, is perhaps, becauſe it conſiſts of fixt parts that have a
greater diſpoſition to unite and adhere to this Humour, which is fixt and
earthy, and by irritating the parts wherein it is chiefly lodg'd cauſe its
ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion.</p>
               <p>Inſtead of Spirit of Vitriol in drawing a Tincture from
Roſes, he ſometimes u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes Spirit of Sugar, ſometimes the Juices of
Barberries and Currants making amends for their leſſer acidity in the
greater quantity. Theſe Tinctures are us'd in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of Priſans in
Diarrhoea's, Hemorrha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gies, Gonorrhoea's, Whites, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Cephalic purging Apozem.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Avens, Male-Peonie, Miſle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toe of the Oak,
of each half an Ounce; leaves of Betony, Roſemary, Sage, of each half a
handfull: let them be boil'd according to art in two quarts of water, to the
Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption <pb n="10" facs="tcp:42878:12"/>of a fourth part in this Liquor ſtrain'd
without expreſſion; infuſe for</hi> 15 <hi>hours, pick'd Senna</hi> 6
<hi>Drams, choice Rhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barb, Agaric trochisk'd, of each two Drams,
Juniper-Berries</hi> 1 <hi>Dram, ſoluble Tartar
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Drams: then let the Infuſion be
ſtrain'd and preſs'd out, in which diffolve Syrup of ſolutive Roſes,
compounded with Agaric an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Syrup of
Peach Flowers of each</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Apozem is taken for ſome days together, a glaſs or two
a day, adding to or leſſening the quantity according as it works. The
quantity of the Ingredients is the leſſer in the Decoction, that there may
be more room left for the Particles of the purging Drugs in the Infuſion.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An aſtringent Emulſion.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sweet Almonds blanch'd,</hi> 6 <hi>couple; Seeds of
Cotton-tree, Plantain, Meadow-Rue, white Poppies, Quinces, Sumach, of each a
Dram and a half; beat them in a Mortar, pouring in by degrees a quart of the
Decoction of Barley, Roots of Plantain, and great Comfrey; then ſtrain and
add Syrup of dry Roſes, and Barberries of each</hi> 2 <hi>Oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, and you
have an Emulſion to be taken in four doſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="11" facs="tcp:42878:12"/>This is us'd in ſpitting of Blood, in
Dyſenteries, Hemorrhagies, Gonorrhoea's, Whites, or where-ever Aſtriction
is pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per; which it cauſes probably in corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cting the ſharpneſs of the
blood by its a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queous mucilage, and checking its brisk Circulation by mixture
of its ſluggiſh, ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritleſs parts.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Almond Milk.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sweet Almonds blanch'd</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces, beat them in
a Marble Mortar, pouring in by degrees a pint of Barley-water, and when you
have ſtrain'd the Liquor, diſſolve there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in an Ounce and a half of the
beſt refin'd Sugar.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If you put to this half an Ounce of Orange-Flower-Water, perfume
it with Musk or Ambergreece, and keep it in Ice it will drink deliciouſly. It
is much eſteem'd at <hi>Paris,</hi> and called there, <hi>Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geat des
Limonadiers.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Antinephritic Potion.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Syrup of Marſh Mallows, Oil of ſweet Almonds drawn
without fire, of each an Ounce and a half; boſt white Wine</hi> 3 
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:42878:13"/>
                  <hi>Ounces, water of Radiſhes, and Pellitory of the wall,
of each</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces; Cryſtal Mine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral</hi> 1 <hi>Dram, Spirit of
Turpentine, and of Salt, of each</hi> 8 <hi>drops, mix them all for</hi> 2
<hi>Doſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This mixture is us'd in Nephritick Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licks. Its oily ſlimy
parts, ſmooth and lenifie the urinary paſſages, dull the edge of the
ſabulous matter, and facilitate its Excretion.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Diuretick mixture.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Spirit of Turpentine one Ounce, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctified Spirit of
Salt, dulcified Spirit of Ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tre, Spirit of Creſſes, Amber, and of</hi>
Elixir proprietatis, <hi>of each</hi> 2 <hi>Drams; mix all toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Mixture is taken in white Wine and in other appropriate
Liquors, from 4 to 15 drops: it is uſefull in Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion of Urine,
Nephritick Cholicks; it attenuates and incides the gravelly mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and
cleanſes the Kidnies.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Antiepileptic Mixture.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Imperial water, Cinamon water, of <pb n="13" facs="tcp:42878:13"/>each one Ounce, rectified Spirit of Man's Skull</hi> 2 <hi>Drams;
rectified Oil of Amber, Vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>latile oleous Salt, and Tincture of Salt of Tartar,
of each one Dram; mix all together.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Mixture is proper in the falling-ſick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and other
Diſtempers of the Brain; it is taken in and out of the fit to two
Scruples.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="section">
            <head>Of Gargariſms, Maſticatories, Errhines, or Tents put up
into the Noſtrils, Inje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions and Peſſaries.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>GArgariſms</hi> are liquid mixtures deſigned for
Diſeaſes of the Throat, Mouth, Palate and Gums; they are alſo us'd
ſometimes to ſtop a Salivation, they are to be held in the mouth and not
ſwallow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Maſticatories</hi> are ſharp hot Drugs, that being chew'd
in the Mouth, open the ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lival Ducts, incide groſs Humours that ſtop the
Glands, and ſo provoke ſpitting; Tabaco, Ginger, Pellitory of
<hi>Spain,</hi> Mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtard-Seed, Pepper, Orrice-root, and ſuch like may be
us'd as Maſticatories.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Errhines</hi> are akin to theſe they are put in the Noſe
to make it run, or to <pb n="14" facs="tcp:42878:14"/>provoke ſneezing, they may be
either of a liquid or ſolid form.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Injections</hi> are us'd upon ſeveral occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons,
eſpecially in venereal caſes, to allay pain, to ſtop a running,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> and in deep Wounds.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Peſſaries</hi> are us'd only for Women, to provoke the
Menſes, ſtop undue Fluxes, or heal Ulcers: we add but a few Formules,
becauſe thoſe are to be ſeen in moſt pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctical Books.</p>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Gargle to ſtop a Salivation rais'd by Mercury.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Whole Barley</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, leaves of Plantain,
knot Graſs, red Roſes, of each half an handfull, Cypreſs Nuts, Rinds of
Granates; Flowers of Sumach, of each half an Ounce; Berberry-Seeds</hi> 2
<hi>Drams; let them be boil'd in a quart of red Wine and Water, to the
Conſumption of a third part, then ſtrain'd, diſſolve in a pint of the
Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quor</hi> 2 <hi>Drams of the aſtringent Extract of</hi> Mars, <hi>half a
Dram of Salt of Saturn, and</hi> 2 <hi>Drams of Honey of Roſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Gargle deterges and dries the Ul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers of the Mouth,
faſtneth the looſe Teeth, ſtrengthens the Gums, Cheeks, and if often
uſed, entirely ſtops a Saliva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion that continues over long.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:42878:14"/>
               <head>Paſtills to be held in the Mouth and chew'd.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Orrice, Staveſacre, of each half an Ounce;
long Pepper, Pellitory of</hi> Spain, <hi>and Muſtard-Seed, of each</hi> 2
<hi>Drams; let them be all powder'd and mix'd with a ſufficient quantity of
the Syrup of pale Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, that they may be made into Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe being put into a piece of fine Linen, and ſlightly
chew'd, open the ſalival Glands, and excretory Ducts, and by ſtimulating
the parts, cauſe a great diſcharge of tough viſcid Phlegm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Sneezing Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>White Hellebore, Tabaco-roots, of</hi> Florence
<hi>Orice, of each</hi> 2 <hi>Drams; Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Lilies of Vallies, leaves of
Betony, Marjoram, and Sage, of each one Dram; powder all together.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder may be made ſtronger, by adding a Scruple of
Euphorbium to it. It may be of good uſe in Apoplexies, Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thargies and other
ſoporiferous Diſtem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:42878:15"/>
               <head>An Injection to ſtop a Gonorrhoea.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Plantain and Roſe-water, of each</hi> 4 <hi>Ounces;
Honey of Roſes</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, medica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental Stone</hi> 1 <hi>Dram; mix
them for an Injection.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>When it's proper to uſe this Injection, it will be convenient
to take aſtringent Pills to ſtrengthen the relax'd parts: if inſtead of
the Stone [you uſe the Tro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chisks of <hi>Raſis,</hi> the Injection will be
the milder, but not ſo drying, deterſive nor aſtringent.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Vulnerary Injection.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of round Birthwort</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce; let it boil
in a pint and a half of white Wine, to the Conſumption of a third part; then
add to the Liquor ſtrain'd and preſs'd out an Ounce and half of Honey of
Roſes, Tincture of Myrrh, and Aloes, of each half an Ounce.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Injection being ſquirted or ſy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring'd into Wounds,
cleanſes and deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges them, reſiſts putrefaction, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vents in a
great meaſure a Gangrene; <pb n="17" facs="tcp:42878:15"/>the Pledgets and Compreſſes
may be dren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ched in it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Lotion to kill Vermine in the Head.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Staveſacre</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces, Worm-Seed</hi> 1
<hi>Ounce, Wormwood, Tanſey, Betony, leſſer Centaury, of each</hi> 2
<hi>handfulls; let them boil in</hi> 2 <hi>quarts of water, to the
Conſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ption of a third part; bath and waſh the head with Sponges drench'd
in the ſtrain'd Liquor.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They that would have this Lotion ſtronger, may boil the
Ingredients in U<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rine.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Lotion againſt the Itch.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of ſharp-pointed Dock, Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>campane, of each
four Ounces, white Helle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bore</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, leaves of Wormwood,
Water-Creſſes, of each</hi> 1 <hi>handfull; boil them in two quarts of
water to the Conſumption of a third part; in the ſtraining, made with
expreſſion, diſſolve</hi> 6 <hi>Drams of Salt of Tar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tar.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If the Ingredients were boil'd in the Lotions of white
Precipitate, the Liquor <pb n="18" facs="tcp:42878:16"/>would prove much more efficacious
againſt the Itch, running Sores, Scab, Tettars, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Waſh to make Hair black.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Rinds of green Wall-nuts half a pound, Bark of Oak,
Alder, Galls, of each</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces; leaves of Myrtle, Pomegranate, of
each</hi> 1 <hi>handfull; boil them in three pints of water, untill a third
part is conſumed; then ſtrain with a ſtrong expreſſion, and
diſſolve in the Liquor an Ounce and a half of Rock-Alum, and the like
quantity of</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh <hi>green Vitriol.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This darkens red hair wonderfully, if often moiſtned and, left
to dry of it ſelf without rubbing.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The common emollient Mucilage.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Marſh Mallows</hi> 4 <hi>Ounces, Lin-Seeds,
Seeds of Fenugreek, of each</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce; let them be infus'd for</hi> 12
<hi>hours in two quarts of common water over hot embers, then boil'd in a
ſlow heat to the Conſumpti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of half the water, and the Mucilage
ſtrain'd with expreſſion.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="19" facs="tcp:42878:16"/>This is not only us'd as a Mucilage, but
alſo as a Fomentation to allay Pains, ſof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten Tumours, and to diſpoſe
them to Diſſolution or Suppuration.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Mucilage to ſtop Hemorrhagies.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Seeds of Flea-wort and of Quinces, of each half an
Ounce; infuſe them for</hi> 12 <hi>hours over hot embers in a pint of the
di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtill'd waters of Plantain and Roſes; then boil them ſlowly untill a
third part is boil'd away, and let them be ſtrain'd and preſs'd
out.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Mucilage being mix'd with an e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qual quantity of Syrup of
Quinces, or ſome other aſtringent Syrup is taken of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten, and by large
Spoonfulls in all ſorts of Hemorrhagies: it cauſes a ſmoothneſs in the
Palate, defends the Throat from the ſharpneſs of Rheums, and by its ſlime
and roapy parts check the violent motion of Humours, inviſcating their
ſharp ſaline Particles.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Mucilage or Gelly of Iſinglaſs.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Iſinglaſs out ſmall</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, infuſe
it in a pint of water, and boil it gently to a Gelly.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:42878:17"/>It may be made in Milk. It is good in moſt
Fluxes, in Whites, and proves effectual, when many other Medicines fail in
ſtopping an inveterate troubleſome Gleet.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Powder for quilted or ſpice Caps.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cloves, Cinamon, Aromatick-Reed, ſweet Ruſh,
Orrice, Marjoram, Roſemary, Betony, Sage, Caſſidonie, of each</hi> 1
<hi>Dram; Laurel Berries, Storax, Benjamin, Taca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mahac, of each half a Dram,
powder all groſly, and put them into Cotton for ſpice Caps.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Quilted ſpice Caps were formerly much more in uſe than they
are now; they were believ'd to ſtrengthen and refreſh the Brain, and were
therefore commended againſt Epilepſies, Lethargies, Palſies and
Apoplexies; they conſiſt of ſubtil volatile parts, which may in ſome
ſmall quantity get through the Sutures of the Skull, and by attenuating and
rarifying tough and viſcid Humours, render them more flux'd and eaſier of
diſcharge. Musk and Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber may be added, if the patient be not ſubject to
Vapours. The Powders are not to be beaten fine, that they may not 
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:42878:17"/>ſpend themſelves too ſoon, nor paſs thro' the thin
Taffities the Caps are made of. The ſame, or like Powders may be quil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted in
Stomachers, which if they do not comfort and fortifie the Stomach, will at
leaſt keep it the warmer.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="section">
            <head>Perfumes.</head>
            <p>MEdicinal Perfumes are not all equally agreeable, there being many
ſcarce ſupportable, that are nevertheleſs very beneficial on ſeveral
occaſions, where the more pleaſant would prove deſtructive. Perfumers mix
<hi>Florence</hi> Orrice, Benjamin, Storax, <hi>Lignum Rhodium,</hi> yellow
Saun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, Aromatick-Reed, Somes, Flowers of Benjamin, and a few Cloves,
moiſten them with Orange-Flower-Water, and keep them in the cold, in a
Matraſs, and when they have occaſion to uſe the mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, they pour
ſome into Caſſolets or perfuming Pans, which plac'd in a gentle heat,
yield a moſt pleaſant ſweet ſmell.</p>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Fumigation to raiſe a Salivation in the Venereal
Pox.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cinnabar an Ounce and a half, Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niper-Berries, 
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:42878:18"/>Frankinſence, Maſtick, La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>danum, of each a Dram and a
half; let them be powder'd and kept for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This way of receiving Mercury is dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gerous, being often
attended with grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vous Accidents; whether becauſe it is all receiv'd into
one part, or affects the Nerves more. Moſt certain it is, that it will prove
far ſafer to proceed by Fri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, and other preparations of Mercu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to
raiſe a Flux; and that where theſe do not prove unſucceſsfull, fuming
with Cinnabar is by no means to be attempted. It is uſed with leſs danger
for ſtubborn venereal Ulcers, that lie remote from the Head and Throat. This
Powder, when uſed, is to be caſt into a Chafingdiſh of live Coals, and
the Fume to be receiv'd, and this to be repeated at different times, untill the
Mouth begins to be ſore, then is to be diſcontinued.</p>
               <p>Women troubled with Suppreſſion of their Menſtrua's, and
labouring under hyſteric Paſſions, may ſit over the Fumes of fit and
appropriate Pomanders: to ſla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken and diſſolve the ſluggiſh groſs
Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours that ſtagnate or circulate but very ſlowly in the
Womb-Veſſels.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="23" facs="tcp:42878:18"/>Some Aſthmaticks alſo receive Fumes and
Smoke at the Mouth and Noſe, to cut and attenuate the thick and viſcous
Phlegm that obſtructs; but this method ought not to be recommended to ſuch
as have ſpit Blood, or have Ulcers in the Lungs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>D. Brunis</hi>'s <hi>Collyrium,</hi> or Eye-water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Aloes Succotrine</hi> 1 <hi>Dram, white Wino and white
Roſe-water of each an Ounce and a half; after they have ſtood ſome days,
fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trate the water and keep it for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Madam <hi>Fouquet</hi>'s Eye-water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Prepar'd Tutia</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces, Mace finely
powder'd</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, white Vitriol</hi> 1 <hi>Dram, Fennel and
Roſe-water, of each a pint, and half a pint of Plantain-water; mix them
together, and expoſe them for ſome days to the Summer Sun in a
well-ſtop'd bottle, then keep the Collyrium for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Collyrium's are of good uſe in infirmities of the
eyes; they deterge and dry ſmall Ulcers, cure Redneſs and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flammations,
and either entirely conſume Webs and Pins, or check their growth.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:42878:19"/>
               <head>A Water to preſerve the Eyes againſt the Small
Pox.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Oriental Saffron</hi> 1 <hi>Scruple, infuſe it for
three hours in an Ounce and a half of Roſe, Plantain, and Eye-bright-waters,
diſſolve-ſixteen grains of the medicamental Stone in the filtrated
Liquor.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This clears the ſight, and by drying and conſuming the
filthy ſharp Ichor of the Small Pox, hinders its making an im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion
upon the eyes.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>℞. <hi>Orpine two Drams, Verdigreece one Dram, Myrrh, Aloes
of each a Dram, diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve all finely powder'd in a pint of white Wine, and
ſix Ounces of Plantain and Roſe-water.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is us'd in Injection to cleanſe and dry Ulcers in the
Urethra, and to ſtop runnings or a Gleet, the Virulency being corrected by
precedent proper Medicines. It may be weaken'd by addition of a greater
quantity of Plantain-water.</p>
               <p>Notwithſtanding what many famous Phyſicians and Chymiſts
have writ in commendation of red Coral, Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> 
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:42878:19"/>pretends, that they are not to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer'd to other Alcaline bodies,
whoſe whole vertue conſiſts in dulling Acids, by deſtroying their
ſharp points, or ſheathing their cutting edges: and ſays the ſo much
fam'd Tincture of Coral, is owing alto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether to an inconſiderable quantity
of worthleſs Bitumen contain'd in that mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture and concludes that white
Coral is e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very whit as good as the red.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Rob of Speedwell.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Depurated juice of Speedwell</hi> 2 <hi>pound, Sugar
or clarified Honey</hi> 1 <hi>pound; let them boil on a ſlow fire in an
earthen glaz'd veſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel to the conſiſtence of Honey.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Speedwell or Fluellin is recommended by many good Practitioners,
as an extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary purifier of the Blood, and heal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of Ulcers in the Lungs.
Doctor <hi>Elles</hi> of <hi>Hartfordſhire</hi> is a great admirer of it, as
having often us'd it with good ſucceſs.</p>
               <p>The <hi>French</hi> Acacia is made as the <hi>Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans</hi> make
their juice of Sloes inſpiſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted in B. M. It is ſubſtituted for the
true Acacia.</p>
               <p>Lotions and boiling deprive Turpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tine of a great part of its
eſſential Salts, <pb n="26" facs="tcp:42878:20"/>and conſequently of much of its
vertues; wherefore it is better to mix it with o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pening Powders, <hi>viz.</hi>
Millepedes, cryſtal Mineral, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to give it the conſiſtence
chiefly deſign'd in boiling it.</p>
               <p>Becauſe chymical Oils and Eſſences do n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> diſſolve in, nor mix with Water
through the diſproportion of the Tex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of their minute parts with this
Men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruum, they are mix'd with Sugar, wherein they divide themſelves into
im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perceptible parts; and this Intermedium readily diſſolving in water,
keeps the Oils and Eſſences ſo divided, that though they make the Liquor
look ſomewhat more white, they can never unite ſo as to appear what they
were. There is no need of Sugar to make theſe Eſſences mix with Spirit of
Wine or other ſulphureous Liquors, for here being a conformity of Texture,
they readily unite.</p>
               <p>Here followeth the deſcription of a Drug ſold for the juice
of Liquoriſh, tho' it is nothing but a Gum impregnated with a few parts of
that root. The Adul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teration is owing to <hi>Blois.</hi> In a decocti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of
Liquorice they diſſolve a vaſt quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity of Gum Arabick groſly
powder'd, add a little Sugar, then filter the Liquor and evaporate it to a due
conſiſtence, <pb n="27" facs="tcp:42878:20"/>which though thus ſophiſticated is
much better for the Lungs than a great part of that called <hi>Spaniſh</hi>
Liquorice, which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing gritty and full of impurities, muſt be rather
obnoxious than beneficial.</p>
               <p>The Ladies of <hi>Tours,</hi> much fam'd<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> for ſweet
Meats, make their Gelly of Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants thus. They boil 3 pounds of Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gar in
common water to the conſiſtence of Tablets, to which they then put four
pounds of fair ripe Currants, and let them boil ten or a dozen Wambles, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>till
the Currants burſt without being touched with a Spoon; then they pour them
upon a hair ſieve revers'd, under which is placed an earthen Diſh to
receive the Gelly, which is ſaid to be the beſt that is made in
<hi>France.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A purging Wine.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cleanſed leaves of Senna</hi> 6 <hi>drains,
Hermodactyles, roots of Arum, dried Seeds of Violets, of each</hi> 2 <hi>drams;
Agaric tro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chisk'd, choice Rhubarb, of each a dram and a half; Cinnamon</hi> 1
<hi>dram; let all be infuſed for</hi> 24 <hi>hours in a quart of white Wine,
and then filter'd to be kept for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Wine is proper for cold phlegma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick Conſtitutions; it
may be uſed a <pb n="28" facs="tcp:42878:21"/>conſiderable time: the doſe is a
glaſs in the morning faſting.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Febrifuge Wine.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Jeſuit's bark reduced into powder</hi> 2 <hi>Ounces,
good white Wine</hi> 2 <hi>quarts; put them into a large Matraſs, ſo that a
third part remain empty; then having ſtop'd the Veſſeleloſe, ſhake it
well, and put it for</hi> 24 <hi>hours in a ſand bath or in ſome other
mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derate heat, ſtirring and ſhaking the mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture now and again; which
done, pour off the Wine by inclination, leaving the mark or dregs at the
bottom.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>As ſoon as the fit is over, let the pati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent drink a glaſs
of this Wine and repeat it every fourth hour. The more turbid and leſs clear
he takes his Wine, the more effectual he will find it. For this reaſon, that
the bark in ſubſtance being of great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er efficacy than any known preparation
of it; that which contains moſt of this ſubſtance, muſt work the
greateſt effects.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Steel Wine.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Opening Saffron of</hi> Mars <hi>prepared without
fire</hi> 4 <hi>Ounces, Cinnamon, outward <pb n="29" facs="tcp:42878:21"/>rind of bitter
Oranges, of each</hi> 2 <hi>drams, Mace</hi> 1 <hi>dram, Saffron half a dram;
infuſe and let them ſtand to digeſt for</hi> 15 <hi>days in</hi> 2
<hi>quarts of good white Wine; then filter and keep the Wine for
uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Wine being an extraordinary a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peritive, brings down Womens
Menſes, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens the Obſtructions of the Spleen and Meſentery; it may be
taken from one to three Ounces, with a ſufficient quantity of Sugar, or Syrup
of opening roots to make it palatable.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Wine called Hypocrate.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Refined Sugar reduced into powder, two pound and a
half, ſweet Almonds blan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ched and bruiſed</hi> 4 <hi>Ounces, Cinnamon
groſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly powdered one Ounce and a half; let all be mixed and put in infuſion
for</hi> 24 <hi>hours in</hi> 7 <hi>quarts of good Claret, and a pint of the
beſt Brandy; then paſs twice or trice through a Wine Sack, or through</hi>
Hippocra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tes<hi>'s ſleeve, and diſſolve in the ſtrained Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quor half a
grain of Ambergreeſe, and the like quantity of Musk.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Wine warms the Stomach, and helps Digeſtion, yet is
oftner taken <pb n="30" facs="tcp:42878:22"/>for Pleaſure than as Phyſick. It is
cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>Hypocrate,</hi> either becauſe <hi>Hippocrates</hi> invented
ſome ſuch Liquor, or that it is ſtrained through ſuch a cloth as he
uſed in his Filtrations. This is different from common preparation.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The compound Claret water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cinnamon, Mace, Cloves, of each</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce,
Galangale half an Ounce, leſſer Cardamoms, Aromatick-reed, of each</hi> 2
<hi>drams; Ginger half a dram, Sugar pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered eight Ounces, Brandy one quart,
leave them to digeſt together for</hi> 24 <hi>hours, then filter the liquor
three or four times through</hi> Hippocrates'<hi>s ſleeve and put it up for
uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This water being a Tincture of the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>romatic Ingredients
ſweetned with Sugar, helps Digeſtion, expells Wind, and is a good cordial
Water; it will be purga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive if you diſſolve a dram of Reſin of Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lap
and Scammony in it; and Emetic, if you infuſe an Ounce of <hi>Crocus
metallorum</hi> in it for four or five days.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A purging Ale.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Polypodie of the Oak</hi> 1 <hi>pound, 
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:42878:22"/>Monk's Rhubarb, leaves of Senna, ſton'd Raiſins,
ſlic'd Rhubarb and horſe-Radiſh, of each three Ounces; leaves of Garden
Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy-graſs and Sage, of each four handfulls; ſlic'd Oranges number four;
infuſe them in</hi> 5 <hi>or</hi> 6 <hi>Gallons of Ale, when it is
working.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This purges mildly by Stool and Urine, it is given in the
Scurvy, Gout, Rheuma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſms, Defluxions of thin ſaline Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours to purifie
the maſs of Blood, is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued for a fortnight or three weeks to be drunk
in the morning.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Ratafia of Cherries.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Depurated juice of Cherries</hi> 6 <hi>quarts, juice
of Currants and Rasberries, of each</hi> 3 <hi>pints, good brandy</hi> 5
<hi>quarts; infuſe in theſe for two days</hi> 2 <hi>pound of Kernels or
bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken Stones of Cherries,</hi> 8 <hi>pound of refined Sugar; powdered
Coriander-ſeed, Cinnamon, Cloves groſly powdered, of each an Ounce and a
half; let them be ſtirred and ſhook together to the perfect diſſolution
of the Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gar, then ſtrained through</hi> Hippocrates'<hi>s ſteeve and
botled.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Liquor is much in faſhion now in <hi>France,</hi> and is
differently prepared accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding <pb n="32" facs="tcp:42878:23"/>to the different fanſies
and palates of thoſe that make it. This preparation comes ſhort of none,
either for taſt or goodneſs, and is abundantly better than the common
Cherry-water, which loſes much of the ſtrength of the Brandy in be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
ſet ſo long in the Sun as is uſual.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Ratafia of Clove-gilly-flowers.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Flowers of red ſingle garden Finks, well pick'd and
cleans'd from the green her<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by part</hi> 2 <hi>pounds; infuſe them for</hi> 8
<hi>days in</hi> 10 <hi>quarts of very good Brandy, in a cloſe ſtopt
Veſſel; let the Infuſion be filtrated with a ſlight expreſſion;
then put to it</hi> 7 <hi>pound of fine Sugar, Peach and Apricock Kernels a
little bruis'd, of each one dozen; Cinnamon</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, Cloves groſly
powdered half an Ounce; let them ſtand for</hi> 6 <hi>days together,
ſhaking them ſometimes, that the Sugar may be entirely diſſolved; then
ſtrain the Liquor through a woollen cloth or Wine ſack, untill it appears
fine and clear fit to be bottled for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Ratafia is much ſtronger than the former, becauſe the
Brandy is not weak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned by the addition of ſo great a quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity of juices, as
the other is. Some to have <pb n="33" facs="tcp:42878:23"/>a deeper Tincture put into the
infuſion 7 or 8 Ounces of the flowers of Corn-Pop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pies dried in the Sun.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Ratafia of Kernels or Kernel-water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Peach and Apricock Kernels beaten in a Mortar, of each
a pound and a half, Cinnamon</hi> 1 <hi>Ounce, Cloves and Coriander<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeeds
groſly powdered, of each half an ounce; fine powdered Sugar</hi> 2 <hi>pound
and a half; in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe the whole in five quarts of good Brandy in a cloſe
ſtop'd Veſſel for</hi> 20 <hi>days; then let the Liquor be filter'd
untill it becomes clear, then bottle and lay it up for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Some who think this Ratafia too ſtrong, weaken it with the
juice of Apricocks, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with the expreſſion of Muſcadine-Raiſins,
and ſome perfume it with Musk and Ambergreeſe.</p>
               <p>Some Ladies put in the Kernels whole, becauſe when they beat
them, they find the water thick and heavy; but this fault is corrected by
repeated Filtrations, thro' a Wine Sack, and the beaten Kernels load the
Menſtruum more. The mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture muſt be often ſhook whilſt in
dige<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="34" facs="tcp:42878:24"/>
               <head>A preparation of Verjuice.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sugar-candy</hi> 2 <hi>ounces, roch Allum, Magiſtery
of Biſmuth, prepared Porcelain Shells, of each an ounce; Salt of glaſs</hi>
3 <hi>drams; theſe being powder'd, mix'd, and put into a glaſs bottle, pour
on ſix quarts of diſtilled Verjuice; then ſtop the bottle, and let it
ſtand in the Sun for</hi> 15 <hi>days, ſtirring and ſhaking it often,
then let it be filter'd and kept for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This preparation of Verjuice is recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mended to ſmooth, whiten
and preſerve the complexions of Ladies. It takes away Freckles, Morphew, and
Sun-burning.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A preparation of Ox-gall.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sugar-candy</hi> 2 <hi>ounces, Roch-Allum half an
ounce, Borax and Salt of glaſs, of each</hi> 3 <hi>drams; powder all and put
them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a glaſs bottle; pour upon them</hi> 3 <hi>quarts of diſtilled
Ox-gall; ſtop the bottle and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe it for</hi> 15 <hi>days to the Sun,
ſhaking it often, then filter the liquor and keep it for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="35" facs="tcp:42878:24"/>This has much the ſame vertues with the
other, but is ſomewhat more deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive and cleanſing.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Conſerve of the roots of Enula Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pana.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Enula Campana what quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity you pleaſe,
boil them in fountain water, to a due ſoftneſs, then maſh and pulp them
through an inverſed Sieve. Let the Deco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction be boiled over a gentle fire,
with a dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble weight of Sugar to the root, to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtence of a
ſolid Electuary; and when it grows a little cold, add the pulp and put it up
for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Conſerve is of good effect in Aſth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ma's, becauſe it
conſiſts of ſulphurous ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>line parts, proper to incide and attenuate
the groſs Phlegm that is impacted to the Lungs.</p>
               <p>The Conſerve of Violets is ſomewhat looſning by reaſon
of ſharp Salt envelop'd in its mucilaginous and ſlimy parts. The Ancients
preferr'd the ſtale Conſerve of Roſes to the freſh made; becauſe the
firſt had fermented more, and had there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore its parts more looſe and
diſengag'd.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="36" facs="tcp:42878:25"/>Some ſprinkle their Roſes with a few
drops of Vitriol, which rarifying and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viding the parts that yield the
colour, render the Conſerve much more beauti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full. He makes a Conſerve of
the tops of Parſely, of the roots of Enula Campana, and of the roots of
Althaea, to be us'd in Diſtempers of the Lungs.</p>
               <p>Before Sugar was ſo common as now, Honey was much in uſe,
and is ſtill on ſeveral accounts preferr'd to Sugar. It purges more in
gliſters, deterges and clean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes Wounds better; for which reaſon it is
mix'd with Digeſtives, unites and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerves the great Compoſitions of
Treacle and Mithridate much better than Sugar would do.</p>
               <p>The Honey of <hi>Dauphiné, Languedoc</hi> and
<hi>Narbonne</hi> is commended beyond all other, becauſe thoſe Provinces
abound in flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Thime, Roſemary, Violets, Lilies of the Vallies, and
other odoriferous Plants from which this Balſom of life is gather'd, for
<hi>Democritus</hi> was of opinion, that the beſt method to prolong life was
to moi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſten the inwards with Honey, and to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noint the outward parts with
Oil. Yet ſuch as are of a bilious hot Conſtitution, ought to forbear the
uſe of it, becauſe it is apt to change into Choler the too great 
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:42878:25"/>heat of the Bowels, turning it bitter as Sugar, liquorice,
and other ſweet things when boil'd too long acquire that taſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Honey of Tabaco.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Depurated juice of Tabaco, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Honey equal
parts, let them boil to the conſiſtence of a Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Oil purges violently; it is uſed in Gliſters for
Apoplectick and Lethargick Patients. Syrups being but liquid Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerves, the
Syrup of Maiden-Hair may be very well made of the Conſerve of Maiden hair
brought from <hi>Canada;</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides the Herb having fermented with the
Sugar in that compoſition, its more active parts are looſen'd and
diſengag'd, and the more adapted for the Syrup which is thus made.</p>
               <p>Take a pound of Conſerve of Maiden-hair, infuſe it in two
quarts of warm wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter for four or five hours, then filter the Infuſion with
expreſſion, and mix there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with three pounds of fine Sugar, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving
clarified it with the white of an Egg, boil it to the conſiſtence of a
Syrup. There are ſome at <hi>Paris,</hi> that ſell well clarified 
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:42878:26"/>Sugar for this Syrup, which by reaſon of its more
agreeable taſt, takes with moſt Patients preferrably to the genuine Syrup
of Maiden-hair.</p>
               <p>Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> is much againſt Spice as corrective in the
Syrup of Succory with Rhubarb, becauſe they heat the body and clog the
Menſtruum, ſo that it can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not receive ſo many particles of the Rhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barb,
as otherwiſe it would; whereas fix'd Alkali ſalts, as that of Succory helps
to draw a more ſaturate Tincture from the Rhubarb, and renders the Syrup
con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderably more deobſtruent.</p>
               <p>He recommends ſoluble Tartar for a general corrective of
purgers, becauſe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Salt, it is much more proper to at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenuate and
rarifie viſcous roapy Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances, that otherwiſe would be apt to adhere
to the inward Membranes of the Bowels, and gripe in their paſſage.</p>
               <p>In the compoſition of the Syrup of Peach flowers, may be
uſed the more tender leaves of the tree; and the Infuſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of both is to be
repeated, untill they come out undiſcolour'd, then the Men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruum is as
much impregnated as it can be from theſe Subſtances.</p>
               <p>The Syrup of dry Roſes becomes of a much fairer colour, by
adding to it when <pb n="39" facs="tcp:42878:26"/>boil'd to its due conſiſtence;
ten<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> twelve drops of Spirit of
Vitriol or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Sulphur, or a dram
and a half of the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of Sugar or 2 ounces of the Syrup of Berberries or of
Pomegranate.</p>
               <p>Experience teaches, that the ſureſt corrective of the Syrup
of Buck-thorn-berries is to eat ſoon after taking of it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Syrup of Scammony.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Choice Scammony groſly powder'd</hi> 6 <hi>drams,
Liquorice raſp'd and beaten</hi> 3 <hi>drams; infuſe them for three days in
a pint and a half of good Brandy; then filter the Tin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture, add</hi> 2
<hi>pound of Sugar, and evapo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate it into a Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Diagridium Glycyrrhiſatum</hi> is made after this manner.
Half an ounce of ſlic'd Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quorice being infus'd for 2 hours in 9 ounces of
hot water, the Liquor is pour'd into an earthen glaz'd Pipkin upon 4 oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of
Scammony, and put upon a gentle fire untill the moiſture being conſumed,
the Scammony becomes ſolid and firm as before: this given from half a Scruple
to a Scruple purges briskly without griping in the leaſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:42878:27"/>
               <head>Syrup of wild Saffron.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Seeds of wild Saffron bruiſed</hi> 4 <hi>ounces,
leaves of Senna cleanſed</hi> 1 <hi>ounce and a half, choice Rhubarb</hi> 6
<hi>drams, Agaric trochisk'd, and ſoluble Tartar, of each half an ounce,
infuſe them over hot embers for</hi> 24 <hi>hours in</hi> 3 <hi>pints of
diſtill'd Bugloſs-water; then ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving boil'd them a little, filter with
expreſſion. In the ſtrain'd Liquor clarify'd by ſetling, and a ſecond
filtration, diſſolve a pound and a half of refin'd Sugar, half a pound of
ſolu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Syrup of Roſes, and then boil them in a gentle heat to the
conſiſtence of a Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Syrup purges gently, and carries off a great quantity of
Seroſity, and may be us'd upon moſt occaſions, where pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging is proper,
eſpecially in Cachexies, Dropſies, and Rheumatiſms, Melancho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, Mania,
from half an ounce to an ounce and a half in white Wine or ſome aperient
Decoction.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Syrup of <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Broom corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Depurate juice of Broom-flowers</hi> 3 <hi>pints, tops
of keys of Aſh and Fumitory, of each one pound; add to them Senna</hi> 4
<hi>oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, <pb n="41" facs="tcp:42878:27"/>Tamarinds</hi> 3 <hi>ounces, ſeeds of
Violets beaten</hi> 2 <hi>ounces, Polypody of the Oak pound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed</hi> 1 <hi>ounce
and a half, Salt of Broom</hi> 1 <hi>ounce, let them macerate together for
three days over hot Embers, then being boil'd a little and ſtrain'd,
depurated and ſetling, and a ſecond filtration, diſſolve in it two
pound of refin'd Sugar, a pound of the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compound Syrup of Apples, and boil it
over a gentle fire into Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Syrup is given with ſucceſs to o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen Obſtructions of
the Liver, Spleen, Meſentery and Matrix, it purges gently viſcous and
tenacious humours, the O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riginal of Cachexies, Dropſies, Melancho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and
often of the ſuppreſſion and irre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gularities of the Menſes. It is a
great purifier of the blood, may be taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lone, from half an ounce to two
ounces, or mix'd with diſtill'd waters, white Wine or ſome appropriated
Decoction.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Emetic Syrup.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Liver of Antimony finely powder'd an ounce and a half,
depurated juice of Quin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces</hi> 1 <hi>quart, put them to digeſt over hot
embers, for</hi> 6 <hi>days in a Matraſs well ſtop'd, ſhaking and
ſtirring it often; then filter the liquor, and with a pound of refin'd Sugar 
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:42878:28"/>boil it over a gentle fire to the conſiſtence of a
Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Syrup empties the Stomach of hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours that are ſometimes
ſo obſtinately fix'd, as not to yield to purgatives, there is no
preparation of Antimony that works with more gentleneſs, or with leſs
trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble; but ſhould it at any time prove rough and churliſh in its
operation, either fat broth or oil will in entangling and involving its keen
edges abate the, irrita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. It is given to all Ages and Sexes, proportioning
the doſe to the ſtrength of the patient: it may be taken alone or in white
Wine broth or other conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent liquor, and it is ſometimes mix'd with
Purgatives. The uſual doſe, when it is gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven alone, is from 6 drams to an
ounce and a half.</p>
               <p>In the remarks upon the Syrup of Wormwood, we find this method
of ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king a Syrup of Wormwood at pleaſure without fire, <hi>viz.</hi> ℞.
Wine of Worm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood and refin'd Sugar reduc'd into pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, of each equal weight,
put a ſmall quantity of Cinnamon-water to them, and ſhake all together to
the entire diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolution of the Sugar. A good Tincture may be made thus; put
what quantity <pb n="43" facs="tcp:42878:28"/>you pleaſe of dry tops of Wormwood into a
Matraſs, pour on Spirit of Wine, untill they are throughly humected, then
ſtop the veſſel, and leave them to digeſt 5 or ſix days, afterwards
filter the liquor with expreſſion, and when it has ſetled, ſtrain it a
ſecond time: it ſtrengthens the Stomach, helps Digeſtion, and provokes
Womens Ordinaries, being given from 6 drops to 30.</p>
               <p>Beſides the Syrup of Verjuice, there is a water, which is
nothing elſe but com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon water and Sugar put to the depura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted or diſtill'd
Juice; and this will keep better, if you add a ſmall quantity of Salt to it.
It cools, refreſhes, and provokes Urine.</p>
               <p>He makes a Syrup of the white of 8 Eggs beaten and diſſolv'd
in 3 pints of water, and boil'd with 2 pounds of Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gar unto the
conſiſtence of a Syrup, to be us'd where mucilaginous Medicines are
proper.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The compound Magiſterial Syrup.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of common Orrice, Hermoda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctyles, of each</hi> 2
<hi>ounces, gummy Turbith, Mechoacan, Jalap, of each</hi> 1 <hi>ounce and a
half; dwarf Elder and choice Rhubarb, <pb n="44" facs="tcp:42878:29"/>leaves of Senna,
ſoluble Tartar, of each an ounce; trochisk<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d Agaric, Seeds of Violets, leaves of baſtard Hedge-Hyſſop, of
each half an ounce; let all be pounded, then infus'd for</hi> 4 <hi>days
in</hi> 2 <hi>quarts of good white Wine; filter the Tincture through Cap-paper,
or through</hi> Hippocrates<hi>'s ſleeve, and evaporate it upon a ſlow fire
to the conſistence of a Sy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rup. Then let the drugs that were infus'd be
boil'd in three quarts of common water to the conſumption of a quart, and
then being filter'd, boil the liquor with</hi> 4 <hi>pound of good Sugar, and
with</hi> 4 <hi>ounces of clarified Honey to the conſiſtence of a Syrup,
mixing exact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly the above mentioned Tincture with it, as it boils to its due
conſiſtence.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Syrup purges briskly, and may be given with good
ſucceſs in hydropical and gouty caſes. It is taken in white Wine in an
appropriate decoction, or by it ſelf, from half an ounce to an ounce and a
half.</p>
               <p>They that mix Acids with their Syrup of Violets, as Spirit of
Vitriol, Spirit of Sulphur, Juice of Citrons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> do, its true,
heighten its colour, and render it more pleaſant to the Palate, but this
mix<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ture ſoon occaſions a Fermentation that turns the Syrup reddiſh and
makes it keep the leſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:42878:29" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <head>A ſtrengthing Syrup.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Choice Rhubarb ſlie'd</hi> 4 <hi>ounces, red Roſes
well pick'd and cleanſed three ounces, white Tartar groſly powdered one
ounce; let all infuſe</hi> 24 <hi>hours in three quarts of ſteel'd water
over hot embers, then boil it a little, which done, ſtrain the liquor from
the groſs Ingredients; add</hi> 4 <hi>pound of Sugar, clari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie it with the
white of an Egg, and boil it into a Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Syrup is highly commended to ſtrengthen the Stomach, and
to repair the impair'd Tone of its Fibres. It is of good uſe in Diarrhoeas,
Lienteries, and bloody Fluxes, in the over-flowing of the Menſes, Whites,
troubleſome Gleets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is taken faſting alone, or mix'd
with proper Decoctions from 1 to 2 ounces.</p>
               <p>The Syrup of Coral is found fault with, becauſe the vertue of
the Coral, which wholly conſiſts in its abſorbing Acids, is ſo much
impair'd by the ſowre Juice of Berberries, that it can dull but few pec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cant
Acids in the body, the Pores where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in it might ſheath them, being already
ſatiate. And moſt certainly to powder Coral very fine is the beſt way to
prepare it for medicinal uſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:42878:30"/>
               <head>Syrup of Cinnamon.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Beſt Cinnamon groſly powder'd half a pound, put it
into a glaſs Cucurbit, and pour on it a quart of Sack; then place it in B.
and having fitted a head and recipient, let it ſtand in Digestion</hi> 3
<hi>days, and then be diſtill'd with a moderate fire to</hi> 8 <hi>ounces;
when the Cucurbit is cold, take out the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder, put a pint of common water
to it, and boil it a little, then filter the liquor with expreſſion, and
having added</hi> 2 <hi>pound of refin'd Sugar, clarif<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> it, and let it be boil'd to the conſiſtence of an
opiate, mixing with it as it grows cold its ſpirituous water, and</hi> 6
<hi>drops of oil of Cinnamon.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>By this diſtillation you preſerve the ſpi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rituous-volatile
parts, that would be loſt and by the boiling you have what is more fix'd.
After this method may be prepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red Syrup of Cloves, Saſſafras-wood,
A<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>niſa and Coriander Seeds, Mace, Juni<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>per-berries, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It
ſtrengthens the Sto<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mach, helps Digeſtion, provokes the Ca<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tamenia, and is
good againſt a ſtinking breath, it may be taken to an ounce.</p>
               <p>The Syrup of white Poppies is not gi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ven in as large a Doſe in
<hi>Provence, Lan<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>guedoc,</hi> 
                  <pb n="47" facs="tcp:42878:30"/>and other hot Climates as
with us, becauſe they are more Narcotick there, than in our colder Country;
their effect ſeems to proceed chiefly from their ſlimy glutinous
ſubſtance, which in thick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning their humours, ſtays Defluxions and takes
off the Acrimony that often inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts ſleep; they ſtop the violence of
coughing, and give great help to thoſe that ſpit blood.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Syrup of Quina Quinae, or Jeſuits Bark.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Jeſuits Bark, groſly beat half a pound, infuſe
it for</hi> 3 <hi>days over hot embers in two quarts of white Wine, then boil
it gently to the conſumption of a fourth part, then filter and add to the
ſtrain'd liquor</hi> 3 <hi>pounds of refin'd Sugar, clarifie and boil it to a
Sy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It may be to 2 ounces in a glaſs of Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taury water.</p>
               <p>The Strawberry and Rasberry waters, ſold by the
<hi>Limonadiers</hi> at <hi>Paris</hi> are thus prepar'd: They maſh the fruit
in a Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Mortar; then they add as much Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gar and water as is neceſſary
to render the liquor clear and palatable; and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving let it ſtand for ſome
hours, they <pb n="48" facs="tcp:42878:31"/>pour it ſeveral times out of one veſſel
into another; then they filter it through a woollen cloth, untill it becomes
clear, which when it does, they put it to cool in Ice.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Syrup of Mucilages.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Seeds of Althea, Mallows, Quinces, of each one ounce,
Gumm Tragacanth,</hi> 3 <hi>drams, infuſe them over hot Embers for</hi> 6
<hi>hours in a quart of Decoction of Mallow-ſeeds; of white Poppies, and
Alkekengi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berries; then preſs out the Mucilage, and add to it a pound and a
half of the beſt Sugar and boil it to the conſiſtence of a
Syrup.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Syrup is deſervedly commended in diſeaſes of the
Breaſt, chiefly where ſharp acrimonious and thin humours are to be ſtay'd
and allay'd. It defends by its ſlimy Mucilage the Throat from the
ſharpneſs of Rheums, the Stomach from corroſive Humours and Medicines,
and the Ureters and Urethra from ſometimes ſcarce the inſupportable
Acrimony of the Urine.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Syrupus Kermeſinus</hi> without fire, may be made thus:
beat grains of Kermes full ripe in a Marble Mortar, and mix with 
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:42878:31"/>them a triple quantity of refin'd Sugar finely powder'd;
ſtir them often toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and leave them to digeſt in the cold ten or
twelve Hours, then ſtrain them with expreſſion through a clean Linen
Cloth; the filter'd Liquor is the Syrup, and retains ſome Volatile parts that
would be loſt the ordinary way: Syrup of Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons may be thus made, and a
Syrup of Peach Flowers by beating and mixing in a Marble Mortar ſome Pounds
of the Flowers with an equal weight of Sugar; as 4 Pound of each, putting half
a Pint of Water to them, and ſtirring them toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther to the conſiſtence
of a Liquid Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve, then cover an Earthen Pot glaz'd, with Linen or
Taffety, tie the Cloth round the Brim, that it may bear down in the middle,
where put the Conſerve; cover it with another Cloth, and place the Pot in a
cold Cellar; the Liquor that will drop into the Pot is the Syrup, what remains
being boil'd in Water, and clari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy'd, will make the common Syrup of
Peach-Flowers.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Powder againſt Worms us'd by the Phyſicians of
<hi>Paris.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Seeds of Tanſey, common Wormwood, 
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:42878:32"/>Purſlain, Aloes, of each half an Ounce; choice Rhubarb,
pickt Senna, Corallina, dry tops of Scordium, of each</hi> 2 <hi>Drachms,
powder all together.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder kills Worms, and carries them off, together with a
naſty Slime; it alſo brings down Women's Menſtrua. It may be taken to
half a Drachm in Syrup, Conſerve, or in the Pulp of a roaſted Apple The
<hi>Semen contra vermes</hi> or Wormſeed is leſs nauſeous, wherefore it
may be given Children without any addition.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Mynſicht</hi>'s Powder of Jalap.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>The beſt and moſt reſinous Root of Ja<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lap two
Ounces and a half, cryſtal of Tar<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tar half an Ounce, Oyl of Cinnamon one
Scru<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ple, beat them into fine Powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is given in Dropſies,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning and fixt Gouts,
Rheumatiſms, <hi>&amp;<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> from one Scruple to four: Some call
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>Pulvis Solutivus
Tartariſatus.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Anti-epileptick Powder, common<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> call'd <hi>Powder of
Gutteta.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Male Peony, Miſletoe
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <pb n="51" facs="tcp:42878:32"/>the Oak,
unburied Human Scull, Hoof of an Elke of each three Drachms, Seeds of Baſil
and of Peony, of each two Drachms; Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Betony, Tyle, of each</hi> 4
<hi>Scruples; Powder of Diambra without Musk, one Drachm; Sugar of Roſes
equal weight to all the reſt, or two Ounces ſix Drachms; ten Leaves of
Gold; powder all according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Gutteta</hi> in the <hi>Languedoc Patois</hi> ſigni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fies,
the Falling-Sickneſs, againſt which this Powder is of great efficacy, as
alſo a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Apoplexies and Palſies. It is uſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally given from half a
Scruple to half a Drachm in Cephalick Waters. Children born in the Southern
Countries are more ſubject to Worms, and conſequently to Fits, than thoſe
born in the more cold and Northern Climates.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A famous Anti-epileptick Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Shavings of a Man's Scull dead of a violent Death,
Livers and Hearts of Vipers, Elke's-hoof, of each five Drachms; Miſle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toe of
the Oak, Roots of Peony, Valerian, Contrayerva, and White Amber, of each half
an Ounce; Woman's After-burthen <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>leans'd from its Membranes and dryed, Bone <pb n="52" facs="tcp:42878:33"/>taken
out of a Deers Heart, Peacocks Dung, of each three Drachms; Cinnabar of
Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony and Volatile Salt of Harts-horn, of each one Drachm; powder all
according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Compoſition conſiſts of choice and appropriate
Ingredients, and may be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferr'd to any yet publickly known, not only
againſt Epilepſies but againſt Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vulſions of any kind. It may be
taken by Women without danger of raiſing Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pours a whole Month without
intermiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, in Syrup of Peony or ſome appropri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate Conſerve, in
Cephalick Waters or Decoctions.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An extraordinary Powder againſt Dy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſenteries.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Root of Ipecacuanha two Ounces, Yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low Myrabolans,
choice Rhubarb, of each three Drachms; Seeds of Meadow Rue two Drachms; powder
all according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder Vomits, and works by Stool. It owes its chief vertue
to the Ipeca<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cuanha, the beſt and moſt Soveraign Re<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>medy now known
againſt Dyſenteries and other Belly Fluxes. It was brought into 
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:42878:33"/>
                  <hi>France</hi> in 86 by one <hi>Helvetius</hi> a young
Dutchman, and held a great Secret untill the King purchas'd it for his
Soldiers, and afterward charitably publiſh'd it for the publick good. Being
at <hi>Paris</hi> that Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, I do remember the College Phyſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cians did
what lay in them to hinder the uſe of this Remedy, would not allow tryal to
be made of it at <hi>L'Hotel dieu</hi> or other Hoſpitals, tho' a great
number died daily of a Dyſentery that was very rife that Seaſon, until the
King hearing that Fluxes began to ſweep away a great ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of his Swiſs
that were at work at <hi>Marli,</hi> ſent abſolute Orders it ſhould be
try'd in the City Hoſpitals. Then the Phyſicians delegated two of their
number to attend <hi>Helvetius,</hi> hear what Queſtions he ask'd, ſee what
he gave, and the Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs; who obſerving that his Powder did only vomit and
purge, mix'd emetick Tartar and Rhubarb, which curing two or three ſlight
Dyſenteries, they conclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, the Secret was ſome ſuch common Mixture,
but further tryal ſoon diſabus'd them, and made them own, they knew nothing
comparable to his, which ſeldom fails if timely given, or unleſs the
Patient is diſeas'd in his Lungs, under conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble decay, Hydropick,
diſorder'd in his <pb n="54" facs="tcp:42878:34"/>Head, has a Hiccough, vomiting pains,
in the lower Belly, accompanied with Stools reſembling the waſhing of
Fleſh and ſmel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling like Carrion. <hi>Gulielmus Piſo</hi> in his
<hi>Medicina Braſilienſis</hi> deſcribes two ſorts of Ipecacuanha, one
a thick ſtringy white Root, call'd by the <hi>Portugueſe, Ipecacuan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ha
Blancha,</hi> to diſtinguiſh it from the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, it is the milder of the
two; and may be ſafely given to Big-bellied Women and to Children; the other
is a ſmall crooked knotty Root, of a darkiſh colour, of an ungrateful,
bitter, hot, and acri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monious taſt. It is given in Powder to a Drachm, in
Infuſion to about two Drachms; the Natives uſe the Infuſion moſt. The
Powder that has ſtood in Infuſion is not to be deſpiſed, for tho' it
purges but weakly, it is a very good Aſtringent and Strengthener of the
relax'd Fibres of the Stomach and Guts. <hi>Georgius Marogra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vius</hi> in his
<hi>Hiſtoria rerum naturalium Bra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiliae,</hi> ſays, That this Root is
not unlike Tormentil in Colour, that it has a white Pith in the middle,
eaſily ſeparable from the other part; ſays, that when it is freſh it
has a very bitter biting taſt; and adds, that a Drachm or two of its Powder
ſteep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed all Night in a Mixture of Wine and Water, ſlightly boil'd in the
Morning, the <pb n="55" facs="tcp:42878:34"/>Infuſion filter'd and drunk, is not only an
excellent Remedy in Dyſenteries, ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtinate Obſtructions, and
Diſaffections of the Stomach, but alſo a great reſiſter of Poiſon. I
have dwelt the longer upon this Root becauſe it begins to be pretty much
preſcrib'd now with us, and will not fail of growing into greater uſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Powder to help Digeſtion.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sweet Fenil-Seeds, Annis-Seed, and Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riander-ſeed,
of each an Ounce and a half; Cinnamon, outward Rind of Citron and O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>range, of
each three Drachms; Cloves and Rhubarb of each one Drachm, Sugar-candy eight
Ounces; powder all according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder helps Digeſtion, creates an Appetite,
ſtrengthens a weak, cold Stomach, expells Wind. It will correct the noiſom
Steams of the Stomach and Lungs, and ſo ſweeten ſtinking Breath if a few
Grains of Ambergriſe be added. It may be taken to two Drachms.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Hartman</hi>'s Simple Cachectick Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Of the opening Saffron of</hi> Mars <hi>half an Ounce,
Cinnamon or Caſſia Lignea one <pb n="56" facs="tcp:42878:35"/>Ounce and a half,
Sugar-candy two Ounces; reduce all into Powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It is given to raiſe Obſtructions, and is commended
againſt the Retention and Ir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>regularities of the Menſes, Jaundice, and all
manner of ill habits of Body proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from, or fomented by want of due
Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretions. It is taken from half a Drachm to two Drachms, and continued a
conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable time; the Patient muſt walk and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſe during its
uſe.</p>
               <p>At <hi>Toulouſe</hi> and in ſeveral other places about it
are found Bodies ſtill entire that have been buried two hundred Years a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goe,
but it is obſervable that Lime has been formerly kept in the Cellars where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in
they are found; they appear ſo little altered, that many are ſeen with
their Beards. It is alſo obſervable, that Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>balming ſucceeds better in
hot than in colder Countries, becauſe the Moiſture of Vaults in cold
Climates makes the Drugs give and run, whereas in thoſe that are warmer, the
Earth being dry, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bounding more with Salt, helps to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve Bodies
from Corruption. In hot Countries are alſo ſometimes found dead Bodies on
the Sea-coaſts, which being ſal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by the Sea-water, and afterwards 
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:42878:35"/>dry'd by the Sun may be us'd for Mum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Powder that haſtens the Birth.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cinnanton, Cretan Dittany, Saffron, Borax, of each two
Drachms; Trochiſces of Myrrh one Drachm, Savine half a Drachm; reduce them
into Powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It quickens Labour, brings on the Pains, and expells the
After-burthen. It may be alſo given with ſucceſs to bring down the
Menſtrua. The Doſe from 15 Grains to two Scruples in White-wine or Mugwort
Water.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Diuretick Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>River Crab's-Eyes, the ſtony Bones found in the
Heads of Pearches, and leſſer Whitings, dry'd Cheſlops or Hogs-lice,
Goat's Blood prepared, and Seeds of Gromel, of each an Ounce; powder them for
uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is aperitive, proper in Nephritick Cholicks,
ſtoppages of Urine from ſlimy Gravel, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is given to a
Drachm in White-wine, or in an appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priate opening Decoction.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="58" facs="tcp:42878:36"/>
               <head>The Solutive Powder of Sarſaparilla.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sarſaparilla an Ounce and a half, Leaves of Senna
one Ounce, Hermodactyles, Turpethum, Jalap, of each half an Ounce; Diagrydium
and white Tartar of each two Drachms, Olibanum and Annis-ſeed of each one
Drachm; reduce them into Powder ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder purges ſerous watry Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours, is uſed not only
in Dropſies, Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion of the Menſes, Sciatica's, and ſuch like
Diſtempers, but alſo to carry off by Stool and Tranſpiration the Dregs of
an inveterate Clap or Pox; it is given from one Scruple to ſour.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>℞. <hi>Warts that grow on the inſide of Horſes Legs taken
off in the Spring, one Ounce; Aſſafaetida, Horn and Hoof of a Goat, of each
one Drachm; reduce them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to powder.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Dukes Compound Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cinnamon two Drachms, Ginger, leſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſer Galangal,
Cloves, Nutmegs, Carda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moms, Cubebs, long Pepper, of each one 
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:42878:36"/>Scruple; Saffron half a ſcruple, Sugar-candy half a
Pound; reduce them into powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder rarifies and diſſipates groſs viſcous
Humours that adhere to the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner Coat of the Stomach and hinder Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſtion.
The ſimple Powder conſiſting of half an Ounce of Cinnamon, and half a
Pound of Sugar-candy is more palatable than this, but is not of equal efficacy;
the Seeds of Wild Carrot, Gromel, Sweet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fennil, Parſley, and ſuch like
other with Juniper Berries, Leaves of Cretan Ditta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, Powder of the Roots of
<hi>Florence</hi> Orrice may be added to the Compound Powder to extend its
Vertue to expel Wind and Gravel, and to make it more convenient in Nephritick
Cholicks. Theſe Powders may be made up into an Electu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ary with a convenient
quantity of Sugar or clarify'd Honey.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Ophthalmick Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>White Sugar-candy two Drachms, pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd Tutty one
Drachm, Aloes, Salt of</hi> Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn, <hi>White Vitriol, Sarcocolla, of each
half a Drachm,</hi> Florence <hi>Orrice half a Scruple.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is blown into the Eyes to <pb n="60" facs="tcp:42878:37"/>cleanſe them from Filth and Corruption, to diſſipate Cataracts
and conſume out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Films.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Grey Imperial Powder againſt the Plague.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Burnet, Gentian, Tormentil, Serpentwort,
Juniper Berries, Leaves of Rue and Wormwood, of each one Ounce; Caſtoreum
half an Ounce; reduce them into Powder according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is given in Malignant Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers, and as well to cure
as preſerve from Infection in time of Peſtilence from ten Grains to two
Scruples. It may be made into Pills with equal parts of Treacle and Vinegar of
Roſes, and a Paſte of beaten Nuts; or with Treacle, Mithridate, and a
little quantity of Spirits of Wine. There is a red powder deſign'd for the
ſame end with this, it contains beſides theſe Ingredients,
Bole-Armoniack, Brimſtone, Zedoary, Ginger, Cretan Dittany, Harts-Horn,
Myrrh, Camphire, and Saffron; it may be made into Pills as the other; both ſo
made are called <hi>Plague Pills.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:42878:37"/>
               <head>The Golden Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Opening Saffron of</hi> Mars, <hi>refin'd Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gar, of
each two ounces; Cinnamon and Galangal, of each half an ounce; Annis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeed two
drachms, four leaves of Gold; re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce them into powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder opens Obſtructions, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vokes the Menſes, and
cures pale Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plexions; it will be convenient to walk upon the taking this or
any other Cache<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctick Remedy, to promote its diſtributi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. It is given from
a Scruple to a Drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Powder of Aſhes corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Aſhes of the Herb Kali and Roots of Colewort, of
each three drachms; Seeds of Stone Parſley, Marſh-mallows, black Pep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per,
tops of Penny-royal, of each a drachm and a half; ſweet Flag, prepar'd Goat's
Blood, Scorpions and dry'd Egg-ſhells, of each one drachm; mix and reduce
them to powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is given to cleanſe the Kid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys and Bladder from
Gravel and trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleſome roapy Mucus, that ſometimes ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructs the
urinary paſſage.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:42878:38"/>
               <head>A Carminative Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cummin and Annisſeeds of each three ounces, white
Ginger ſix drachms, Mace three drachms, and Oriental Saffron one drachm;
reduce all into very fine powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is proper in the Wind Cholick, and does help
Digeſtion: It may be taken immediately after Meals from half a drachm to a
drachm and a half.</p>
               <p>This Powder conſiſting of. Salino-Sulphureous Volatile
Parts, is therefore proper to open the Obſtructions of the Matrix, part
thereof being caſt upon Coals and the Fumes receiv'd in the lower parts thro'
a Funnel. It alſo helps Women ſubject to Fits, and is a quick Remedy and
much rely'd on in Suffocations of the Womb.</p>
               <p>A drachm and a half of Red Roſes well dry'd infus'd in three
ounces of dul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cify'd Spirit of Vitriol, yield a moſt beau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiful Red. This
Spirit is given in Diar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rhaea's, Lienteries, and in Bloody Fluxes, in
overflowings of the Menſes, vomiting, ſpitting of Blood, and all manner of
He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morrhagies. It is alſo mix'd to a grate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful <pb n="63" facs="tcp:42878:38"/>Acidity in
appropriate Liquors in Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Powder of Steel us'd by the Phyſicians of
<hi>Paris.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Filings of Steel prepar'd two ounces, Cinnamon ſix
drachms, Myrrh, roots of Birthwort, and the greater Madder, tops of Time,
Wild-marjoram, Feverfew, Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Calamint, Penyroyal, Mugwort, Hyſſop,
Horehound, Balm, Mint, Pimpernel, Beto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, Savine, of each two drachms; Seeds
of Lovage, Rue, Parſley, great Cummin, of each a drachm and a half; Mace two
Scru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples; reduce all into powder to be kept for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder opens gently obſtructions of the Bowels, and is
therefore a good Remedy againſt the Green-ſickneſs, Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chexies, Jaundice,
and a coming Drop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſie; it kills Worms, brings down the Menſes: It is given
from a Scruple to a Drachm made into Pills.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Hand Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Dregs or Cakes of bitter and ſweet Almonds, Rice
flower, of each ſix <pb n="64" facs="tcp:42878:39"/>ounces; Roots of Florence Orice and
pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd white Chalk, of each one ounce, Ben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zoin, Sperma ceti, Salt of
Tartar, of each two drachms, Oyl of Rhodian Wood half an ounce; reduce them
into powder.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Powder againſt a Pleuriſie.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Prepar'd Goats Blood one ounce, pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of Vipers,
Antimonium diaphoreticum, flowers of Corn Poppies, prepar'd Crab's-eyes,
Boar's-tooth, ſeeds of Carduns Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictus, Olibanum, of each one drachm;
re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce them into powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder abſorbs the Acids that fix and ſtagnate the
Blood, ſo helps to give it its due circulation, and to throw off by
tranſpiration the hoſtile matter.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Imperial Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cinnamon ten drachms, Ginger one ounce, Cloves half an
ounce, leſſer Galan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal, Mace, Nutmegs, of each two drachms, Musk ten
grains.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This helps Concoction, expels Wind, corrects the noiſom Steams
of the Sto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mach and ill ſmell of the mouth.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:42878:39"/>
               <head>Powder of Cinnabar.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Native Cinnabar prepar'd half an ounce, ſhaving of
an Elks Horn three drachms, Man's Skull, Miſletoe of the Oak, of each two
drachms; dry roots and ſeeds of Peony of each a drachm and a half, powders
call'd</hi> Diamoſchi <hi>and</hi> Diambra <hi>of each one drachm, Oriental
Saffron, and volatil Salt of Amber, of each one ſcruple; powder all.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is uſed as other Anti-epileptick Powders againſt the
Falling-ſickneſs and other Convulſions: It is taken from one ſcruple to
two.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Powder of Turbith with Rhubarb cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Gummy Turbith two ounces, choice Rhubarb ten drachms,
Hermodactyles one ounce, Diagrydium, Chryſtals of Tartar and Violet ſeeds,
of each half an ounce; reduce all into powder:</hi> That may be given to a
drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s Sudorifick Powder.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Contrayerva five drachms, roots of Valerian,
Maſterwort and Angelica <pb n="66" facs="tcp:42878:40"/>of each half an ounce, leaves of
bleſs'd Thi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtle, Crabs-eyes and Muſſel-ſhells prepar'd, of each two
drachms; Saffron four ſcruples, Camphire two ſcruples, Laudanum half a
drachm; reduce them into powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Powder is a good Sudorifick, and is therefore
ſucceſsfully us'd in malignant and intermitting Fevers; it abates
Hyſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick Vapours; it is given from a ſcruple to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Trochisks of Ramich correct.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cypreſs Nuts, Myrtle Berries, Gum Arabick, of each
an ounce and a half, red Roſes, yellow Saunders, of each ten drachms; Sumach,
ſhavings of Ivory, of each one ounce, Cloves, Mace, Nutmegs, of each half an
ounce; Camphire four ſcruples; powder all and mix them into a Paſt with the
in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpiſſated Juice of Sorrel, and form Trochisks according to
art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They are given to a drachm in Fluxes and Hemorrhagies, and in
all other caſes where Aſtriction is proper: They are to be finely powder'd,
and to be mix'd with Aſtringent Waters or Decoctions, and to be taken at a
diſtance from Meals.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="67" facs="tcp:42878:40"/>
               <head>Trochisks for a Gonorrhea.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Bole Armene two drachms, prepar'd Amber, ſhavings of
Ivory, of each one drachm and a half, Seeds of Plantain four ſcruples, Agnus
Caſtus, Lettice, flowers of Pomgra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate and red Roſes of each one drachm,
Wood of Saſſafras two ſcruples: let all be pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd and mix'd with
Mucelage drawn from the ſeeds of Quinces in the Water of Nymphea or Water
Lily, and let them be made into Trochisks.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>A drachm of theſe Trochisks may be diſſolv'd in eight
ounces of Plantane Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and an ounce of Honey of Roſes ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded for an
Injection; but neither this nor any other Aſtringent is ever to be us'd
un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til the Virulency is carry'd off by Stool and Urine, and the running appears
white and of a due conſiſtence. To uſe any ſooner is a certain way to
lodge the Infection and give the Pox.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Trochisks of Pomgranate Flowers.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Pomgranate flowers one ounce, red Roſes,
Bole-armene, Gum Arabick, of each half an ounce, true Acacia three drachms; 
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:42878:41"/>powder and mix them all with a ſufficient quantity of the
Mucilage of Gum-Traga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>canth extracted in Roſe Water, then form the
Trochisks.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe are us'd as the former, and may be given where it is
convenient to bind, as in all Hemorraghies, Belly Fluxes, in the Diabetes,
Diſeaſes of the Breaſt caus'd by Defluxions, for they thicken Humours and
qualify Acrimony.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Eſcharotick Trochisks.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Corroſive Sublimate, Minium, equal parts, with a
ſufficient quantity of the Mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cilage of Gum Tragacanth, that thence may be
form'd hard and ſtiff Trochisks.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe are us'd for making Eſcars, and to conſume proud
Fleſh and Excreſcencies about the Anus from illicit and prepoſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous
Coition; they are alſo apply'd to Venereal Cancers, Scrophulous Tumours, they
do not ſpread, and are quick in o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perating.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Trochisks of Arſenick.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>White Arſenick four ounces, Corroſive 
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:42878:41"/>Sublimatte half an ounce; powder both, and form them into
Trochisks with the Muci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage of Gum Tragacanth.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Trochisks are us'd as the former and being apply'd whole
or in Powder to Corns conſume and eat them away. The Arſenick contains a
very corroſive Salt, which being envelop'd in a great quantity of Sulphur
would diſengage it ſelf, but ſlowly without the addition of the
corro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive Sublimate. Tho' this Compound is an extraordinary Cauſtick, yet
it doth not cauſe great pain becauſe the Sulphur of the Arſenick and
Mucilage of the Gum do in a great meaſure curb the Salts, and check their
motion, involving their points in the branchy parts of the one, and ſli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my
roapy particles of the other.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Trochisks to be us'd in a Diabetes.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Myrtle Berries, ſeeds of Wood Sorrel, of each three
ounces; Gum Arabick, poun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded Wheat-flower, of each an ounce; reduce them into
powder, and make them into Tro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chisks with a ſufficient quantity of Mucilage
of Fleawort ſeeds.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe are ſaid to ſtrengthen the Sphin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cter 
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:42878:42"/>of the Bladder, and thicken the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum of the Blood, which
makes them not only proper in a Diabetes, but alſo fit to be given in
appropriate aſtringent De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coction in Hemorrhagies occaſion'd by over-thin
and ſharp Blood; on the other hand, Aloes being a provoker of the Men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrua
in thinning and inciding the Blood, and opening the Womb Veſſels, is not to
be given in the caſes before mention'd.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Trochisks of Enula Campane.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Dry'd roots of Enula Campane two ounces, flourr of
pounded Wheat, Gum Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gacanth, Gum Arabick, root of</hi> Florence <hi>Orrice,
Magiſtery of Sulphur, of each two drachms, flowers of Corn-poppy a drachm and
a half, flowers of Benzoin one ſcruple, Balſam of Sulphur anniſated ten
drops, with a ſufficient quantity of Mucilage of Gum Tragacanth drawn in Corn
Poppy-water; form Trochisks to be dry'd in the ſhade.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe are us'd in inveterate Coughs and Aſthma's; they
incide and attenuate tough roapy Phlegm, and facilitate its Expectoration; they
are taken from a ſcruple to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="71" facs="tcp:42878:42"/>
               <head>Trochisks of Orrice.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of</hi> Florence <hi>Orrice, white Pep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per, and
Gum Armoniack, of each half an ounce.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe attenuate and diſſolve viſcid Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours, and
facilitate their Expectoration; they are alſo proper to open Obſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons
of the Spleen and Womb, and to cure pale Complexions: They may be taken from
half a drachm to four ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Mynſichi</hi>'s Hydragogue Pills reform'd.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Mineral Turbith half an ounce, Tro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chisks of Alhandal,
roots of black Hellebore, of each three drachms; choice Rhubarb and Elaterium,
of each two drachms; Saffron of Metals prepar'd with Salt of Wormwood one
drachm, Spirit of Vitriol dulcify'd half a drachm; mix and make them into a
Maſs with Syrup of Buckthorn.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Pill purges and vomits with ſome violence; it is given in
Dropſies, Mania's, the Pox, Scurvy, and King's Evil, and other like
obſtinate Diſtempers, from <pb n="72" facs="tcp:42878:43"/>half a ſcruple to half a
drachm. The Crocus Metallorum calcin'd, with an e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qual weight of Salt of
Wormwood, and often waſh'd with warm Water, is leſs vomitive than the
common, becauſe the fix'd alkaline Salt has deſtroy'd ſome of its
irritating points. This preparation of Antimony often purges and cauſes
ſweat; it is given to eight grains.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Imperial Pills of the Phyſicians of
<hi>Lyons.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Extract of Aloes four ounces, Rhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barb one ounce,
Maſtick half an ounce, and with the Juice of Roſes form a Maſs of
Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills may be taken juſt before Meals, that the Salt of
the Aloes being dull'd by the particles of the Food may gripe the leſs.
Theſe Ingredients mix'd with the Extract of Juniper-berries will make much
ſuch a Pill as Dr. <hi>Anderſon</hi>'s.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Bontius</hi>'s Hydropical Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Aloes Succotrine two ounces and a half, Gambogia well
powder'd diſſolv'd in Malmſey and dry'd, one ounce and a half, 
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:42878:43"/>Diagrydium prepar'd the ſame way one ounce, choice Gum
Ammoniack one ounce and half, Tartarum Vitriolatum half an ounce; make them
into a Maſs with Solu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Syrup of Roſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The <hi>Tartarum Vitriolatum</hi> doth not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſerve as an
opener in this Compoſition, but alſo fixeth the ſalin emetick Sulphur of
the <hi>Gum. Gut.</hi> and determines it to purge by Stool, which it doth with
ſome vehemency. It is given from half a ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple to two, to purge off
ſerous Humours, particularly in Dropſies, for the cure of which it was
chiefly ſtudied.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Mercurial Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Choice Rhubarb, Trochisks of Alhan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dal, Diagrydium,
ſweet Sublimate, of each one ounce,</hi> Venice <hi>Turpentine waſh'd in
its own diſtill'd Oyl a ſufficient quantity to make them into a Maſs for
Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Tho' theſe Pills are properly deſign'd againſt Venereal
Diſtempers, yet they may be ſucceſsfully given in the King's E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vil, and
in obſtinate Rheumatiſms. Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> is of opinion, that they
would prove more effectual in Venereal Diſtem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers, <pb n="74" facs="tcp:42878:44"/>if
inſtead of the ſweet Sublimate an equal quantity of crude Mercury be put,
kill'd, as they call it, in <hi>Venice</hi> Turpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tine; for this reaſon,
that the Pores of the crude Mercury not being ſatiate as thoſe of the
ſweet Sublimate are, they would load themſelves with a greater quantity of
the Venereal Venom, and carry it off either by Stool or Tranſpiration. They
that ſhall like this reaſon may uſe the fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing Pills.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Pills of <hi>Barbaroſſe</hi> corected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Mercury well kill'd in a ſufficient quantity of
Venice Turpentine ſix drachms, Agarick trochiſc'd half an ounce, choice
Rhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barb two drachms; mix and make them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a Maſs of Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>In this the Spices are left out as being uſeleſs in the
other common Preſcription, and Turpentine is us'd inſtead of the Juice of
Roſes, it being ſcarce poſſible to kill the Mercury in this latter as
<hi>Barbaroſſe</hi> di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rects. Theſe Pills are given from a ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple to
a drachm, and may be taken at Night going to Bed, or in the Morning
faſting.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="75" facs="tcp:42878:44"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Quercetan</hi>'s Tartarous Pill reform'd.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Succotrine Aloes four ounces, Cream of Tartar and
yellow Myrobalans of each two ounces, pickt Senna one ounce, roots of black
Hellebore, Turbith, of each half an ounce; Salt of Wormwood and Aſh of each
two drachms; mix and make them into a Maſs with the Syrup of Apples of King
Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bor. The Doſe from half a ſcruple to half a drachm.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills purge Tartarous heavy Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours and tough Phlegm;
they are pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcrib'd in Mania's, Hypochondriack Affe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions, and alſo in
the ſuppreſſion of the Menſes.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The greater Pills of Bdellium.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Beſt Bdellium one ounce and a half, Annis Seed three
drachms, Myrobalans yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, Indian, Emblick, and Bellerick,
Porce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lain-ſhells burnt, Amber, of each two drachms and a half, with the
Juice of Leeks make a Maſs.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is given as an aſtringent to ſtop
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he overflowing of the Menſes,
Hemor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rhodies, <pb n="76" facs="tcp:42878:45"/>
                  <hi>&amp;c.</hi> There is a Pill call'd the
leſſer Pill of Bdellium; it conſiſts of 15 drachms of Bdellium, and of
5 drachms of the Myrobalans mix'd and made into Pills with Juice of Leeks.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Pills of Gambogia.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Aloes Succotrine two ounces and a half, Gummi Gutta,
Gum Ammoniack of each an ounce and a half, Roſine of Scam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony one ounce,
Tartarum Vitriolatum half an ounce; make them into a Maſs of Pills with a
ſufficient quantity of Syrup of Buck-thorn.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Gambogia</hi> is of it ſelf both Emetick and Purgative,
but being mix'd with the Tar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tarum Vitriolatum purges only by Stool<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> It is
given from half a ſcruple to half a drachm, in which Doſe it powerfully
car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries off watry humours without any con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderable gripes.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Spaw Pill.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cryſtal of Tartar three ounces, Dia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grydium half an
ounce, Salt of Steel two drachms, with Mucilage of Gum Traga<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>canth drawn in the
Spaw-water: make Maſs for Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="77" facs="tcp:42878:45"/>This is call'd Spaw Pill, not only
be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe the Mucilage is extracted in Spaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>water, but chiefly becauſe they
that drink the Waters do often make uſe of it. <hi>Henricus ab Heer</hi> in
his <hi>Spadacrene</hi> commends this Pill, and the Waters a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt many
Diſtempers, eſpecially He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>micrania's, Vertigoes, Obſtructions, and even
Scyrrhus's (if not inveterate) of the Liver and Spleen, and the Diſeaſes
ſpring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thence, as Jaundice, Melancholy, Hy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pochondrianiſm, Dropſies,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> as alſo a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Gravel, Ulcers of the Kidneys, Caruncles
in the Urethra and reſembling Affections, Leproſie, Cancers and Scyr<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rhus's
of the Womb, Fluxes, Sterility, Worms, &amp;c. They may be given from a
ſcruple to a drachm, and may be taken with good ſucceſs by ſuch as
drink <hi>Tun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bridge</hi> Waters.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Pill. Rudii</hi> corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Aloes ſuccotrine one ounce, Trochisks of Alhandal
ſix drachms, Agaricks, Scam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony, roots of black Hellebore, Turbith, of each
half an ounce; ſoluble Tartar three drachms, with a ſufficient quantity of
Sy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rup of Buckthorn, make them into Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="78" facs="tcp:42878:46"/>Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> ſays, That when we
eva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porate our Tincture for the Extract we loſe a great deal of the purging
Particles of the Druggs in the exhaling Steams, and prefers the ſoluble
Tartar for reaſons mention'd before. There may be ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what in this laſt
Remark, but there is but very little in the other, for ſince the Pill made
according to our <hi>Diſpenſatory</hi> works as well as any can do, and as
ſtrong as upon moſt occaſions is requir'd, what need we be concern'd at
the loſs of ſome groſs foetid Sulphurs, that in making the Pill
ſtronger, would render it more rough and churliſh in the operation. I have
ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded this, to ſhew upon what grounds ſome will correct and reform, as
they call it, but muſt do Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> Juſtice, he is generally
civil to the <hi>London</hi> and to <hi>Bates</hi>'s <hi>Diſpenſatory,</hi>
from both which he has ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken ſeveral Receipts, and gives them for the moſt
part unalter'd, always quoting the Books, which he has forgot to do to others;
eſpecially to <hi>Charas,</hi> from whom he has borrow'd conſiderably, but
ſeldom mentions him.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>℞. <hi>Juice of Liquorice, Frankincenſe, of each half an
ounce, Myrrh, beſt Saffron, O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pium, <pb n="79" facs="tcp:42878:46"/>of each four
ſcruples; make them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a Maſs of Pills with Syrup of Corn
Pop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pies.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills thicken and allay thin ſharp Humours, ſtay
Defluxions, and cauſe Reſt; they are given to a ſcruple in dry husking
Coughs; a ſcruple con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains two grains of Opium.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Turpentine Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. Venice <hi>Turpentine boil'd in Water of Radiſhes or of
Pellitory of the Wall, four oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; Liquorice finely powder'd one ounce; mix
them for Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>℞. <hi>Good clear Turpentine four ounces, roots of
Marſh-mallows dry'd and powder'd, Crabs-eyes prepar'd, of each an ounce;
pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rify'd Nitre and Hogs-lice prepar'd, of each an ounce; Salt of Amber two
drachms; make them into-a Maſs for Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>In this laſt Preparation the Salt of Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentine is
preſerv'd, part of which, in the former, is evaporated in the boiling, and
part diſſolv'd in the Water. The Powders alſo do better ſecond the
Inten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Pills than Liquorice can do, <pb n="80" facs="tcp:42878:47"/>but the
Maſs will hardly keep of due Conſiſtence, eſpecially in Summer. Both
Pills are Diuretick, and are of good uſe to carry off Gravel, to cleanſe
the Kid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys and Bladder; they may be given in the beginning of a Gonorrhea
from one ſcruple to four. They looſen and carry off the Viſcous and
Tartarous Concreti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons that ſtop the urinary paſſages, and for that
reaſon are helpful in ſuppreſſions of Urine.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Diuretick Pills of <hi>Cloſſaeus.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Venice Turpentine and white Vitriol reduc'd into very
fine powder of each equal parts, mix into a Maſs.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Turpentine in this Compoſition checks and deſtroys the
emetick quality of the Vitriol, for being wholly Viſcous and Sulphureous, it
does ſo intangle and em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>baraſs the volatile acid Salt of the Vitriol by its
branchy parts, that it cannot ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciently irritate or excite that kind of
Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vulſion wherein vomiting conſiſts; but being carry'd with the
Turpentine into the Maſs of Blood, it incides and attenu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ates its groſs
roapy Seroſities, and ſo proves a great Piſs-driver. Theſe Pills 
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:42878:47"/>diſcharge the Reins and Ureters of gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velly and
tenacious Concretions, and make the urinary paſſages ſlippery and
eaſie.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Aſtringent Pills to ſtop a Running or Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norrhea.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Mineral Diaphoretick, ſeal'd Earth, Amber, Dragon's
Blood, prepar'd Coral, binding Extract of Steel, of each half an ounce; red
Roſes, rinds of Granates, Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtick, Seeds of Meadow Rue, of each three
drachms; Salt of Saturn four ſcruples, Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um one ſcruple, with a
ſufficient quantity of Turpentine half boil'd, make them into a
Maſs.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills abſorb and ſuck into their Pores the viſcous
ſaline Humour that gletes from the Veſſels, and ſtrengthens their
relax'd Fibres. But whereas it of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten proves very difficult to ſtop
inveterate runnings, eſpecially where the parts af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fected have been much
impair'd by irre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular living, hard riding, or other vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent exerciſe we
muſt ſecond the Pills with proper Injections, with aſtringent
fomen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations on the Perineum, and with dry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Diet-drinks, Tincture of
Roſes, in <pb n="82" facs="tcp:42878:48"/>dulcify'd Spirit of Vitriol, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
Theſe Pills are to be taken twice a day for a conſiderable time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Le Mort</hi>'s ſweating Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Gum Guajacum one ounce, Extract of Contrayerva ſix
drachms, Myrrh five drachms and one ſcruple, Saffron half an ounce, Camphire
two drachms and two ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, Laudanum Opiatum two ſcruples; mix them
according to art into a Maſs with a ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient quantity of Syrup of
Clove-gilliflowers.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Pill is commended againſt Poiſon and Infection; it
eaſes pain, cauſes reſt, and provokes Sweat, quiets the inordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate
motion of the Blood and Spirits; it is given in malignant Fevers from a
ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Hyſterick Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Extract of Aloes prepar'd with the Juice of Mugwort
ten drachms, Faeculas or Dregs of Bryony, choice Myrrh, Vitriol of</hi> Mars,
<hi>Salt of Mugwort, of each two drachms, Caſtoreum, Camphire, leaves of Rue,
of each two ſcruples; make them into Pills with the Juice of
Mugwort.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="83" facs="tcp:42878:48"/>Theſe Pills provoke the Menſes,
ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs Vapours, and carry off the Impuri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of the Matrix; they are
taken for ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral days together, the Doſe not above half a drachm if they
be continued for a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Pills conſiſting of two Ingredients.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Trochisks of Alhandal, Scammony, of each equal parts;
Syrup of Buckthorn Ber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries a ſufficient quantity to make them into
Pills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills purge Phlegm and groſs roapy Seroſities; they
are given in the Gout and Dropſies from eight grains to a ſcruple.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Anti-epileptick Pills corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Dry'd roots of Male Peony ſix drachms, fecules or
dregs of Briony three drachms, mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Cinnabar eight ſcruples, Caſtoreum,
Amber, Solar precipitate, of each two drachms, leaves of black Hellebore, Oyl
of Antimony, of each four ſcruples, Oyl of An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gelica, Spirit of Vitriol, of
each twenty drops; make them into a Paſte with the Juice of Leeks.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="84" facs="tcp:42878:49"/>This Pill is given from half a ſcruple to
half a drachm. The Solar Precipitate is made thus, one part of Gold cut ſmall
and five parts of Mercury are put into a Matraſs into a Lamp-fire until they
diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve and become a red Calx.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Anti-hypochondriacal Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Succotrine Aloes half a pound, roots of black
Hellebore one ounce, Hermodactyles, Gum Ammoniack depurated, Salt Armoni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ack
ſublim'd with Mars, Vitriol of Mars, of each three drachms; make them into a
Maſs with a ſufficient quantity of Syrup of Buckthorn.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Pill purges the groſs tartarous Humours that cauſe
Obſtructions in the Bowels, and ſend groſs naſty Effluvia in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the
Blood that diſorder its Circulati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and diſcompoſe the Brain; they may
be given to two ſcruples or a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Chalybeat Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Beſt ſuccotrine Aloes one ounce, ope<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Saffron
of Mars five drachms, Scam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony, Gum Ammoniack, of each half an 
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:42878:49"/>ounce, Saffron, Tartarum Vitriolatum, of each a drachm and
a half; make them into a Paſte with Oximel of Squills.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills carry off tartarous and mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cilaginous Humours,
open Obſtructions of the Liver, Spleen, and Matrix, and cure the Diſeaſes
that proceed from thence.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Angelick Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Extract of Aloes half a Pound, Rhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barb half an ounce,
Agarick trochisk'd two drachms, Cinnamon one drachm; make them into a Maſs
with Syrup of Roſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills require no regiment at all, they purge gently, may
be taken at meals, or a little before eating, that the Aloes may gripe the
leſs. They are given to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Pills of Savine.</head>
               <p>℞. Venice <hi>Borax, Maſs of Pilulae Foeti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dae, of each one
ounce and a half; leaves of Savine and Salt of the ſame ſix drachms,
Juniper Berries and Eſſence of Savine, of each three drachms, Saffron one
ſcruple; make them into a Maſs with Syrup of Mugwort.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="86" facs="tcp:42878:50"/>Theſe Pills provoke the Menſes,
diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve the groſs viſcid Humours that ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruct the Womb
Veſſels, and clog the Blood, ſuppreſs Hyſterick Vapours; they may be
given to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Gout Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Reſin of Jalap half an ounce, Dia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grydium, Rhubarb,
of each four ſcruples; Tartarum Vitriolatum and Diaphoretick Mars of each one
ſcruple; make them into a Maſs with a ſufficient quantity of Syrup of
Apples.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Pill is us'd in the running and fix'd Gout, in
Rheumatiſms, old Aches and Pains; it may be taken from a ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple to a
drachm. See the Preparation of <hi>Mars Diaphoreticus</hi> in the Third Edition
of <hi>Lemery</hi> in <hi>Engliſh.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Sweating Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cryſtals of Tartar, Cinnabar of Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony, of each
ſix drachms, Myrrh and A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loes, of each three drachms; make them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a
Paſte with a ſufficient quantity of Oyl of Guajacum.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="87" facs="tcp:42878:50"/>Theſe correct the Acids that fix the
Blood, and hinder its Rarefaction, quick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en the Circulation, and diſpoſe
the Serum to paſs by the cuticular Glands; they are given from half a
ſcruple to half a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Schroder</hi>'s Tartar Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Beſt ſhining Aloes waſh'd and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pregnated with
the Juice of Strawberries two ounces, Gum Ammoniack purg'd from all filth
ſeven drachms, purging Magiſtery of Tartar diſſolv'd ſeveral times in
Bugloſs<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>water and again coagulated half an ounce, Extract of Gentian three
Drachms, Salt of Steel and Tincture of Saffron, of each two drachms, with
Tincture of Tartar make them into a Maſs.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills purge off the tartarous ear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Humours that
create Obſtructions in the Bowels, and are ſucceſsfully us'd in
Cachexia's, ſuppreſſion of Menſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The purging
Magiſtery of Tartar con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſts of the fix'd Salt of Tartar well ſati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate
with diſtill'd Vinegar, and then mix'd with Spirit of Wine, which being twice
or thrice diſtill'd from it leaves this pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging Magiſtery.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="88" facs="tcp:42878:51"/>
               <head>Anodine Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Laudanum half an ounce,</hi> Indian <hi>Pepper infus'd
a whole Night in Vinegar and dry'd, two drachms; Saffron four ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples,
Myrrh two ſcruples, Musk ſix grains; mix and make them into a Maſs with
Sack.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Pills are proper to ſtay Defluxi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons upon any part,
procure Sleep, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but were chiefly deſign'd againſt Cholicks
and Belly-fluxes; they may be taken to ſix Grains.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Sweet ſcented Pills.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Beſt</hi> Syrian <hi>Storax one ounce, Ben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zoin half
an ounce, root of</hi> Florence <hi>Orrice, Trochisks of Gallia Moſchata,
yellow Saun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, of each four ſcruples; Chymical Oyl of Roſemary two
ſcruples; mix and make them into a Maſs with the Mucilage of Gum Tragacanth
prepar'd in Cinnamon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>water.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The uſe of this Pill is againſt a ſtinking loathſom
Breath, which it corrects, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing put into a hollow Tooth or otherwiſe held
in the Mouth.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="89" facs="tcp:42878:51"/>
               <head>Tablets of Manna.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Calabrian Manna one ounce and a half, refin'd Sugar
one pound; make them into Tablets.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe are pleaſant to the taſte, keep the Body ſoluble;
they are moſt proper for Children, and ſuch as are a verſe to leſs
grateful Phyſick.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Treacle Tablets reform'd.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Old Treacle one ounce, Balſam of Sulphur, ſeeds of
Sorrel, Elk's hoof, roots of Enula Campana and Angelica, wood of A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loes, bone
of a Deer's heart, white Amber; Camphire and Myrrh, of each one drachm; Oyl of
Cinnamon eight drops, refin'd Sugar one pound; mix them in a Marble Mortar, and
with a ſufficient quantity of Mucilage of Gum Tragacanth drawn in Carduus
Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter make a ſolid maſs, of which form the Tablets.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Tablets ſtrengthen the Noble Parts, reſiſt the
Infection of the Air; they may be taken in time of Sickneſs from one drachm
to three.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="90" facs="tcp:42878:52"/>
               <head>Emetick Tablets or Lozenges.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Emetick Tartar, Liquorice-ras'd Wheat-flower, of each
two ounces; refin'd Sugar half a pound, with Mucilage of Gum Tragacanth make
Tablets of half a drachm each.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe Lozenges both vomit, and purge by Stool, they are
pleaſant to the taſt; if they ſhould chance to work with too much
violence, fat Broth or Oyl of ſweet Almonds will check it; two Tablets will
prove a full Doſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Compound Tablets of Marſh mallows.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Pulp of Marſh-mallow-roots two oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, ſeeds of
white Poppies, powder of</hi> Flo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence <hi>Orrice, Liquorice, and of the
powder call'd Diatragacanthum frigidum, of each three drachms; refin'd Sugar
boil'd in Roſe water one pound, make Tablets according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe are us'd in inveterate Coughs and Aſthma's, to cut and
looſen the im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacted Phlegm, and facilitate its Expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctoration; they are held
in the Mouth to diſſolve ſlowly.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="91" facs="tcp:42878:52"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s purging Tablets.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Seeds of Zedoary, Corallina, of each three drachms;
root of Jalap two drachms, Diagrydium one drachm, ſweet Sublimate one
ſcruple, beſt refin'd Sugar boiled in the Infuſion of Tanſey to the
conſiſtence of Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blets one pound, form the Tablets.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They purge mildly, kill and expell Worms, hinder the corruption
of Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours: They may be taken from a drachm to an ounce. The three laſt days
of the Moon are made choice of in giving this and other Medicines againſt
Worms, tho' no reaſon appears, why they ſhould pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail then more than at
any other time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Mercurial Tablets.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Mercurial Panacaea two ounces, ſharp biting
Cinnamon,</hi> Florence <hi>Orrice, Ginger, of each one drachm; fine Sugar four
ounces, with the Mucilage of Gum Tragacanth form a ſolid Maſs, of which
make your Tablets of a drachm weight each.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They are to be chew'd by thoſe in whom it is difficult to
raiſe a Salivation, <pb n="92" facs="tcp:42878:53"/>the Ginger and Mace heat the Mouth,
and open the ſalival excretory Ducts, and ſerve as a Vehicle to the
Panacaea. The Salivation they raiſe when us'd alone is but ſlight, and may
be ſtop'd almoſt at pleaſure by the uſe of an aſtringent Gargle.</p>
               <p>The Panacaea is ſweet Sublimate thus prepar'd; Take what
quantity you pleaſe of ſweet Sublimate, beat it into fine Powder, put it
into a Matraſs upon a Sand-bath, lute on a Head; after it has ſtood in that
heat an hour, augment the Fire by degrees until all is ſublim'd; then take it
off, let the Veſſel cool, then break it; powder your Sublimate again; and
do all as before; repeat this ſeven times, then having reduc'd your Sublimate
into fine Powder pour on it Spirit of Wine alkoliz'd, four Fingers high, leave
it to ſteep fifteen days, ſtirring it pretty often with an Ivory Slice; at
laſt place it in Baln. M. draw the Spirit off, and dry your Panacaea in a
Sand-fire. This is a moſt noble Medicine in wary Hands a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt all
foulneſs of Blood, whether Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nereal or Scorbutical, againſt Itch,
Tet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tars, Scabs, Scald-heads. See a fuller ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count in the third
<hi>Engliſh</hi> Edition of Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi>'s Chymiſtry.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="93" facs="tcp:42878:53"/>
               <head>Rotules of white Poppies.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Syrup of white Poppies newly made what quantity you
pleaſe, and having boil'd it to the conſiſtence of a ſolid Electuary
form the Tablet.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They have the ſame vertue with the Syrup that is by their
ſlimy Mucilage; they allay the ſharpneſs of thin corroſive Phlegm,
hinder the too great expanſion of the Spirits and the inordinate agitati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
of Humours.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s hot Philonium.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Annis, Fennil and Carraway ſeeds, of each five
drachms, Cinnamon half an ounce, Ginger and Extract of Opium of each three
drachms, Nutmegs two drachms, clarify'd Honey ten ounces; make them into an
Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This tho' leſs compound than others of this name, yields to
none in goodneſs; it eaſes Pain, reſiſts the maliguity of Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours, and
cauſes Reſt; it is given from a ſcruple to a drachm.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="94" facs="tcp:42878:54"/>Some make an Extract of new made Treacle in
Spirit of Wine, and call the Preparation <hi>Laudanum tutiſſimum;</hi> but
old Treacle having in its longer fermen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation ſubtilized and exalted its
active parts more than the new, ſeems the fitter to rarifie and diſſolve
the Coagulations caus'd in the Blood, and Humours by the bite or ſting of
Venomous Beaſts coagu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating Poiſons, infected Air, or a too great quantity
of Acids accumulated in the Body.</p>
               <p>He commends the Apothecaries of <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ris</hi> for leaving out
Silk in their <hi>Confectio Alkermes,</hi> aſſerting, that neither wrought,
nor raw Silk can communicate the leaſt vertue to that or any other
Compoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. But Dr. <hi>Liſter</hi> could inform him otherwiſe, and
tell him as he did Dr. <hi>Turnfort,</hi> That Silk yields a noble Spirit, the
fineſt, he ſays, that ever was taſted, with an incredible quantity of
Volatil Salt, which being refin'd and often co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hobated with rich Aromatick
Chymical Oyls, he thinks makes that call'd King <hi>Charles</hi>'s Salt.
However Silk being a dry Gelly of the Inſect kind, which for the moſt part
conſiſt of extream active parts, is not ſo deſpicable for phyſical
uſes as Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> and <hi>Zwelfer</hi> would inſinuate.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="95" facs="tcp:42878:54"/>Among the Remarks made upon <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectuarium
de Ovo Quercetani,</hi> we have this method of preparing the Diaphore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick
Sulphur of Gold, call'd by Chymiſts <hi>Potable Gold, or the true Tincture of
Sol.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Diſſolve what quantity of Gold you pleaſe in <hi>Aqua
Regalis,</hi> evaporate the Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolution over a gentle Fire, and there will
remain a Calx of Gold, which moiſten into a Liquid Paſt with the
Eſſence of Cinnamon; and having put the mixture in a Matraſs, pour upon
it Spirit of Wine tartariz'd until it appears an Inch over; then having
ſtop'd the Veſſel very cloſe, put it to digeſt until the Liquor
ſeems ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly tinctur'd, which done, pour it off and add new until the Spirit
ceaſes to draw a Tincture, then mix the Diſſolutions toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther and keep
them for uſe.</p>
               <p>This Preparation is a Diſſolution of ſome parts of the
Subſtance of the Gold in the Sulphurs of the Cinnamon and of the Spirit of
Wine; for if it were quite diveſted of its Sulphur, as ſome Chymiſts
fooliſhly pretend the Calx could be never reduc'd into Gold again, which it
eaſily can being well dry'd, and adding a ſmall quantity of Borax to
it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="96" facs="tcp:42878:55"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s cold Philonium.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Red Roſes one ounce, Caſſia Lignea ſix
drachms, Bole-armene, roots of Snake-weed, of each half an ounce; Extract of
O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pium two drachms and a half, clarify'd Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney nine ounces; mix and make them
into an Opiate according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is proper in all loſſes of Blood in Diarrhaea's,
Lienteries, and Bloody-fluxes, it allays Pain and cauſes reſt; it is given
from half a ſcruple to a drachm.</p>
               <p>Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> juſtly ſuſpects the truth of what is
ſaid of King <hi>Mithridates</hi>'s having been poiſon-proof, and to have
ow'd this to the Compoſition that bears his Name, whereof he himſelf is
ſaid to have been the Inventor. It might indeed have been of good uſe
againſt Coagulating Poiſons, ſuch as Hemlock, Wolf's-bane, the biting of
Vipers or Serpents, ſtings of Scorpions and the Tarantula; but is of little
efficacy againſt Corroſive Sublimate and Arſenick.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Confection of Jacinth corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Jacinth Stones prepar'd, red Coral <pb n="97" facs="tcp:42878:55"/>ſeal'd Earth, of each one ounce; ſhaving of Hart's-Horn ſix
drachms, of the Bone of a Deer's Heart, roots of Tormentil and Dit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tany, leaves
of Cretan-dittany, Saffron, Myrrh, red Roſes, Seeds of Sorrel, Purſlain, of
each three drachms; Crab's Eyes pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd, outward rind of Citrons and bitter
Oranges dry'd, of each four ſcruples; Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ental Musk and Ambergreaſe of
each ten grains, Syrup of Kermes one ounce, Syrup of Clove-gilliflowers three
pound; mix them according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>In this Reformation the Gold and Sil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver are left out as
uncapable of alteration in our Bodies. They dry Kermes grains as effete and
worthleſs, and the Syrup of Clove-gilliflowers made uſe of, becauſe the
Syrup of Coral commonly uſed, deſtroys in great part the Alkaline
Ingredients of the Confection, whoſe chief Cordial ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue conſiſts in
the Diſpoſition of their Pores, and texture of their parts that fit them to
ſheath the points and edges of the hoſtile peccant Acids, which the Syrup
of Clove-gilliflowers does in no wiſe do; but being a ſtrengthener of the
Heart and Brain, and other noble parts, does conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derably ſecond the good
effects of the Compoſition. If it ſhould be objected, <pb n="98" facs="tcp:42878:56"/>That the Juice of Limons, the foundation of the Syrup of that name, is
uſeful in opening the Stones and Earth, we will anſwer, That this being
much weakened by addition of the Sugar, it rather clogs than opens; beſides,
they being Natural Alcalies, as is apparent by their great ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferveſcence
with this Syrup, there is no ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity of opening them otherwiſe than in
multiplying their abſorbing Superficies by fine grinding, certainly the
beſt Prepara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of ſuch Concretes for Medicinal uſe, as was ſaid
before in our Diſcourſe upon Coral. He ſubſtitutes Syrup of Kermes to
the Grains, becauſe theſe grow worth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs and effete by the loſs of
their inward ſucculent ſubſtance which is ſpent, and turns into little
Worms as it dries. The ſhavings of Harts-horn are deſervedly preferr'd to
the burnt, becauſe the ſha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vings retain all the valuable parts that the
Horn loſes in the uſtion; for they not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly contain the Mucilaginous and
Cordial parts which the Horn affords to Gellies, but alſo the Volatile
Spirit, Salt, and Oyl which it yields by Diſtillation; all which are quite
loſt in Calcination. Crab's-eyes, he ſays, are every whit as good as Pearl,
tho' conſiderably cheaper. Gold, he ſays, tho' never ſo thin beat into
leaves, is unca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pable <pb n="99" facs="tcp:42878:56"/>of alteration in our Bodies; and
truly conſidering the compact texture of that Metal, and how few known
diſſol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vents can diſunite its parts, I ſhould be apt to think it more
ornamental than uſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful in Phyſick, did I not conſider how many
Subſtances, and of how differing natures are diſſolv'd by the ferment of
our Stomach: Beſides, what Mr. <hi>Boyle</hi> ſays of a Menſtruum drawn
from Bread that en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tirely diſſolves Gold, and what Monſieur
<hi>Couder,</hi> a skilful Apothecary of <hi>Milhan</hi> in <hi>Rouvergne</hi>
affirms of Capons fed for a conſiderable time with a Paſte made of Vipers,
leaf Gold and Wheat; <hi>viz.</hi> that having carefully preſerv'd their Dung
all the time, and calcin'd it at length, adding Mercury to amalgamate with the
Gold exhal'd the Quickſilver, and fus'd what was left with the addition of a
ſmall quantity of Borax; he recover'd not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove two parts in ſix, or a
third of what the Fowl had eat, and this too very much paler than ordinary
Gold.</p>
               <p>This Confection is ſaid to repair and recreate the Vital and
Animal Spirits, and is therefore recommended in palpitations of the Heart, and
in ſwooning fits, to reſiſt Putrefaction, and to re-eſtabliſh
languiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and decay'd Strength. It is given <pb n="100" facs="tcp:42878:57"/>from a
ſcruple to a drachm in Wine Broth or Cordial Liquors, and is mix'd with
Epithemes for the Heart. A part of the Compoſition is to be kept without
ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition of Musk or Ambergreaſe, becauſe thoſe Perfumes do not agree
with Hyſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick, and ſeveral other Patients.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The <hi>Tholouſe</hi> Hydrotick Opiate.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Conſerve of Eglantine and flowers of Enula Campana
or</hi> French <hi>Orrice, of each two ounces; powder of Rhubarb, pickt Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na,
of each two drachms; Reſin of Jalap and Scammony of each one drachm, Salt of
Wormwood and Tamarisk of each two ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, Extract of Hedge Hyſſop
prepar'd with Spirit of Wine half a drachm, Syrup of Buckthorn as much as is
requiſite to make them into an Opiate.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Preparation as well as many o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther is improperly call'd
Opiate, not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining the leaſt quantity of Opium. It purges ſerous
Humours both by Stool and Urine, is preſcrib'd in Diſtempers of the Spleen
and Meſentery to open Obſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons in Retention or Irregularities of
Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men's courſes. It may be taken every other day to the quantity of two
drachms. <pb n="101" facs="tcp:42878:57"/>Our Author prefers the leaves of Gratjo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>la dry'd
and reduc'd to powder to its Extract, becauſe the Spirit us'd in pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paring
the Extract carries with it in the Evaporation much of the purging parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles
of the Rhubarb, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Cordial Opiate of <hi>Lyons.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Juniper-berries four ounces, powder of Vipers, Mace,
roots of Angelica, long and round Birthwort, Suakeweed, Carline Thiſtle,
Contrayerva, Cretan Spignel, of each one ounce, with</hi> Narbonac <hi>Honey
boil'd in Water of Scordium, make an Opiate ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Opiate is us'd with ſucceſs in Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lignant Fevers,
Epidemick Diſeaſes, and is not only a Cure of Peſtilence, but alſo a
good preſervative againſt it: It reſiſts Putrefaction, and is therefore
ſucceſsfully taken againſt Worms, Crudities, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is taken
from a ſcruple to a drachm in a Bolus, or diſſolv'd in Wine or ſome
Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dial Liquor.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Opiate againſt Worms.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Wormſeed one ounce, choice Rhubarb, 
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:42878:58"/>ſweet Sublimate, of each half an ounce; Syrup of the
Juice of Purſlain boil'd to the conſiſtence of a ſoft Electuary half a
pint; mix them into an Opiate.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Diaſcordium corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Dry leaves of Scordium, roots of Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſterwort,
Cinnamon, of each one ounce; roots of Gentian, leaves of bleſs'd Thiſtle,
Cretan Dittany, Bole Armene, Gum Arabick, of each half an ounce; Nutmegs three
drachms, roots of Angelica, Opium, Saffron, of each two drachms; true Acacia
one drachm and a half, Honey of Roſemary boil'd to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtence of a
ſoft Electuary two pound; make them into an Opiate according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Electuary is a good Sudorifick, is us'd with good
ſucceſs in Malignant Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers, Fluxes, Cholick, and againſt Worms; it is
given to half a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Camphir'd Electuary.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Camphire, Ginger, prepar'd Pearl, of each half an
ounce, roots of white Dittan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, Tormentil, bone of a Stags heart, of each two
drachms; Treacle of</hi> Androma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chus <hi>four ounces, refin'd Sugar boil'd in 
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:42878:58"/>the Water of Wood Sorrel one pound; make it into an
Electuary according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Electuary provokes Sweat, is a good Hyſterick, and
powerfully reſiſts the malignity and corruption of Humours; it owes its
chief vertue to the Camphire and Treacle, both experienc'd Remedies in
Epidemick Diſtempers: It is given to two drachms.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Electuary of the Juice of Rue.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of long and round Birthwort, Dyers Madder,
Berries of Laurel and Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niper, Savine, ſeeds of wild Carrot, Agnus Caſtus
and Rue, of each one drachm, pithy part of Piony-ſeeds two ſcruples, Cretan
Dittany half a drachm, Saffron, Myrrh, Caſtoreum, of each one Scruple; mingle
and reduce the whole into powder, and with three ounces of refin'd Sugar
diſſolved in the Juice of Rue make them into an Electuary according to
art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This provokes the Menſes, ſuppreſſes Hyſterick
Vapours, haſtens Delivery and the coming away of the After-burthen. It is
given from one ſcruple to four.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="104" facs="tcp:42878:59"/>
               <head>The Royal Electuary.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Pine Kernels one ounce and a half, ſweet Almonds
half an ounce, red Roſes two drachms, yellow Saunders two ſcruples,
Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bergreaſe half a ſcruple, Musk three grains, white Sugar diſſolv'd
in Roſe-water one pound; make them into an Electuary.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is ſaid to ſtrengthen the Stomach and Breaſt, to
raiſe the Spirits and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voke Luſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Hoffman</hi>'s Orvietan.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Swallow-wort, Zedoary, Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lina, Angelica,
Butter-bur, Valerian, white Dittander, Enula Campana, Celandine, of each three
ounces; leaves of Cretan Dittany, Scordium, Rue, of each three hands full;
powder of Vipers two ounces, Oriental Saf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fron one ounce or ſix drachms,
Galbanum an ounce and a half, choice Myrrh, Sulphur and ſeal'd Earth, of each
one ounce, volatile Salt of Vipers ſix drachms, Cinnamon, Cloves, of each
half an ounce; Opium cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected or laudanum Opiatum three drachms, Oyl of Amber
and of Citrons of each one drachm and a half, Honey of Juniper ten 
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:42878:59"/>pound, mix them well and leave them to ferment for ſome
Months in a cloſe Veſſel.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is the beſt Preparation of the kind, and has been
prefer'd as ſuch to all others by the Apothecaries of <hi>Paris</hi> in 94;
it is us'd in Malignant Fevers, and all Epide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mick Diſeaſes, as Plague,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> where it proves a cure and preſervative, as alſo againſt
the ſtings and bitings of veno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous Creatures, Fluxes, Indigeſtion,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is given to a drachm and a half.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Chalybeat Electuary.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Opening Extract of Mars half a pound, Cinnamon,
Nutmegs, of each ſix drachms, beſt Rhubarb half an ounce, cla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rify'd Honey
and Sugar of each one pound; mix and make them into an Electuary ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to
art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Electuary opens Obſtructions of all ſorts, is given
with good ſucceſs in Hypochondriacal Diſtempers, and cache<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>xies,
Green-ſickneſs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It may be taken along with Mineral Waters
or other de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>obſtruent Liquors.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="106" facs="tcp:42878:60"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Zwelfer</hi>'s Hydrogogue Electuary.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Middle rind of Elder, roots of dwarf Elder, of each
three drachms; wild Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumber two ounces, ſeeds of dwarf Elder one ounce and
a half, Colefoot, leaves of black Hellebore and Hedge Hyſſop of each one
cunce; being all cut ſmall and pounded, let them boil in a ſufficient
quantity of common Water to a quart, then filter with expreſſion, and
having clarify'd the ſtrain'd Liquor, add refin'd Sugar and clarify'd Honey
of each ten ounces, powder of Jalap three ounces, Cinnamon ſix drachms,
Cloves, Nutmegs, Gambogia and Elaterium, of each half an ounce; make them into
an Electuary.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Electuary purges Seroſities pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erfully, and is therefore
of good uſe in an Aſcites, if taken in hand before the Liver, Spleen, and
other Bowels become cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupted, and if it be cloſely follow'd. It may be
given to half an ounce diſſolv'd in White-wine or ſome opening Liquor, or
may be made into a Bolus.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="107" facs="tcp:42878:60"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Sylvius Delboe</hi>'s Hydrotick Electuary.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Extract of Juniper, Pulp of Tama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinds, of each four
ounces, Jalap one ounce and a half, choice Scammony one ounce, Cinnamon,
ſweet Fennel ſeeds, of each two drachms, white Sugar diſſolv'd and
boil'd in common Water ten ounces; make them into an Electuary.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi>'s Hydragogue Electuary.</p>
               <p>℞. <hi>White Sugar ten ounces, boil them in a ſufficient
quantity of common Water to the conſiſtence of Honey, then add four ounces
of Extract of Juniper Berries, as much Caſſia Fiſtula; powder of Jalap
one ounce and a half, Scammony one ounce, ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luble Tartar half an ounce; make
them into an Electuary.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This and <hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Electuary are not only recommended
for all ſorts of Drop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies, but are alſo proper to cleanſe the Kidneys
and Bladder from a ſlimy and gravelly Mucus that often counterfeits the
Stone; they are alſo proper in Hypo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chondriack Affections, Cachexies,
ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion of the Menſes or Urine, in the <pb n="108" facs="tcp:42878:61"/>Gout,
Rheumatiſm, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> they are taken to ſix drachms.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Electuary of Garlick.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Eight cloves of Garlick, to which fried and maſh'd
with Honey add four ſcruples of Caſtor, Sperma Ceti, Juniper-berries, and
dry'd leaves of Pellitory of the Wall, of each two ſcruples, Mithridate five
drachms, Oxymel of Squills boil'd to the conſiſtence of an Opiate four
ounces; make them into an Electuary according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It is proper in Nephritick and Wind Cholicks, in running and
fixt Gouts, in Aſthma's, Dropſies, and moſt ſorts of Cachexies; for it
cuts and attenuates tough roapy Humours, that obſtruct both the Conglobate
and Conglomerate Glands, and ſo hinder the due Secretion of the uſeful, and
the diſcharge of Excre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentitious Humours. It is us'd in time of
Peſtilence. The Doſe from a ſcruple to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Terebinthinate Electuary.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Good clear Turpentine one pound, roots of Mallows, of
Graſs, reſt Harrow, <pb n="109" facs="tcp:42878:61"/>Butchers Broom, Liquorice, of each
one ounce; Gum Arabick, Tragacanth, prepar'd Crab's-eyes, Nitre purified, Salt
of Sulphur, Cheſlops prepar'd, of each three drachms; Volatile Salt of Amber
and ſweet Sublimate of each two drachms; make them up into an Electuary
according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Electuary attenuates and wears by degrees the Stone in the
Kidneys and Bladder, carries off the Gravel and all gravelly Slime or
Tartareous Concretions by Urine, and is therefore proper in Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phritick
Cholicks: It deterges and heals Ulcers in the Urinary Paſſages, and in the
Matrix, wherefore it is ſucceſsfully preſcrib'd in Gonorrhaea's and in
ſuppreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of Urine.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Wound Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Leaves and roots of great Cumfrey, leaves of Sage,
Mugwort, Bugle, of each four handfulls, Betony, Sanicle, Ox-eye, Water Betony,
leſſer Conſound, Plantain, Agrimony, Vervein, Wormwood, Fennil, St.
John's Wort, Birthwort, Sengreen,</hi> Paul<hi>'s Betony, leſſer Centory,
Yarrow, Tabacco, Mint, Hyſſop, of each one handful; let all be beaten mix'd
and macerated for three <pb n="110" facs="tcp:42878:62"/>days in ſix quarts of White Wine
over hot Embers, then diſtill them in B. M. and keep the Water for
uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water is much us'd in <hi>France</hi> for Contuſions,
Diſlocations and the Reſolu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Tumours, to cleanſe Wounds and
Ulcers, and to reſiſt Mortification; they call it <hi>Eau
d'arquebuſade.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Nephritick Water corrected.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Narbon Honey half a pound, Venice Turpentine two
ounces, Nephritick Wood, Reſt Harrow, of each an ounce and a half; Wood of
Aloes one ounce, Galengale, Cloves, Cinnamon, Mace, Cubebs, Maſtick, of each
half an ounce; beat and pound what is to be pounded, and let the whole be
macerated in two quarts of Brandy, then diſtill'd with a gentle
fire.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It diſcharges the Kidneys, Ureters, and Bladder of a gravelly
tenacious Mucus, and helps in Wind and Nepritick Cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licks; it may be given to
half an ounce in white Wine or ſome appropriate De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coction.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="111" facs="tcp:42878:62"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Cloſſaeus</hi>'s Coſmetick Water with Myrrh.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>New Goat's Milk two quarts,</hi> Spaniſh <hi>Wine
three pints, Juice of the greateſt Houſleek a pint and a half, Water of
Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter-Lilies and white Roſes of each one pint, whites of twelve Eggs;
diſtill them in B. M.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>℞. <hi>Of the above deſcrib'd Water a quart, beſt Myrrh
finely powder'd two ounces; let them ſtand in digeſtion for</hi> 24
<hi>hours, then diſtill again. You may diſſolve in half a pint of this
myrrh'd Water Sugar-candy two drachms, Borax one drachm, burnt Alum one
ſcruple.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water ſmooths, beautifies and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerves the
Complexions of Ladies, takes off Sun-burning, Freckles, or Spots; it is to be
us'd with a Linen Cloath or Spunge.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Prophylactick Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Green unripe Wallnuts cut ſmall two pound, freſh
Cirrons ſlic'd one pound, leaves of Garden-Rue four ounces, Balm, Scabious,
Marygold-flowers, roots of Butter-Dock, of each two ounces; Setwall, Angelica,
of each <pb n="112" facs="tcp:42878:63"/>an ounce; pour upon all l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ten together ſin quarts of diſtill'd Vinegar, let
them ſtand a whole Night, next Mornign diſtill with a gentle fire almost to
a dryneſs.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water or rather Vinegar is high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly commended againſt the
Plague, and in all Contagious and Epidemick Diſtem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers. It reſiſts
Poiſon and the Contagious Effluvia of an Infectious Air; cures the biting of
venomous Beaſts, kills Worms, and in attenuating groſs viſcid matter
quickens Digeſtion. It is mingled in Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and in liquid Epithems put up
into the Noſtrils, and apply'd to the Temples, Stomach and Wriſts. A Spunge
ſoak'd in it, put into a Box with little holes in the Lid, is carry'd in the
Pocket to be ſmell'd to in Sickneſs-time. Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi> who
attributes the good effects of this Compound to the Volatile Particles of its
Ingredients, would change the Vinegar, which fixes too much, for white Wine;
but ſince the Experience not only of <hi>Syl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vius, Diemerbroeck</hi> and
<hi>Deker,</hi> but of many other conſiderable Practitioners has found this
Preparation efficacious, I ſhould not alter it for the ſake of a ſpecious
no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, eſpecially Vinegar and ſuch like mild Acids proving extraordinary
Remedies in <pb n="113" facs="tcp:42878:63"/>Diſtempers wherein the Texture of the Blood
is deprav'd, and the Maſs inclines to a Diſſolution.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Water of Magnanimity.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Two handfulls of Ants, Spirit of Wine a quart;
digeſt them in a cover'd Veſſel until they putrefie into a Liquor, then
di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtill them in B. M. and aromatize the di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtill'd Liquor with a ſmall
quantity of Cinnamon.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water raiſes and quickens the Spirits in diſſolving
the clammy cold Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours that clog'd and depreſs'd them, increaſes and
ferments the Seed; its Doſe is from one drachm to two.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Apoplectick Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Tops of Marjoram, Tilet or Lime-tree, flowers of Lily
of the Valley, Roſemary, La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vender, Sage, Primroſe, of each a handful and a
half; let them macerate eight days in the Sun or in a Stove in a pint and a
half of Spirit of Wine, and an equal quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity of Orange-flower-water, then
diſtill them in a Sand Bath according to art, and put it up for
uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="112" facs="tcp:42878:64"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#OXF" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="113" facs="tcp:42878:64"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#OXF" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <p>
                  <pb n="114" facs="tcp:42878:65"/>This Water corrects the Acids that fix the
Blood and hinder its due Rarefacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and ſo quickens its Circulation. The
Ingredients being of the number of Ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phalicks it is chiefly recommended
againſt Diſtempers of the Brain, as to prevent Apoplexies, Lethargies,
Palſies, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Charles</hi> the Fifth's Cephalick Water dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fers from this
by an addition of Cinna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon, Cloves, Mace, Cardamoms, Cubebs and grains of
Paradiſe, which make his much hotter and more ſtomachick.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A famous ſweet-ſcented Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Root of Florence Orrice and Benjamin, of each one
ounce and a half, choice Storax ſix drachms, lignum Rhodium half an ounce,
yellow Saunders two drachms, Aromatick Reed and Labdanum of each two
ſcruples; flowers of Benjamin one ſcruple; all reduc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d into powder and put into a Matraſs well ſtopt, let
them macerate</hi> 24 <hi>hours in a lukewarm B. M. in a pint of Roſe-water,
and half a pint of Orange-flower-water; then draw them off in the ſame bath
ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what hotter, and diſſolve ſix grains of Musk and the like quantity
of Ambergreaſe in the diſtill'd water.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="115" facs="tcp:42878:65"/>The uſe of this Water is only external to
perfume Linen, Gloves; the Musk and Amber may be left out by ſuch as are
ſubject to Vapours; what is left at the bottom of the Cucurbite being dry'd,
may ſerve to burn upon occaſion. Some content themſelves with a Tincture
of the Ingredients, without giving themſelves the trouble to diſtill
them.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Stomachick Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Outward rind of Oranges one ounce, leſſer Galengal
five drachms, Ginger three drachms, Aromatick Reed, Enula Campana, of each two
drachms; Cardamoms, Cloves, of each a drachm and a half; Spirit of Nitre two
drachms; good Brandy twenty ounces; let them ſtand in digeſtion for ſix
days, then ſeparate the clear from the thick according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water ſtrengthens and warms the Stomach, helps
Digeſtion, breaks and expells Wind in rarifying and attenuating the flatulent
viſcous matter it meets with. The Spirit of Nitre is mixt to help to draw off
the better Tincture, and to give the Water a more agreeable ſmell.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="116" facs="tcp:42878:66"/>He adviſes to diſſolve a drachm and a
half of the Salt of Guajacum in <hi>Bates</hi>'s <hi>Aqua Syphilica</hi> to
make it more efficacious for the end it is deſign'd for.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Water for a Conſumption.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Snails fleſh parted from the ſhells two pounds,
boil it well in rough auſtere Wine and Plantain-water, then filter the Liquor
with a ſtrong expreſſion, and having diſſolv'd in it a pound of
Conſerve of Roſes and the like quantity of Conſerve of the greater
Comfrey, diſtill them in an Alembick, then ſtrain the Water through a
woollen Cloth, firſt having added to it two ounces of Sugar diſſolved in
Plantane-water, Saun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders and Spicknard of each half a ſcruple.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water is commended in the decay and ulcers of the Lungs; it
is given in Pectoral Decoctions, or may be taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lone, an ounce at a
time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Water to break or crumble the Stone.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Juice of Leeks, Onions, Radiſhes, of each a quart;
Juice of Lemons, and Pelitory of the Wall, of each half a pint; let all the
Juices be mix'd, digeſted and fermented, then diſtill'd.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="117" facs="tcp:42878:66"/>The fermentation of the Juices looſens
and diſengages their eſſential Salts, which would otherwiſe hardly
riſe in the Diſtil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation. This Water by addition of two drachms of Spirit
of Salt will be of great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er efficacy againſt the Gravel and Stone, and will
better cut and attenuate tough roapy Humours, and diſcharge them by
Urine.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Diuretick Water drawn from Kernels.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Peach and Cherry Kernels of each one pound, bitter
Almonds and flowers of Elder of each half a pound, being cut and groſly
beaten, let them macerate in three pints and a half of white Wine for</hi> 24
<hi>hours, then diſtill'd in B. M. according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Moſt of the oily ſubſtance of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gredients remaining
in the Cucurbite af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Diſtillation, it would be conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient at the time
of uſing this Water to beat a few Kernels and ſome Almonds in a Mortar, and
make a ſort of Emulſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on with the Water, which tho' it would not be ſo
opening as the former, would by waſhing the Ureters with its ſlimy
mucilaginous parts ſecure them from ſharp <pb n="118" facs="tcp:42878:67"/>Cholerick
Urine, ſmooth and ſecure the paſſages from the Gravel.</p>
               <p>He diſtills a Water from the Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and Cups of Blue-bottle
or Corn-flower, macerated for ſome time in Snow Water, which he ſays is
wonderfully ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectual, not only to cure all inflammatory and hot Infirmities
of the Eyes, but alſo to clear and ſtrengthen the Sight of old people, for
which reaſon it is call'd, <hi>Eau de caſſelunettes</hi> or <hi>Spectacle
breaker,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe they that uſe it ſtand in no need of thoſe
Glaſſes; the manner of uſe is only dropping ſome of it into the Eyes
Morning and Evening.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Divine water of <hi>Fernel.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Corroſive Sublimate half a drachm, Plantane-water
half a pint; mix and boil them over hot Embers in a Glaſs Viol to the
conſumption of one half part, then put up the Water for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It drys and deterges powerfully; it is us'd in Venereal Ulcers,
and to reſiſt Mortification, the Wound or Sore being waſh'd with ſome
Lint ſoakt in it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="119" facs="tcp:42878:67"/>
               <head>A Water us'd againſt Mortification.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>White Sugar eight ounces, roots of round Birthwort
four ounces, white Wine two quarts; mix and let them ſtand in In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſion for
ſix hours, then boil them in an Earthen Veſſel well cover'd until a third
part is conſum'd.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is not only us'd outwardly to cleanſe and deterge as the
other, but is alſo ſyring'd into Wounds to reſiſt a Gan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grene, and to
attenuate groſs and viſcous Humours that hinder a kind digeſtion of the
Sore.</p>
               <p>He is for leaving out in <hi>Bates</hi>'s <hi>Aqua
Epidemica</hi> the Celandine, Mugwort, Sca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bious and Agrimony, with the
Liquorice and Tormentil Roots, becauſe they con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain but few if any Volatil
Parts, and that the eſſential and fixt Salt to which they owe their chief
vertue remains in the bottom of the Cucurbit; which nice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty is the more
remarkable in our Author, becauſe he often uſes the diſtill'd water of
Plantane in his Remedies, which by his own reaſonings ſhould be
worthleſs, as containing as few Volatile Parts as any of the Herbs he finds
fault with in ours; <pb n="120" facs="tcp:42878:68"/>beſides, had he conſulted the
Regiſters of the <hi>French</hi> Royal Academy of Sciences, he would find,
that Scabious analyz'd yields ſome Urinous Spirit and Concret Volatil Salt,
and that it is not only re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commended there as Deterſive and Vul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerary, but
alſo as Alexiterial and Sudo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rifick.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Compound Queen of <hi>Hungary</hi>'s Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Freſh flowers of Roſemary a pound and a half, tops
of Roſemary, Time, La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vender, Coſt-mary, Sage of vertues, Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joram, of
each two ounces; let all be bruis'd and put into a Glaſs Cucurbit with half
an ounce of Sal Armoniack and the like quantity of Salt of Tartar powder'd
a-part, being well mix'd, pour upon them two quarts of the beſt Brandy, and
having fix'd a Head and Recipient, and luted the Jun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctures, macerate and then
diſtill.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is preferable to the ordinary Queen of <hi>Hungary</hi>'s
Water to rarifie and penetrate groſs Humours, and to give a brisker motion to
the Blood and Spirits in Soporiferous Diſtempers; yet it may be made
conſiderably ſtronger, by adding a drachm of the Eſſence of Roſemary
to <pb n="121" facs="tcp:42878:68"/>each pint of the Water, and diſſolving three
drachms of Camphire in the like quantity will make it more prevalent a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt
Vapours and Gangrene.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Womens <hi>Aqua Vitae.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Leaves of Sage of Vertue, criſpt Menth, Balm, of
each one handful; Cin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>namon, Nutmegs, Mace, Ginger, Cloves, grains of
Paradiſe, Cubebs, Cardamoms, of each an ounce and a half; Galangale one
ounce, long Pepper half an ounce; reduce all into groſs powder, and let them
infuſe for fourteen days in three quarts of ſtrong White-wine in a cloſe
Veſſel; then be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtill'd in B. M.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Hyſterick Water of the <hi>Amſterdamers.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Dry roots of Briony, ripe and dry El<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der-berries, of
each two ounces; the outward peel of Oranges an ounce and a half, leaves of
Mugwort, Cretan Dittany, Feverfew, Cat's Mint, Baſil, Penny-royal, Rue, dry
Savine, of each half an ounce; Myrrh and Caſtor of each three drachms,
Saffron one drachm; all being powder'd, let them ſtand for</hi> 8 <hi>days in
two quarts of very good Spirit of <pb n="122" facs="tcp:42878:69"/>Wine, then diſtill
them according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This and the foregoing Water are pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per in Hyſterick
Paſſions and Suppreſſion of the Menſes, which they provoke and render
regular; they are alſo given in Palſies and Apoplexies; they are given to
two drachms.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Anti-ſcorbutick Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Garden and Horſe Radiſh
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> each one pound, Juice of
Scurvy-graſs, Wa<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ter-creſſes, Brook-lime, Navelwort, Mint Bawm, Fumitory,
of each half a pound<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> let them macerate together for</hi> 24 <hi>hour<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> then let them be diſtill'd in a
modera<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Sand heat.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water is a great opener of a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Obſtructions, not only proper againſt t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Scurvy, but alſo againſt Gravel,
Neph<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tick Colick,
ſuppreſſion of Urine, &amp;<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> It is a great purifier of the Blood if take<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> for ſome conſiderable time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of</hi> Florence <hi>Orrice, leaves
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Cretan Dittany and dry Mint of
each <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> ounce, Seeds of Agnus
Caſtus, Rue a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <pb n="123" facs="tcp:42878:69"/>Lectuce of each ſix drachms, Venice Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentine and
White-wine of each twenty ounces; bruiſe what is to be bruis'd and diſtill
them in B. M.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water does cleanſe and deterge the Spermatick
Veſſels, and Urethra; it is given after the uſe of Emulſions and
neceſſary Purgations in virulent Gonor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rhaea's.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Mercurial Water.</head>
               <p>℞. Venice <hi>Ceruſs two ounces, crude Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lum an ounce and
a half, Litharge, corro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive Sublimate, of each one ounce, Salt of Nitre,
Armoniack, of each two drachms; Ginger one drachm and a half, Vinegar one pint,
Water of Knot-graſs four ounces, Nightſhade, Plantain, and Roſe-water, of
each three ounces; mix and boil them a little.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water kills the Itch, Tettars, ſcruffy dry Scabs that
deform the Skin; it alſo cures ſcald Heads, Venereal and other obſtinare
Ulcers or Sores; the Parts are to be fomented with it, but bleeding and purging
ought to precede.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="124" facs="tcp:42878:70"/>
               <head>A Water of three Ingredients.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Treacle Water camphorated five oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, rectify'd
Spirit of Tartar three ounces, Spirit of Vitriol one ounce; put them to
digeſt until they unite perfectly.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This hardly differs from our <hi>Mixtura ſimplex.</hi> It is
an extraordinary Remedy in Malignant Fevers, it reſiſts the Putre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction
of Humours, and provokes Sweat given from half a drachm to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Water of Caſtor.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Freſh Caſtor four ounces, green leaves of Lavender
one ounce, Cinnamon ſix drachms, leaves of Sage and Roſemary of each half
an ounce, Mace and Cloves of each two drachms, rectify'd Spirit of Wine three
quarts; let them ſtand in digeſtion for two days, then diſtill them in B.
M.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water ſuppreſſes Hyſterick Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pours, provokes
Womens Menſes, gives life and quickneſs to the Blood and Spirits in
Palſies, Apoplexies, and Lethargies; it may be given in ſome Cephalick or
Hyſterick Julep from half a drachm to two drachms.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="125" facs="tcp:42878:70"/>
               <head>A Water to allay Gouty Pains.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Dry Cows Dung and Frogs Spawn of each equal parts, mix
and put them into a Glaſs Alembick and diſtill them with a moderate heat in
B. M.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is us'd in inflammatory Gouts, a Spunge or Flannel drench'd
in the Water is laid upon the painful parts.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Carminative Water.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Aniſe-ſeeds well pounded four ounces, Cinnamon two
ounces, ſeeds of wild Carrots one ounce, Nutmegs, Mace, Galangale, Cloves, of
each two drachms; having pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd all groſly infuſe them for two or three
days in ſome hot place in two quarts of Malmſey, then distill them
according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water attenuates groſs viſcous Humours, expells Wind,
ſtrengthens the Stomach, and helps Digeſtion; it is given from one drachm
to an ounce.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="126" facs="tcp:42878:71"/>
               <head>A Water to take away Spots and Freckles of the Face.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Strawberries a pound and a half, flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of Lilies
and Bean flowerrs of each half a pound, Roach-Allum half an ounce, Sal Gem,
Nitre, Verdigreaſe, of each two drachms; let them macerate for ten days in
three pints of Malmſey, White-wine Vinegar, and</hi> Narbonne <hi>Honey, then
di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtill'd in a moderate Sand heat.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Water ſmooths &amp; preſerves Ladies Complexions, takes
off Freckles, Sun-burns, and other ſuch Deformities of the Skin.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Elixir of three Ingredients.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Enula Campana and Ange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lica newly dry'd,
Juniper-berries, of each four ounces, having cut and beaten them groſly put
them into a Matraſs, and pour on them a pint and a half of rectify'd Spirit
of Wine, let them ſtand in Infuſion in a moderate heat until the Spirit is
fully tin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctured, then filter and put it up for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>It is commended againſt Peſtilence, Aſthma's, Palſies,
Apoplexies and Lethar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gies, <pb n="127" facs="tcp:42878:71"/>given from a ſcruple to two
drachms in a convenient Vehicle.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Crollius</hi>'s Peſtilential Elixir.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Balſam of Sulphur prepar'd with Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niper and Amber
four ounces, Tincture of Treacle impregnated with Myrrh and Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phire three
ounces, a drachm and a half of the Elixir of three Ingredients; put them into a
Matraſs, and let them ſtand in B. M. for</hi> 14 <hi>days until they are
perfectly u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nited.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This proves a preſervative in time of Peſtilence and other
Contagious Diſtem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers, it is excellent in Aſthma's, it de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terges and heals
inward Ulcers, is given from a ſcruple to a drachm.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Epileptick Elixir.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Spirit of Coral and Tartar of each three ounces and a
half, Volatil Spirit of Man's Skull, human Blood and Amber, of each two
ſcruples; mix and let them ſtand to digest fourteen days.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Elixir is Sudorifick, a great ſtrengthener of the Brain
and purifier of <pb n="128" facs="tcp:42878:72"/>the Maſs of Blood; it is given in
Epilep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies, Palſies and Apoplexies, from ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drops to thirty.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Elixir us'd againſt the Stone and Gravel.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Strawberries one pound, Sugar-candy half a pound,
ſeeds of Gromel bruis<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d three
ounces, Alkekengi Berries an ounce and a half, tops of Golden-rod, leaves of
Ground-Ivy, Saxifrage, of each half a handfull; being all cut ſmall and
pounded, put them into a Matraſs, and pour on good Brandy until it is the
breadth of four fingers over the Ingredients, then ſtop the Veſſel
cloſe and put it to digeſt in a Sand Bath or other moderate heat for four
or five days, ſtirring it every day, which done, filter it with
ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion, and when it has ſettled, pour it from the ſubſiding
dregs, and having ſtrained it a ſecond time, put it up in a Glaſs
Veſſel well ſtop'd.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Elixir, or Tincture, is much us'd in <hi>Languedock</hi>
againſt Gravel and diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culty of Urine, alſo in windy and ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phritick
Colicks, ſuppreſſion of the Men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, Hyſterick Paſſions,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> it may be taken to two ounces.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="129" facs="tcp:42878:72"/>
               <head>An Elixir of Garlick.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Twenty heads of Garlick waſh'd very clean, and
having beaten them in a Mortar put them into an Alembeck, pour on Spirit of
Wine to the height of four fingers, then diſtill in B. M. pour the Spirit
upon freſh Garlick, and add in the laſt Diſtillation a ſcruple of
Camphire ty'd in a knot.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Elixir of Garlick recovers Appetite decay'd by viſcid
crude Phlegm clogging the Stomachical Ferment, attenuates and incides the
groſs Phlegm impacted on the Bronchiae and ſtreightning the Breath, and is
of good uſe in time of Peſtilence and Sickneſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An extraordinary Anti-epileptick Elixir.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Opium cut very ſmall half a pound, put it into a
Matraſs, and pour on Spirit of Wine to the height of four fingers over the
Opium, and having carefully ſtop'd the Veſſel, put it in digeſtion for
three days in ſome moderate heat, then diſtill by a Glaſs Alembeck in B.
M. and you will have a clear Spirit.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="130" facs="tcp:42878:73"/>℞. <hi>Of this Spirit and of the Spirit
of humane Skull of each equal parts; mix and let them circulate the ſpace of
two days, then put up the Liquor for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Some call this Elixir by the name of <hi>the Engliſh
Drops</hi> but unjuſtly, if Doctor <hi>Lyſter</hi> ſays right; ſee
Notes upon <hi>Confe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctio Alkermes.</hi> However this Preparation is commended
much againſt Convulſions, Vapours, Pains, troubleſome Hiccoughs,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> It may be taken to 30 drops. The Opium that remains in the
Cucurbit after Diſtillation may be made into the uſual Extract.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Anti-hyſterick Elixir.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Best Caſtor, Aſſa foetida, of each half an
ounce, diſtill'd Oyl of Amber one drachm, Oyl of Savine half a drachm, Rue,
and Camphire of each one ſcruple, well rectify'd Spirit of Wine ten ounces;
leave them to di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſt together for a while, then diſtill and pour again the
Spirit that ſhall come off on the Ingredients, adding two ounces of rectify'd
Spirit of Hart's Horn, then diſtill them a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain and draw off half,</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="131" facs="tcp:42878:73"/>This Elixir is proper in diſaffections of
the Womb, it brings down the Catame<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nia, haſtens Birth, ſuppreſſes
Vapours, is us'd in the Falling-ſickneſs, in Malignant Fevers, and in the
Plague; it may be given to two ſcruples.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Oyl of Ants of <hi>A. Mynſicht.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Live Ants and ſeeds of Rocket of each what quantity
you pleaſe, mix and beat them into a kind of Paſte, put it into a Glaſs,
expoſe it to the Sun until an Oyl ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears, which is to be ſeparated by
expreſſion and kept for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Oyl is us'd <hi>in venere languida,</hi> the Perinaeum and
Reins are anointed with it, to excite the Spirits and raiſe a gentle
fermentation <hi>in Semine.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Apoplectick Balſam.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Oyl of Nutmegs by expreſſion one ounce and a half,
beſt</hi> Syrian <hi>Storax three drachms, Balſam of</hi> Peru <hi>two
drachms, Benzoin, Ambergreaſe and Civet, of each half an ounce; Musk one
ſcruple, Chymical Oyls of Cloves and Rhodian-wood of each one 
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:42878:74"/>drachm and a half, Oyl of Cinnamon, Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tron and Oranges of
each two ſcruples; mix them into a Balſam.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Balſam is call'd Apoplectick be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe it is of great
efficacy againſt Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plexies and other Diſeaſes of the Brain, which it is
ſaid to ſtrengthen as well as the other noble parts. The Temples and
Sutures of the Skull are anointed with it and part put into the Ears with
musk'd Cotton: It may be taken inwardly for the ſame Diſtemper and to
excite the Seed.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>
                  <hi>Le Mort</hi>'s Polychreſt Balſam.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Sarſaparilla five ounces, Spirit of Wine
four pints and a half, let them infuſe in a Glaſs Veſſel until the
Spirit of Wine appears of a golden colour, then filter it and add eight ounces
of Gum Guajacum, leave them to digeſt together, ſtirring them ſometimes,
until the Gum is throughly diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd, which when it is add a ſpoonful of
Balſam of</hi> Peru.</p>
               <p>This Balſam is Sudorifick, and is of excellent uſe in the
Pox, Leproſie, Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy; and tho' it was deſign'd for internal 
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:42878:74"/>uſe it may be us'd outwardly in Palſies, and
Sciatica's: It may be taken in Wine to two drachms. Some add an ounce of
<hi>Virginian</hi> Snake-weed in powder to the Infuſion, and two ounces of
Balſam of <hi>Peru</hi> to this quantity.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The vulnerary Balſam of <hi>Mindererus.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Venice Turpentine one ounce and a half, Oyl of
St.</hi> John's <hi>Wort one ounce, Gum Elami ſix drachms, diſtill'd Oyl of
Wax two ſcruples; mix and make them into a Balſam.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is a very good Balſam for Green Wounds, the Pled gits are
to be dipt in it; it is alſo us'd in Apoplexies to ſtrengthen the
Nerves.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The <hi>Samaritan</hi> Balſam.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Common Oyl, good ſtrong Wine of each equal parts,
let them be boil'd in an earthen glaz'd Veſſel over a gentle Fire to the
con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption of the Wine, and keep the Balſam for uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is the Balſam mentioned in the Goſpel, and tho' plain
is of excellent uſe to cure freſh wounds.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="134" facs="tcp:42878:75"/>
               <head>The Balſam of the <hi>Florence</hi> Phyſicians.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Turpentine one pound, powder of new well-bak'd Tiles
eight ounces, ſtale Oyl half a pound, Oyl of Laurel, Cinnamon, Spike<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nard, of
each two ounces; diſtill them through a Retort.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Balſam is us'd outwardly in Pal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies and pains of the
Joints, and is taken inwardly againſt Worms, Stone and Gravel to ten
drops.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Balſam.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Whole Wheat, roots of Valerian, bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed
Thiſtle, of each one ounce; White Wine one pint; put all into an earthen
glaz'd Veſſel of a narrow Orifice, and having ſtopt it, leave it to
macerate</hi> 24 <hi>hours over hot Embers, then add half a pound of Oyl of St.
John's Wort and boil them to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption of the Wine, which done, let
them be ſtrain'd and preſs'd; diſſolve in the filter'd mixture eight
ounces of Venice Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentine and two ounces of Frankenſence re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duc'd into
fine powder.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Balſam is much eſteemed 
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:42878:75"/>for the cure of all ſorts of Wounds; eſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially
ſuch as happen in the Nervous parts. The Wound is firſt waſhed with warm
Wine, then the Balſam is put in or Syring'd if the Wound be deep, then the
ſides bound with Ligatures and Bolſters, and a Compreſs ſteep'd in
ſtrong Wine, and preſs'd out again, laid on the top.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The <hi>Italian</hi> Balſam.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Oyl of Olives half a pound, Oyl of Laurel five ounces,
Turpentine two ounces, Oyl of Juniper, Spike, Petrolaeum, St. John's Wort, of
each half-an ounce; yellow Wax two ounces; mix them into a Balſan ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This alſo is a good Wound Balſam, and is proper to
ſtrengthen the Nerves.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Ointment to conſume Carnoſities in the Urethra.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Red Precipitate one ounce, burnt Allum half an ounce,
white Ointment of Rhaſis three ounces; mix them into an Ointment, put a
little on the end of a ſmall Wax Candle and thruſt it into the
<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thra.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="136" facs="tcp:42878:76"/>This Ointment conſumes the Carnoſities
or Excreſcences of Fleſh that happen in the Urethra, occaſion'd by the
corroſion of an infectious Gleet.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Ointment to be us'd when the Excre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcence is eat
away.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Oyl of ſweet Almonds drawn without Fire two ounces,
clear Turpentine and pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd Ceruſs of each half an ounce; mix them with a
little white Wax and make them into an Ointment.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Ointment aſſwages the pain caus'd by the other;
deterges and heals without much trouble; both are to be us'd upon the extremity
of a ſmall Wax Candle.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>An Ointment for Scabs and Tetters.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Salt of Lead half an ounce, ſweet Sublimate one
drachm, Ointment of Roſes three ounces; mix them into an Ointment.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Ointment cures the Itch, Tetters, cruſted Scabs, and
other Deformities of the Skin, diſſolves the viſcid ſaline Phlegm that
ſtuffs the Pores; it will be proper to purge before its uſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="137" facs="tcp:42878:76"/>
               <head>A Linement for the Piles.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Pulp of Hog's-lice, Ointment of Pop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Buds and Oyl
of Eggs, of each one ounce; Extract of Opium half a drachm; make a Linement
according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Linement does wonderfully aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwage the anguiſh of the
Piles; it is us'd after well fomenting the part with luke<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warm Wine or ſome
appropriate De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coction.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Linement to hinder the Small Pox from ſeaming or
marking.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Ceruſe waſh'd in Roſe-water, Litharge of Gold
prepar'd, of each one drachm; Oyl of the four greater cold Seeds, ſweet
Almonds and Eggs, of each half an ounce; Nightſhade and Plantain Water what
is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiſite to make them into a Linement.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Face, Hands and Neck are a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nointed with this Linement when
the ſmall Pox begins to dry, to make them ſhell off the ſooner and hinder
the pitting.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="138" facs="tcp:42878:77"/>
               <head>Anodine and Soporiferous Ointment.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Ointment of Roſes and Poplar Buds of each one ounce,
expreſs'd Oyl of Henbane and the more liquid Extract of Opium of each one
drachm; make them into a Linement.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is proper to quiet Head-aches and cauſe Sleep; it is
apply'd to the Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head and Temples.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Royal Plaſter for Ruptures.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Ship-pitch one pound, yellow Wax, clear Turpentine, of
each four ounces; dry roots of the greater Comfrey, Maſtick, of each two
ounces; Labdanum an ounce and a half, under-growth of Cyſtus, ſeal'd Earth,
of each half an ounce, Cypreſs Nuts N<hi rend="sup">o</hi>.</hi> 20; <hi>make them into a
Plaſter according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Plaſter was held a ſecret by the Prior of
<hi>Cabrieres</hi> until the King of <hi>France</hi> purchas'd it and other
Remedies which that Clergyman us'd with great ſucceſs in the cure of
Ruptures. It is not as Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pound as other Plaſters <hi>ad herniam</hi> are,
but yields to none in ſtrengthening the relax'd parts, not without a
Truſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="139" facs="tcp:42878:77"/>
               <head>Dr. <hi>Blondel</hi>'s Plaſter call'd <hi>Diabotanum</hi>
or Plant-plaſter.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Roots and freſh leaves of Bur-dock, Butter-bur,
Hemlock, Ground-pine, Lovage, the greater Valerian, Angelica, Enula Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pana,
Horſe-radiſh, Sowbread, both Brown<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worts, Stone-crop, Hedge Hyſſop,
both Ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>landines, of each one ounce and a half; all being pick'd, well cleans'd
and beaten in a Stone Mortar, let them macerate for four days in nine pints of
the Juices of the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Celandine, Clary and Hemlock, then let them be
boil'd to the conſumption of a third part, afterwards ſtrain'd and
ſtrongly preſs'd. Let the expreſs'd Liquor be well boil'd with Oyl of
Euphorbium, Oyl of Earth-worms, and Letharge of Gold pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd, of each two
pound, and half a pound of the Juice of Stone-crop, ſtirring them continually
with a woodden Spatula to the conſiſtence of a Plaſter; then melt and mix
with them yellow Wax and Burgundy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pitch of each nine ounces, liquid Storax well
cleans'd from its Feculencies, clear Turpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tine, Gum Tacamahac, of each two
ounces; Ammoniacum, Galbanum, Olibanum, Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtick, Bdellium, Opopanax,
Sagapenum, Oyl of Bricks, Laurel-berries, common a Brim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone 
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:42878:78"/>of each one ounce and a half; Bitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of</hi> India
<hi>four ounces, green leaves of Piſtachio's dry'd in the ſhade one ounce
Camphire diſſolv'd in a ſufficient quantity of Oyl of Cloves half an
ounce, Pidgeon's Dung, roots of Florence Orrice, Virgins Seal, Sowbread, round
rooted Crowfoot, Aſara bacca, Crown-Imperial, Dragon's-wort, Hellebore, roots
of long and round Birthwort, Periwinkle, Seeds of Male Peony, Angelica, or if
that can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be found, Staveſacre, Creſſes and Cum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min ſeeds, of each a
drachm and a half; make them into a Plaſter according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Plaſter requires skill and care to be made as it ought,
but its goodneſs will make amends for the trouble, there being ſcarce any
that does either digeſt or diſſolve obſtinate Tumours like it; ſuch
as the King's Evil, Nodes and Ulcerous Calloſities. It may be made of greater
efficacy by an addition of Quickſilver.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>The Diabotanum cerate with Mercury.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Plaſter of Diabotanum, Hemlock and Plaſter of
Tabacco, of each one pound; yellow Wax half a pound, liquid Storax, clear
Turpentine, Oyl of Palm and Laurel, of each four ounces, Quick-ſilver half a
pound.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="141" facs="tcp:42878:78"/>This Cerate is ſucceſsfully us'd to
aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwage pains in the Shoulders, Arms, Thighs, Legs, or any other parts of
the Body proceeding from Venereal Infection; it alſo diſſolves Nodes and
Venereal Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mours, obſtinate cold Swellings; it may be us'd alone or mix'd
with other Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters tending to the ſame effect.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Plaſter of <hi>Sperma Ceti.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>℞. <hi>White Wax four ounces, Sperma Ceti two ounces,
Galbanum diſſolv'd, ſtrain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and boil'd in Vinegar one ounce; mix and
make them into a Plaſter.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Plaſter is apply'd to Womens Breaſts to keep their Milk
from curdling, and to diſſolve what may be already co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>agulated, and may be
alſo put to Scro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phulous Tumours. It is too ſoft to be made up in Rowls,
therefore muſt be kept in a gally pot.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Plaſter for the Tooth-ach.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Gum Tacamahac, Elami and Maſtick, of each two
ounces; Opium two drachms, mix and make a Plaſter according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="142" facs="tcp:42878:79"/>This owes its vertue to the Opium, which
apply'd to the Temporal Artery may impregnate the Blood with ſome few anodine
Particles, or ſtay in ſome meaſure the Defluxion of a Saline Sero<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity
that irritates the Nerve of the aking Tooth.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Febrifuge Plaſter.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Cloves of Garlick well cleans'd two ounces, twenty
live Spiders, Bitumen of</hi> India, <hi>Sal Armoniack, Roſin, Wax,
Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentine, Oyl of Spike and Maſtick, of each one ounce; Camphire two
drachms; make them into a Plaſter according to art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The ſubtiler parts of theſe topick Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicines excited by the
heat of the Body in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſinuate themſelves through the pores, mix with the
Blood, and either by fuſing it or raiſing a gentle Fermentation,
ſometimes happen to occaſion the ſecretion of the morbile matter;
bleeding and purging ought to precede their uſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Plaſter of Cinnabar.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Plaſter of Mucilages three ounces,</hi> 
                  <pb n="143" facs="tcp:42878:79"/>Burgundy <hi>Pitch, clean Galbanum, of each two ounces and
a half; Cinnabar one ounce and a half, Ointment called</hi> Aegyptiacum
<hi>half an ounce, Euphorbium and Orpine of each two drachms and a
half.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Plaſter is us'd to conſume proud Fleſh, to deterge
Venereal Ulcers, and lay open Cancers: It will be of a better Conſiſtence,
if inſtead of the <hi>Aegyptiacum</hi> you uſe a drachm and a half of
Verdi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greaſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>A Plaſter to conſume Excreſcencies in the
Urethra.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Emplaſtrum Diachalciteos half a pound,
Verdigreaſe, Orpine, burnt Allum, red Precipitate, of each three drachms; mix
them according to art into a plaſter.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This Plaſter conſumes the Calloſities and Excreſcenties
that grow ſometimes in the Urethra. It may be made more or leſs Corroſive
by increaſing or diminiſhing the powders; after the ſmall Wax Candle
arm'd with this Plaſter has been drawn out of the Urethra you muſt put in
another beſmear'd with the Oint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Roſes to aſſwage the pain
caus'd by the corroſion of the other.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="144" facs="tcp:42878:80"/>
               <head>The Plaſter of the four Gums.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Gum Ammoniack, Sagapenum, Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>banum, Opopanax, of each
one pound; Colophony half a pound; make them into a Plaſter according to
art.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This ſoftens and diſſolves Tumours and brings them to due
Suppuration.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <head>Plaſter of Vertues.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Common Oyl and Fountain Water of each two pound,
prepar'd Litharge one pound, Ceruſs four ounces; boil them ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to art
to the conſiſtence of a Plaſter, then add eight ounces of yellow Wax and
the like weight of Turpentine.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>This is call'd <hi>Polychreſtum</hi> by reaſon of its
general uſe, but it is more eſpecially recommended for Ulcerous Burns,
Chaps, and Clefts in the Breaſts, Hands, Feet, proceeding from Chilblains,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is apply'd to Wounds and to diſcuſs the remaining
hardneſs of Impoſtumes; if ſpread thin it may ſerve for a Saradrap to
lay upon Iſſues, Setons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="recipe">
               <pb n="145" facs="tcp:42878:80"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>Tinctura Martis Mynſichti</hi> being frequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly
preſcrib'd, and not deſcrib'd in this nor in our
<hi>Diſpenſatories,</hi> I will add it here out of the Author.</head>
               <p>℞. <hi>Sal Armoniack two part, filing of Steel one part; mix
and put them into a Retort, diſtill firſt with a gentle, then with a
ſtronger fire, ſo the Eſſence of Mars will remain in the bottom, which
take out and edulcorate very well from the ſharpneſs of the Sal Armoniack;
then put it into a Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curbit, add Spirit of Wine, and let them ſtand until
the Spirit ceaſes to draw a deeper Tincture, then pour off the Spirit, draw
off half in an Alembeck, filter the reſt through Cap paper and keep it for
uſe.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Others uſe a more expeditious method for drawing this
Tincture. Having pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd the Salt and Filings they throw them into a red hot
Crucible, let them ſtand until they are very hot, then they caſt them into
a Mortar, and having ſtirr'd and powder'd them a little, pour them into a
Cucurbit, add Spirit of Wine and ſtop the Veſſel; thus they have a
Tincture in four and Twenty hours.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="146" facs="tcp:42878:81"/>This Tincture is eſteem'd an
extraor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary opener, and is therefore uſed in Cachexies, Hypochondriack
Melancholy, Suppreſſion of the Menſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is given from
ſix drops to twelve in Wine, Bath-water, or in appropriate Syrup<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and Decoctions.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="appendix">
            <pb n="147" facs="tcp:42878:81"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Remedies</hi> collected out of the <hi>Hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtory</hi> of
the <hi>Royal Academy</hi> of <hi>Sciences,</hi> publiſh'd ſome Months
paſt by <hi>John Baptiſta du Hamel.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>I Need ſay no more in praiſe of Mr. <hi>du Hamel,</hi> than
that he had the honour to be particularly eſteem'd by our fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous Mr.
<hi>Boyle,</hi> and that he has been Secretary to the <hi>French</hi> Royal
Academy of Sciences ſince its firſt Inſtitution. He is Author of the
<hi>Philoſophca vetus &amp; no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>va ad uſum Scholae accomodata,</hi> and of
ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral other excellent Works. He inſert<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed theſe Remedies in his
Hiſtory in hopes they might prove of ſome good to the Publick, which is the
deſign of adding them here.</p>
            <p>Monſieur <hi>Galloy</hi> recommended the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coction or Broth of
Crab-fiſh in Diſtem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ers
vulgarly call'd, <hi>Defluxions on the Breaſt and Lungs;</hi> he was advis'd
to it by the famous <hi>Malpighius.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="148" facs="tcp:42878:82"/>The ſame alſo recommended Urine and Salt
boil'd to the conſiſtence of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney to diſſolve obſtinate Swellings
when they do not yield to the beſt diſcuſſing Plaſters.</p>
            <p>Dr. <hi>Joly</hi> a Native of <hi>Dijon</hi> aſſur'd, that in
<hi>Burgundy</hi> and the Confines of <hi>Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paigne,</hi> where the King's
Evil is very common, they boil two handfulls of Flower in a quart of Vinegar
over a gentle heat to a Gluiſh Conſiſtence, and apply it with new
Flax-yarn never waſh'd to the ſwelling, which does diſcuſs it
wonderfully.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Du Verney</hi> recommends Mr. <hi>Leme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry's</hi> Stiptick
Water as an extraordinary Remedy in Wounds, Hemorrhagies, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and
ſays, It is us'd with great ſucceſs at <hi>Strasbourg.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Others offer'd the Phlegm of Vitriol co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hobated on the Vitriol and
diſtill'd from <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſeveral
times: This may be ſafely take<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
inwardly, being not in the leaſt Corroſive<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Some were for the Oyl of
Vitriol dulc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fy'd by a long
digeſtion with Spirit <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Wine,
then that Spirit drawn off an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
freſh pour'd on; this to be repeated ſeve<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ral times.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="149" facs="tcp:42878:82"/>Mr. <hi>Du Clos</hi> ſaid, He himſelf
cur'd the ſpitting of Blood, by the repeated exhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bition of a grain of Opium
in Syrup of Pomgranate.</p>
            <p>The following ſlight Preparation is ſaid to be of great
efficacy in Wounds, Inciſions and Contuſions. ℞. <hi>Roſe-buds two
handfulls, Sugar half an ounce, Cinna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon one drachm; put them into a pint of
good Brandy, expoſe the Bottle to the Sun for three Weeks.</hi> They give it
a mild A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtringency to ſtop the Blood, a Volatili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to diſſolve what
is extravas'd and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come grumous, and ſay, it Coats the Wound with a ſort
of Varniſh or gluiſh clear Liquor that keeps it from the Inju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries of the
Air. Others commended the Balſam of <hi>Peru.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Upon tryal, which was moſt in the right, Monſieur
<hi>Redi</hi> that plac'd the Poi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of Vipers in a yellow Juice, or
Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liva; or Mr. <hi>Charas</hi> that affirm'd it con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſted in their
irritated Spirits; there was diſcover'd a Bagg or Magazine of the yellow
Juice at the Root of their Teeth, and a natural hollow Channel in the Tooth
through which the Liquor was forcibly ſhot out upon preſſure of its
Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervatory; <pb n="150" facs="tcp:42878:83"/>this yellow Juice was found to be a
killing Poiſon. On this occaſion a Diſcourſe was ſtarted, how thoſe
ought to be help'd, who ſhould have the misfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune to be bit by Vipers. Some
quoted <hi>Ambroſe Parey,</hi> Chirurgion to <hi>Charles</hi> IX. and to
<hi>Henry</hi> the Third of <hi>France,</hi> who being bit in the Finger by a
Viper at <hi>Montpelier,</hi> eſcap'd by making a ſtraight Ligature above
the Wound. Monſieur <hi>Charas</hi> was twice bit; the firſt time
be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides a Ligature, he took twenty four grains of the Volatile Salt of
Vipers, which caſt him into a good Sweat; the ſecond time he truſted to
the Ligature a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lone, and did well.</p>
            <p>The Inhabitants of <hi>Poictou,</hi> who are frequently bit by
Vipers, that are very numerous in that Province, uſe another ſort of
Remedy. When ſtung they heat an Iron red hot with what expedition they can,
and hold it as near and as long as they can bear it, to the Wound. One ſo
dangerouſly bit, that his Arm ſwell'd up immediately, heated the Blade of
his Knife red hot, held it cloſe to the Sore for ten or twelve Minutes, and
the Swel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling and other Symptoms ſoon diſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peared.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="151" facs="tcp:42878:83"/>Monſieur <hi>Blondel</hi> offer'd another
Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy, which he had known to be us'd with good ſucceſs by Huntſmen in
<hi>Ame<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rica, viz.</hi> When bit or ſtung they imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diately ſcarify'd the
part, fill'd it with Gunpowder, and ſet fire to the Powder.</p>
            <p>Others fill the Wound with Cotton well ſoak'd in a
Diſſolution of Treacle in the beſt Spirit of Wine.</p>
            <p>In <hi>Normandy</hi> they firſt preſs and ſuck out the
Blood, and then fill the Wound with Salt, and this they do when hurt by mad
Dogs.</p>
            <p>A tryal was made of an <hi>Indian</hi> Stone given by Father
<hi>Fontenay</hi> to Monſieur <hi>Caſſini,</hi> a Pigeon being wounded by
a Viper the Stone was apply'd to the Wound with ſome ſucceſs; but a Stone
that was ſaid to have been taken out of a Serpent's Head was found to be of
no effect, for the wounded Whelp it was apply'd to died in nine Hours time. The
Stone was believ'd to be factitious; it is commonly call'd <hi>The Stone of
Camboja.</hi> The Blood of this Whelp and of a Pigeon that died bitten by a
Viper was fluid.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="152" facs="tcp:42878:84"/>Monſieur <hi>Charas</hi> upon this Subject
told, he had cur'd his Daughter ſeverely bit by an Ape, by an Application of
pounded Garden Parſley to the Wound. And another offer'd, That Bees ſtings
are immediately cur'd by putting to them bruis'd Laurel Leaves, and that the
Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of a Chamois-horn did the ſame, and was Alexipharmick.</p>
            <p>Upon the Analyſis of Wolf's bane, and ſome diſcourſe of
Poiſons, Mr. <hi>Charas</hi> af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm'd, he had formerly found in a Cheſt
that belong'd to one of the famous poi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoning Ladies, an inſipid clear
Liquor, that kill'd whatever Animal drank it; that the ſame Ladies Brother
liv'd a long time by vertue of the Juice of Citrons; he was of opinion, that
drinking Water in a large quantity was a good Remedy againſt Corroſive
Poiſons.</p>
            <p>The ſame Monſieur <hi>Charas</hi> being ſome Years before he
died, reduc'd by a lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gring Sickneſs to a very low ſtate of Health,
troubled with continual Sweats and troubleſome itching over all his Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy,
bethought himſelf to take a grain of Opium every day, which recover'd his
Strength much, and gave him great eaſe <pb n="153" facs="tcp:42878:84"/>from his itching,
without doſing him in the leaſt, or abating his Appetite to Meat or Drink;
his Sweats continu'd for ſome time after he began to do well, and he
believing from the itch that follow'd them, that they proceeded chiefly from a
turgency of ſharp corroſive Humours, thought beſt to ſecond Nature in
the excretion, took his Opium every day un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til he was perfectly recover'd: This
he obſerv'd, that it had the ſame effect whatever time of the day he took
it. It is alſo commended in a Teneſmus, and not only put into the hollow of
the Tooth, but alſo taken inwardly for the painful Tooth-aches.</p>
            <p>Diſcourſing upon Sea water, and the ſeveral methods try'd to
render it ſweet, as Percolation, Diſtillation, and Precipi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation, they
ſeem'd to conclude the latter impracticable, becauſe to precipitate the
Sea-Salt another Salt muſt be us'd, which will communicate an ungrateful
Acrimo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny or Acidity to the Water. What <hi>Glau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber</hi> ſays of his
Specular Stone ignited wants the confirmation of Experience. Percolation
requires a cloſe light Earth: Sand calcin'd and reduc'd into Powder would be
very proper. Sweetning Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter <pb n="154" facs="tcp:42878:85"/>by Diſtillation has been
perform'd by ſome, eſpecially by D. <hi>Othon</hi> of <hi>Caen,</hi> who by
a ſerpentine Pipe or Worm of his own invention has drawn above forty Pints in
forty Hours: This Water thus diſtill'd, mix'd in a ſmall quantity with
common Water, preſerves it from Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption, if we believe
<hi>Fioravanti</hi> who delivers it as a conſiderable Secret. Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>water drank
in a ſmall quantity is no way hurtful: Some take it againſt Worms, others
to prevent their being Sea-ſick. <hi>Zacutus</hi> tells of a Dropſical Man,
who being at Sea and forc'd to drink Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>water, having none that was freſh,
fell into a Looſeneſs that cur'd him of his Dropſie. Another was known to
have been conſiderably reliev'd by wearing continually round his Loins a
Linen Gir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dle ſtuff'd with dry Salt finely powder'd; and whereas before he
us'd it, he ſeem'd to be at death's door through the vaſt bulk and
extenſion of his Abdomen, yet he liv'd two Years. Hereupon ſome
re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commended Hemp agrimony in Dropſies; another told, how two Dropſical
Perſons found ſome relief in an Anaſarca by going into an Oven
immediately after the Bread was drawn out.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="155" facs="tcp:42878:85"/>Monſieur <hi>Homberb</hi> related the
Hiſtory of an Hypochondriack that was cur'd by the uſe of this following
Mixture.</p>
            <p>℞. <hi>Quick Lime ſlak'd in the Air two parts, Sal Armoniack
one part; mix them well together.</hi> He gave twenty grains of this Mixture at
a time. He ſays, Lime diſſolv'd <hi>per deliquium,</hi> deſerves to be
plac'd among the beſt opening Reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies.</p>
            <p>The ſame ſays, That if you mix equal parts of Salt of Tartar
and Sal Armoni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ack together, draw off the Spirits or U<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinous Flowers, and then
diſſolve, filter, and coagulate what remains, you will have
<hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Salt ſo much commended by the <hi>Dutch</hi> Phyſicians.
He deprives the Glaſs of Antimony of its Emetick quality by an Acid Spirit
drawn from the Oak Tree: The method is thus.</p>
            <p>℞. <hi>Glaſs of Antimony two ounces, pour on it a pint of the
Spirit of Oak-wood, leave them to digeſt for eight days, then change the
Spirit for new, and repeat this till the Spirit draws no more red Tincture from
the Glaſs.</hi> In this Operation not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly the Glaſs of Antimony loſes
its Eme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick <pb n="156" facs="tcp:42878:86"/>Quality, but alſo the Spirit is de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priv'd
of its natural Acidity; the Spirit firſt us'd becomes ſweet and ſomewhat
aſtringent.</p>
            <p>Dr. <hi>Mery</hi> aſſur'd, That he has cur'd not only
ſuperficial but alſo deep fleſh Wounds with a mixture of an
inconſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable quantity of good rectify'd Spirit of Wine with common Water:
He keeps the Wound clean, drops in ſome of this Water, or anoints the Wound
with a Feather dip'd in it.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Turnefort</hi> commends. Garlick in the griping of the
Guts, and a Gargle of Olive Pickle call'd <hi>Pinſolina</hi> in
<hi>Provence</hi> againſt Quinſies.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Du Hamel</hi> has a great Opinion of the Powder of Acorns
given in Wine in the Colick pains. He alſo recommends the Roots of Butter-bur
as a powerful Sudorifick, and the Leaves of the greater Burr dock dry'd in the
Sun and reduc'd into Powder, as Alexipharmick and ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficacious in Malignant
Fevers.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Bourdelin</hi> commends, beſides Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy-graſs,
Creſſes, Buck-Beans, an Infu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion <pb n="157" facs="tcp:42878:86"/>of
Muſtard-ſeed in Scorbutick caſes. Others were for a change of Air: a
third ſort preferr'd Remedies that may allay the Heat and Efferveſcence of
the Humours.</p>
            <p>The Duke of <hi>Montaſaire</hi> who was Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour to the
Dolphin, us'd to find a great relief from the Rheumatick pains he was
frequently troubled with, by rubbing the part well, and then fomenting it with
a ſtrong Infuſion or Decoction of Tanſey.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Du Verney</hi> has experienc'd the Effi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cacy of Camphire,
not only in Rheuma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſms and Malignant Fevers, but alſo in the Kibes and
Piles, againſt which laſt he order'd an Ointment of Horſe-dung fry'd with
Suet and the Juice preſs'd out for uſe.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Bouleduc</hi> cures the Hemorrhoides with a mixture of the
Juices of Henbane and Toads-flax incorporated with the Greaſe of an Eel. The
ſame commends a Conſerve of Rue in Malignant Fevers. Mr. <hi>Marchant</hi>
the Tuberoſe Roots, Birds-foot, againſt the Stone and Gravel. O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers a
Diſſolution of Camphire in Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dial Potions againſt Cephalalgia's, and 
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:42878:87"/>Camphir'd Wine in Rheumatick and Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ratick Pains.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Dodart</hi> obſerves, That moſt that die of the yellow
Jaundice are carry'd off with a Flux of Blood; but with us they are more
ſubject to fall out of incurable Jaundices into deplorable Dropſies.</p>
            <p>The Juice of Bugloſs is recommended in Pleuriſies, and a
Panacaea conſiſting of Mercury, Sea Salt and Vitriol in Malig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant Fevers,
but the Proceſs is not in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerted.</p>
            <p>Half a pound of Oyl of Tartar mix'd with two pounds of quick Lime
and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtill'd ſix times in a moderate heat, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes a good Remedy in
Palſies and in Rheumatick pains.</p>
            <p>An Extract made of Thea turn'd Vei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nous Blood into a darkiſh
black colour, but did not coagulate it in the leaſt; being mix'd with
Arterial Blood, this cak'd in the middle, and appear'd of a lively vivid
colour, the reſt look'd like common Serum.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="159" facs="tcp:42878:87"/>Cows and Goats-milk analys'd yielded nothing
that was ungrateful either in Smell or Taſt; four pints of both gave three
ounces of Oyl and thirteen ounces of a fixt and very lixivial Salt. All that
was drawn from the Aſſes Milk was ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ungrateful or inſipid.</p>
            <p>A Tincture of Gold may be prepar'd thus; <hi>Diſſolve one part
of Gold in thirty parts of Spirit of Salt, and then pour on eſſential Oyl
of Roſemary, and ſhake to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether until the Oyl becomes of a yellow colour,
which when you find it is, ſeparate the Oyl by a Funnel, and pour on it a
tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble quantity of Spirit of Wine acuated with the Spirit of Sorrel, and leave
them in Digeſtion a conſiderable time.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I will conclude with ſome Remedies recommended by Doctor
<hi>Turnfort</hi> the famous Botaniſt, Royal Profeſſor of Plants at
<hi>Paris.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In Agues accompanied with Obſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of the Bowels he
adviſes to give the Kinkina in an Extract of the leſſer Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tory, or in
an Extract made of the leaves of Smallage.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="160" facs="tcp:42878:88"/>He gives us a Remedy againſt the
Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phretick or Stone-Colick, which the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tendant of <hi>Languedock</hi> having
found great Relief by, printed for the good of the Publick.</p>
            <p>℞. <hi>Half a drachm of the outward Bark of the Root of
Star-Thiſtle or Calcitrapa gather'd about the latter end of</hi> September,
<hi>reduce it into powder and infuſe it in a Glaſs of White Wine over
Night, which filter and drink off the next Morning early, and neither drink nor
eat for three hours after.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The ſame day prepare the following Remedy to be taken the next
Morning.</p>
            <p>℞. <hi>A ſmall handful of Pellitory of the Wall, a drachm of
Saſſafras wood, and the ſame quantity of Aniſe-ſeed, and about half a
ſcruple of Cinnamon; infuſe them all Night in a cover'd Veſſel over hot
Embers in ſix ounces of Water, in the Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning ſet it over a clear Eire,
and let it hoil for half a quarter of an hour, then fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and pour it into a
Silver Poringer upon two ounces of Sugar-candy; when the Sugar is diſſolv'd
drink it off as hot as you can bear it, and abſtain from eating or drink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
for three hours.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="161" facs="tcp:42878:88"/>He diſtills a Water from great Celan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dine,
River-Crabs and Honey, which is very good in Conſumptions, Inflammations and
Ulcers of the Eyes, and powerfully ſuppreſſes Hyſterick Vapours.</p>
            <p>He knows no Remedy that gives more preſent eaſe in painful
Cancers than to anoint them with a mixture of Butter and an Oyl drawn by a
Cornue from common Flax-weed or Toad-flax; this Oyl diſſolves the Blood and
extravas'd Humours in the Pores of the Fleſh, and ſo ſupples the Fibres,
whoſe extraordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Tenſion caus'd the intolerable pains. He prepares an
Ointment which he alſo commends much. He infuſes Beetles and Hog's-lice in
Oyl, then puts in ſome Toad-flax, and after they have boil'd for ſome time,
he ſtrains them through a Linen Cloth, adds equal parts of hard boil'd yolks
of Eggs and freſh Bees-wax, until he has brought them to the Conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtence
of an Ointment.</p>
            <p>The Prince of <hi>Mirandole</hi>'s famous pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der againſt the
Gout, kept a great ſecret by many, conſiſts of equal parts of German<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der,
Ground-pine, leſſer Centory, roots of the greater Centory, round Birth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wort
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:42878:89"/>and Gentian reduc'd into fine Powder, which may be taken
in ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance or infus'd over-Night in half a Glaſs of good old Wine: It
is to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinu'd a conſiderable time, and may prove of good uſe in
intermittent Fevers, Dropſies, and all ſuch Diſtempers as are
occaſion'd by Obſtruction of the Viſcera. A Fomentation made with the
Decocti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Heath-flowers is alſo recommended againſt Gouty and
Rheumatick Pains.</p>
            <p>The following Partiſan is very good in a dry husking Cough.</p>
            <p>℞. <hi>Roots of Bugloſs and Dogs-graſs of each three
ounces; boil them in two quarts of common Water, pour the boiling De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coction
upon an ounce of the flowers of Corn-Poppies and three heads of white Poppies
cut ſmall and bruis'd, and tied up in a Bag, that they may be preſs'd and
ſqueez'd out the better; let them ſtand in Infuſion a little, then filter
with expreſſion, and ſwee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten it with ſome Pectoral Syrup.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A ſtrong Tincture of the Flowers of Corn-poppies is us'd with
ſucceſs in diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charges of Humours on the Lungs.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="163" facs="tcp:42878:89"/>A ſtrong Infuſion of Mother-time well
ſweeten'd with clarify'd Honey drank warm is no unpromiſing Remedy in old
inveterate Coughs, proceeding from tough viſcid Humours impacted on the
<hi>Bronchiae.</hi> An Infuſion of the ſame Herb in White-wine or pale
Claret, with five or ſix drops of the Eſſential Oyl of Saſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fras to
each. Doſe taken faſting in a Morning for ſome time together is ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prov'd
in Obſtructions; as is alſo Sola<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num Scandens, Dulcamara or Bitter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſweet,
eſpecially if infus'd in the diſtill'd Water or Decoction of the common
greater Speedwell or Fluellen. It is the middle rind of this Night-ſhade that
is us'd in the Infuſion.</p>
            <p>In <hi>Greenland</hi> the Natives boil Sorrel and Scurvy-graſs
in their Broth, and take large quantities of the Decoction of thoſe Plants,
without any other additi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion againſt the Scurvy, and find that Sorrel is a
great corrector of the Acri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony of Humours, and of great benefit to the
Scorbutick that are of a dry bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leous Conſtitution.</p>
            <p>Wine wherein the tops of Juniper have been boil'd is recommended
as a <pb n="164" facs="tcp:42878:90"/>Diuretick in Dropſies or Suppreſſion of Urine,
wherein Pills made of two parts Aloes, one part of the powder of
Juni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per-berries are very beneficial; they purify the Blood by Urine and by
Tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpiration.</p>
            <p>A ſtrong Decoction of the great Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dock is not only commended
as a puri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fier of the Blood from ordinary Fecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lencies, but alſo to carry off
the Dregs of the Venereal Diſeaſe. <hi>Hollerius</hi> often preſcrib'd it
with good ſucceſs in Pleuri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies; and <hi>Foreſtus</hi> ſays, it
cur'd <hi>Vaſtelius</hi> Penſioner of <hi>Maclin</hi> of the Gout. It made
him make a great quantity of Water that was as white as Milk.
<hi>Et<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>muller</hi> and many others, are of Opinion, That the Roots of
Burr-dock, and of that call'd Butter-burr, may be well ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtituted to
China Roots, and to Sarſapa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rilla, as Box-wood to Guajacum and Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niper-wood
to Saſſafras.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Turnfort</hi> affirms upon his own Experience, the
efficacy of an Infuſion of the Roots of the great wild Valerian in moſt
violent Hyſterick Fits and Convulſive Aſthma's and Coughs. He alſo
ſays, he has ſeen Palſies cur'd in <pb n="165" facs="tcp:42878:90"/>the <hi>Alps</hi>
by the uſe of the Leaves of Alder, eſpecially when that Sickneſs was
occaſion'd by lying abroad on the Ground or in damp wet Houſes. The manner
of uſe is thus, they fill ſeveral Bags with the Leaves, keep them in the
Sun, or put them in Ovens until they are throughly hot, then they ſpread the
Leaves on a Bed, put the Patient in, and cover him well, who will not fail to
ſweat abundantly: And this does not only relieve in Palſies, but alſo in
Rheu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>matiſms, Sciatica's, and old Aches if not Venereal; which are alſo
ſometimes much eas'd by a Linement of equal parts of Oyl of Chamomil, St.
John's-wort, and Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of Wine Camphorated; alſo by the Root of Pepper-wort
powder'd and mix'd with Butter apply'd to the part, and the Tincture of the
ſame Root drawn in Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of Wine taken inwardly.</p>
            <p>An excellent Mouth water, proper in the Scurvy to cleanſe the
Mouth and ſtrengthen looſe Gums, may be made of one part of the Tincture of
Columbine-flowers drawn in Spirit of Wine, and two parts of the following
Diſſolution.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="166" facs="tcp:42878:91"/>℞. <hi>Gum Lac, two ounces, tears of
Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtick two drachms; diſſolve them over a gentle Fire in a pint of good
Brandy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Oily Aromatick Volatile Salt, or a <hi>Spiritus Volatilis
Aromaticus Oleoſus,</hi> for both may be had by this method.</p>
            <p>℞. <hi>Cinnamon five drachms, Mace and Nutmegs of each two
drachms and a half, Cardamoms one drachm, Saffron and Cloves of each two
ſcruples, Citron peel, Bark of Saſſafras, Aniſe-ſeeds and
Caraway-ſeeds, of each three drachms; powder all and put them into a
Matraſs, pour on a quart of the beſt dephlegm'd Spirit of Wine, ſtop the
Matraſs cloſe, and leave them to infuſe for eight days, ſtirring them
at leaſt twice every day; when they have ſtood eight days, preſs out the
Liquor, and pour it into a Glaſs Retort upon half a pound of Salt of Tartar
well dry'd, pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veriz'd, and mix'd with four ounces of Sal Armoniack, and
diſtill them in a mild ſand heat, and you will have not only an Aromatick
Oily Spirit, but alſo a great quantity of Volatile Aromatick Salt that will
be very penetrating, as conſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>rinous part of the Sal
Armo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niack <pb n="167" facs="tcp:42878:91"/>looſen'd and rendered eaſily ſepara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble
from its other Principles by mixture of the Tartar; ſo that it paſs'd into
the Recipient along with the Spirit of Wine, loaded with the Eſſential Oyl
of the Spice.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="errata">
            <head>ERRATA.</head>
            <p>PAge 21. l. 15. read <hi>ſome Flowers.</hi> p. 25. l. 21. Eells.
p. 35. l. 9. r. <hi>this Honey.</hi> p. 41. l. 6. r. <hi>ſettled.</hi> p. 43.
l. 18. r. <hi>whites.</hi> p. 48. l. 20. r. <hi>from the inſupportable.</hi>
p. 49. l. 4. r. <hi>of each half an ounce. After the Powder made of Warts,</hi>
&amp;c. <hi>in</hi> p. 58. r. <hi>the Remark,</hi> p. 62. l. 11. p. 81. l. 18.
r. <hi>ſtrengthen.</hi> p. 97. l. 15. r. <hi>the dry.</hi> p. 101. l. 6. r.
<hi>of the Herb.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:92"/>
            <head>BOOKS Printed for <hi>Walter Kettilby</hi> at the
<hi>Biſhop's-head</hi> in St. <hi>Paul's</hi> Church-yard.</head>
            <list>
               <item>A Courſe of Chymiſtry; containing an eaſie Method of
preparing thoſe Chymical Medicines which are uſed in Phyſick, with
curious Remarks and uſeful Diſcourſes upon each Preparation, for the
benefit of ſuch as deſire to be inſtructed in the Knowledge of this Art.
By <hi>Nicho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las Lemery,</hi> M. D. the Third Edition, tranſlated from the
Eighth-Edition in the <hi>French,</hi> which is very much enlarged be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>youd any
of the former.</item>
               <item> Eſſays of Anatomy, wherein the For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of the Organs,
and the Mecha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nick Operations are clearly explain'd, according to the new
Hypotheſis, by Monſieur <hi>Beddevole</hi> Doctor of Phyſick. Written
originally in <hi>French.</hi> The Second Edition.</item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="index">
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:92"/>
            <head>The INDEX.</head>
            <list>
               <head>A.</head>
               <item>FRench Acacia, what it is, <hi>Pag.</hi> 25</item>
               <item>A purging Ale, 30</item>
               <item>An Almond Milk, 11</item>
               <item>With addition call'd <hi>Orgeat des Limo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nadiers,</hi>
ibid.</item>
               <item>An Analyſis of Cows, Goats and Aſſes Milk 159</item>
               <item>Antimony, its Glaſs deprived of its Eme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick Quality,
155</item>
               <item>A Cephalick purging Apozem 10</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>B.</head>
               <item>An Apoplectick Balſam, 131</item>
               <item>The Balſam of the <hi>Florence</hi> Phyſicians,
134</item>
               <item>The <hi>Italian</hi> Balſam, 135</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mindererus</hi>'s vulnerary Balſam, 133</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Le Mort</hi>'s Polychret Balſam, 132</item>
               <item>The <hi>Samaritan</hi> Balſam, 133</item>
               <item>The <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Balſam, 134</item>
               <item>Bite of an Ape, a Remedy, 152</item>
               <item>For the bite of a Mad Dog, 151</item>
               <item>Bodies buried ſome hundreds of Years paſt ſtill entire,
56</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:93"/>A Broth recommended in Diſtempers of the
Breaſt <hi>Pag.</hi> 147</item>
               <item>A Broth in Scorbutick Caſes 162</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>C.</head>
               <item>Cantharides, the internal uſe; <hi>vid.</hi> the two laſt
Leaves of the Preface.</item>
               <item>Camphire recommended in Cephalalgia's, Rheumatiſms and
Palſies, 157, 158</item>
               <item>Spice Caps, 20</item>
               <item>Confection of Jacinth, with Remarks, 97</item>
               <item>Confectio Alkermes, remarks upon it, 94</item>
               <item>Conſerve of the Roots of Enula Campana, the Roots of
Althea, and of the tops of Parſley, 35, 36</item>
               <item>Conſerve of Rue in malignant Fevers, 157</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>D.</head>
               <item>Decoction, 1</item>
               <item>Decoction, how it differs from a Ptiſan, 6</item>
               <item>A Cephalick Decoction, 4</item>
               <item>A Decoction of the great Bur-Dock, 164</item>
               <item>A Sudorifick Decoction, 5</item>
               <item>Notes upon the <hi>Decoctum Album,</hi> and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the bitter
Decoction, <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Diabotanum, <hi>vid. Blondel</hi>'s Plant Plaſter,
139</item>
               <item>Diabotanum cerate with Mercury, 140</item>
               <item>Diagridium Glycirrhizatum, 39</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Diaſcordium corrected, 102</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>E.</head>
               <item>A Camphir'd Electuary, 102</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:93"/>A Chalybeat Electuary, <hi>Pag.</hi> 105</item>
               <item>An Electuary of Garlick, 108</item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Lemery</hi>'s Hydragogue Electuary, 107</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Hydragogue Electuary,
<hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Zwelfer</hi>'s Hydrotick Electuary, 106</item>
               <item>An Electuary of the Juice of Rue, 103</item>
               <item>The Royal Electuary, 104</item>
               <item>A Terebinthinate Electuary, 108</item>
               <item>An Anti-epileptick Elixir, 129</item>
               <item>An Anti-hyſterick Elixir, 130</item>
               <item>An Epileptick Elixir, 127</item>
               <item>An Elixir of Garlick, 129</item>
               <item>An Elixir of three Ingredients, 126</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Crollius</hi>'s Peſtilential Elixir, 127</item>
               <item>An Elixir againſt the Stone, 128</item>
               <item>Of Embalming, 56</item>
               <item>An Aſtringent Emulſion, 11</item>
               <item>Errhines, 18</item>
               <item>Chymical Eſſences, Notes upon them, 26</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Etmuller</hi> his Opinion of the Roots of great Bur-dock,
Butter-bur, of Box-wood and Saſſafras-wood, 164</item>
               <item>Extract of the leſſer Centaury, or of the leaves of
Smallage given with the Kin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kina when there are great obſtructions in the
Bowels, 159</item>
               <item>An Extract of Tea, its effects upon Blood. 158</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb facs="tcp:42878:94"/>
               <head>F.</head>
               <item>A Fomentation of Heath flowers in Gouty and Rheumatick pains,
<hi>Pag.</hi> 162</item>
               <item>A Fumigation to raiſe a Flux, 21</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>G.</head>
               <item>Ox-Gall, a Preparation of it, 34</item>
               <item>A Gargle to ſtop a Salivation, 14</item>
               <item>Gargariſms, 13</item>
               <item>Gelly of Currants as made at <hi>Blois</hi> 26</item>
               <item>Gelly of Iſinglaſs, 19</item>
               <item>Potable Gold, 95</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>H.</head>
               <item>Honey, 36</item>
               <item>Honey of Tabacco, 37</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>I.</head>
               <item>Infuſions,</item>
               <item>An Infuſion of Mother-Time, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 163</item>
               <item>An Infuſion of Muſtard-ſeed, 157</item>
               <item>The common purging Infuſion, 7</item>
               <item>Infuſion of the Roots of great wild Valeri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an, 164</item>
               <item>Juice of Liquoriſh, how prepar'd at <hi>Blois,</hi>
26</item>
               <item>An Injection to ſtop a Gonorrhaea. 16</item>
               <item>A vulnerary Injection, <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Ipecacuanha, when brought to <hi>Paris;</hi> Its
Deſcription and <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe, 53, 54</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>L.</head>
               <item>
                  <hi>Laudanum Tutiſſimum,</hi> 94</item>
               <item>A Liniment for old Aches, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 165</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:94"/>A Liniment for the Piles, 137</item>
               <item>A Liniment to hinder the Small Pox from ſeaming, 137</item>
               <item>A Lotion againſt the Itch, 17</item>
               <item>A Lotion to kill Vermin in the Head, <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Lozenges; <hi>ſee</hi> Tablets, 89, 90, 91, 92</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>M.</head>
               <item>Masticatories, 13</item>
               <item>Mithridate, Remarks upon it, 96</item>
               <item>An Anti-epileptick Mixture, 12</item>
               <item>A Diuretick Mixture, <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Mixture for Haemorrhoides, 157</item>
               <item>A Mixture for Hypochondrianiſm, 155</item>
               <item>A vulnerary Mixture, 156</item>
               <item>The common emollient Mucilage, 18</item>
               <item>A Mucilage to ſtop Haemorrhagies, 19</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>O.</head>
               <item>Oyl of Ants of <hi>A. Mynſicht,</hi> 131</item>
               <item>Chymical Oyls, Remarks upon them, 26</item>
               <item>An Anodine Soporiferous Oyntment, 138</item>
               <item>An Ointment to conſume Excreſcences in the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>rethra
135</item>
               <item>An Ointment to be uſed when the Excre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcence is eaten
away, 136</item>
               <item>An Ointment for Scabs and Tetters, 136</item>
               <item>An Opiate against Worms, 100</item>
               <item>The Cordial Opiate of <hi>Lyons,</hi> 101</item>
               <item>The <hi>Tholouſe</hi> Hydrotick Opiate, 100</item>
               <item>Opium, <hi>vid.</hi> 149, 151</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Hoffman</hi>'s Orvietan preferr'd to all other 
<pb facs="tcp:42878:95"/>Preparations of that name by the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thecaries of <hi>Paris,</hi>
105</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>P</head>
               <item>
                  <hi>Panacaea Mercurialis,</hi> 92</item>
               <item>Paſtills to be chew'd to diſcharge Phlegm, 15</item>
               <item>Perfumes, 21</item>
               <item>Peſſaries, 14</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s cold Philonium, 96</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s hot Philonium, 93</item>
               <item>Angelick Pills, 85</item>
               <item>Anodine Pills, 88</item>
               <item>Anti-epileptick Pills corrected, 83</item>
               <item>Anti-hypochondriack Pills, 84</item>
               <item>Aſtringent Pills to ſtop a Gonorrhaea, 81</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Barbaroſſa</hi>'s Pills corrected, 74</item>
               <item>The greater Pills of Bdellium, 75</item>
               <item>The leſſer Pills of Bdellium, 76</item>
               <item>Chalybeat Pills, 84</item>
               <item>Diuretick Pills of <hi>Cloſſaeus,</hi> 80</item>
               <item>Pills of Gambogia, 76</item>
               <item>Gout Pills, 86</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mynſicht</hi>'s Hydrogogue Pills reformed, 71</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Bontius</hi>'s Hydropical Pills, 72</item>
               <item>Hyſterick Pills, 83</item>
               <item>Imperial Pills of the Phyſicians of <hi>Lyons,</hi>
72</item>
               <item>Pills of two Ingredients, 83</item>
               <item>Mercurial Pills, 73</item>
               <item>Pectoral Pills. 79</item>
               <item>Pills <hi>Rudii</hi> corrected, 77</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:95"/>Pills of Savine 85</item>
               <item>Spaw Pills, 77</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mort's</hi> ſweating Pills, 82</item>
               <item>Sweet ſcented Pills, 88</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Quercetans</hi>'s Tartar Pills reform'd, 75</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Schroder</hi>'s Tartar Pills, 87</item>
               <item>Turpentine Pills, 79</item>
               <item>An inſipid Poiſon, 152</item>
               <item>A Plaſter of Cinnabar, 142</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Blondel</hi>'s Plaſter call'd <hi>Diabotanum,</hi>
139</item>
               <item>A Plaſter to conſume Excreſcences in the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>rethra,
143</item>
               <item>A Febrifuge Plaſter, 142</item>
               <item>A Plaſter of the four Gums, 144</item>
               <item>The Royal Plaſter for Ruptures, 138</item>
               <item>A Plaſter of Sperma Ceti, 141</item>
               <item>A Plaſter for the Tooth-ach, 141</item>
               <item>Plaſter of Vertues, 144</item>
               <item>An Anti-nephritick Potion, 11</item>
               <item>A famous Anti-dyſenterick Powder, 52</item>
               <item>A famous Anti-epileptick Powder, 51</item>
               <item>Powder of Aſhes corrected, 61</item>
               <item>Powder to haſten Birth, 57</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Hartman</hi>'s Cachectick Powder, 55</item>
               <item>A Carminative Powder, 62</item>
               <item>Powder of Cinnabar, 65</item>
               <item>A Powder to help Digeſtion, 55</item>
               <item>A diuretick Powder, 57</item>
               <item>The Duke's compound Powder, 58</item>
               <item>His ſimple Powder, 59</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:96"/>A Golden Powder, 61</item>
               <item>Powder of Gutteta, 50</item>
               <item>A Hand Powder, 63</item>
               <item>A Powder burnt in Hyſterick Fits, 58</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mynſicht</hi>'s Powder of Jalap, 50</item>
               <item>The Imperial Powder, 64</item>
               <item>The grey Imperial Powder againſt the Plague, and the red
Powder, 60</item>
               <item>A Powder againſt Pleuriſies, 64</item>
               <item>Prince of <hi>Mirandola</hi>'s Powder in Rheuma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſms,
161</item>
               <item>Powder of Sarſaparilla, 58</item>
               <item>An Opthalmick Powder, 59</item>
               <item>Sneezing Powder, 15</item>
               <item>Powder for Spice Caps, 20</item>
               <item>A Steel Powder uſed by the Phyſicians of <hi>Paris,</hi>
63</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mort's</hi> Sudorifick Powder, 65</item>
               <item>Powder of Turbith with Rhubarb corrected,
<hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Powder againſt Worms us'd at <hi>Paris,</hi> 49</item>
               <item>A Ptiſan to be drank in a dry husky Cough, 162</item>
               <item>The ordinary Ptiſan, 7</item>
               <item>A Reſtringent Ptiſan, 7</item>
               <item>One more reſtringent, <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>R.</head>
               <item>Ratafia of Cherries, 31</item>
               <item>Ratafia of Gilli flowers, 32</item>
               <item>Ratafia of Kernels, <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:96"/>A Remedy that gives eaſe in Cancers,
161</item>
               <item>A Remedy for Wounds, Inciſions, Contuſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> 149</item>
               <item>One for the King's Evil, 148</item>
               <item>A Remedy for the Nephritick Colick prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by the Intendant
of <hi>Languedock,</hi> 160</item>
               <item>For obſtinate Swellings, 148</item>
               <item>For Palſies and Rhumatiſms, 158</item>
               <item>Another us'd frequently in the <hi>Alps,</hi> 165</item>
               <item>Rob of Speedwel, 25</item>
               <item>Rotules of white Poppies, 93</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>S.</head>
               <item>King <hi>Charles</hi>'s Salt, 94</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sylvius</hi>'s Salt, 155</item>
               <item>A Volatile Oily Aromatick Salt, 166</item>
               <item>Silk, 94</item>
               <item>Sugar, 36</item>
               <item>Sugar well clarify'd, ſold for Syrup of Mai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den-hair at
<hi>Paris, ibid.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Syrup of <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Broom corrected, 40</item>
               <item>A Compound Magiſterial Syrup, 43</item>
               <item>An Emetick Syrup, 41</item>
               <item>Syrup of Maiden-hair made without Fire, 37</item>
               <item>Syrup of Quina Quinae, 47</item>
               <item>Syrup of Scammony, 39</item>
               <item>A ſtrengthening Syrup, 45</item>
               <item>Syrup of the Whites of Eggs, 43</item>
               <item>Syrup of Wild Saffron, 41</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:97"/>Remarks upon Syrup of Wormwood, <hi>Syru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus
Kermeſmus,</hi> Syrup of Limons and Peach Flowers 49</item>
               <item>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon the Syrup of Coral, 45</item>
               <item>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon the Syrups of Succory and of dry Roſes, 35</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>T.</head>
               <item>Emetick Tablets or Lozenges, 90</item>
               <item>Tablets of Manna, 89</item>
               <item>Compound Tablets of Marſh Mallows, 90</item>
               <item>Mercurial Tablets, 91</item>
               <item>Tablets of white Poppies, <hi>vid.</hi> Rotules,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> 93</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mort</hi>'s purging Tablets, 91</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Tartarum Vitriolatum</hi> recommended for a general
corrective of Purgers, 38</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Tinctura Martis Mynſichti,</hi> 145</item>
               <item>Tincture of Coral, what it is, 25</item>
               <item>Tincture of Gold, 95, 159</item>
               <item>Tincture of Roſes, 62</item>
               <item>Tincture of Wormwood, 42</item>
               <item>Trochisks of Arſenick, 68</item>
               <item>Trochisks to be us'd in a Diabetes, 69</item>
               <item>Trochisks of Enula Campana, 70</item>
               <item>Eſcharotick Trochisks, 68</item>
               <item>Trochisks us'd in a Gonorrhaea, 67</item>
               <item>Trochisks of Orrice, 71</item>
               <item>Trochisks of Pomgranate Flowers, 67</item>
               <item>Trochisks of Ramech corrected, 66</item>
               <item>Turpentine, 25</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb facs="tcp:42878:97"/>
               <head>V.</head>
               <item>Vipers, a Diſcourſe upon their Poiſon, with ſeveral
Remedies againſt it, <hi>pag.</hi> 148.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>W.</head>
               <item>A Waſh to turn Hair black, 18</item>
               <item>An Anti-ſcorbutick Water, 122</item>
               <item>An Apoplectick Water, 113</item>
               <item>A carminative Water, 125</item>
               <item>Water of Caſtor, 124</item>
               <item>Compound Claret Water 30</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Cloſſaeus</hi>'s Coſmetick Water, 111</item>
               <item>A Water for Conſumptions, 116</item>
               <item>A coſmetick Water, 122</item>
               <item>The divine Water of <hi>Fernel,</hi> 118</item>
               <item>A Diuretick Water drawn from Kernels, 117</item>
               <item>A drying Water for external uſe, 24</item>
               <item>D. <hi>Brun</hi>'s Eye-Water, 23</item>
               <item>Madam <hi>Fouquet</hi>'s Eye-water, 23</item>
               <item>A Water to preſerve the Eyes againſt the Small-Pox,
24</item>
               <item>A Water to allay Gout pains, 125</item>
               <item>The Hyſterick Water of the <hi>Amſterdamers,</hi>
121</item>
               <item>A Water of three Ingredients, 124</item>
               <item>Kernel Water; <hi>vid.</hi> Ratafia Water of magnanimity.
113</item>
               <item>A Mercurial Water, 123</item>
               <item>A Water us'd againſt Mortification, 119</item>
               <item>An excellent Mouth-Water, 165</item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:42878:98"/>The Nephritick Water corrected, <hi>pag.</hi>
110</item>
               <item>Prophylactick Water of <hi>Sylvius,</hi> 111</item>
               <item>Queen of <hi>Hungary</hi>'s Water-compound, 120</item>
               <item>Sea-Water, ſeveral methods try'd to ſweeten it,
153</item>
               <item>A Water for Spots and Freckles, 126</item>
               <item>A Stomachick Water, 115</item>
               <item>A Water againſt the Stone, 116</item>
               <item>Strawberry and Rasberry Water, how made by
<hi>Limonadiers</hi> of <hi>Paris,</hi> 47</item>
               <item>A ſweet ſcented Water, 114</item>
               <item>A Water of Verjuice, 43</item>
               <item>The Women's <hi>Aqua Vitae,</hi> 121</item>
               <item>A wound Water, 109</item>
               <item>For internal wounds, a Stiptick, 148</item>
               <item>A Febrifuge Wine, 28</item>
               <item>Wine call'd <hi>Hypocras,</hi> 29</item>
               <item>A purging Wine. 28</item>
               <item>A Steel Wine, 28</item>
            </list>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:42878:98"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
